<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>hololive</title><link>https://asideaside.github.io/feed/</link><description></description><item><title>Entergram Delays Steam Release of Hololive Visual Novel Okayunyumu! - Gaming Amigos</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxPZXlWMnBvTFhPMk4wdTZxRGJEZUdvWVB0QXhYYTlOREJ2dUI2R01zU1Zkcnh1TVgtMHZVWmJEd183Ym4xV1dscmlNNFhzVTFORU1WWEZidkhscjMxemRsaHFrc2xhRG8zOWVNUm1FdF9aOEZleWJranhkY1NDdjNlQ3pB?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sat, 9 Aug 2025 11:55:49 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>New Hololive Event Gives Ouro Kronii &amp; Friends Stunning Makeovers for Limited Edition Release - IMDb</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiTkFVX3lxTE9Fd0pvSFpkN05KelRqRnFSemhpNVdLNzBudTFTX1Y4eDgtTC1ocVkzQU9ZZ2NXSFdma0w2TnJmNUJfTEtrQng5dGd2a3ZNUQ?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sat, 9 Aug 2025 08:09:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>RHINOSHIELD Launches Exclusive Collaboration with hololive production — Limited-Time VTuber Phone Accessories Now Available for Preorder - Hololive</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihwJBVV95cUxPbEpKbE85bW1lUXl4ZThWRFJnS1BLTDJlX0FIX21iTnJyRDZOOHd0QnFYaks2V1N0WV83U09ncmstWEoxcGJMX2hfSjk2S01DMUNGdlUwQUpvbDdqVW04TnVwUS0taHUtdVJjOEF3UUxfWmRDWnZDN3pBRmxVbF9wQzlkeW1rQmNvUjJJRlJKNWY0YWdGLUktdWJkVjNlRVFWNXVtbm96SUxIS2haR21Ub2Jtc1pyT29zbEZWSmQyVGFBMm9hWkg3bEdGaWNsdlA1MlVNRldDdGpZbTV1Q2o4OThYTW9CM1pqWDFIYktiX3R5ZzB6YUZRb2hzR3hVcEhwa0ZDaG9mOA?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 8 Aug 2025 13:01:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>RHINOSHIELD Launches Exclusive Collaboration with hololive production — Limited-Time VTuber Phone Accessories Now Available for Preorder</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250808-rhinoshield-launches-exclusive-collaboration-with-hololive-production-limited-time-vtuber-phone-accessories-now-available-for-preorder/</link><author>os_pr</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 8 Aug 2025 10:00:03 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Global mobile accessories brand  today announced the launch of its biggest summer collaboration yet — the “VTuber Summer Fest 2025” — in partnership with four popular talents from , offering fans a series of officially licensed phone cases, lifestyle accessories, and exclusive gifts.
Available for a limited time from , the collection will be sold across Taiwan, Japan, Europe, North America, and other key markets.An Officially Licensed Dream Collaboration with Four hololive production talentsThe “VTuber Summer Fest” brings together a cross-generation lineup of hololive talents.
Returning collaborator  is joined by first-time partners , , and . Together, they star in over 12 limited-edition summer-themed designs inspired by swimwear, yukata, and mascot motifs.Products include RHINOSHIELD’s signature Impact-Resistant Phone Cases and the fan-favorite AquaStand MagSafe Water Bottles.Impact-Resistant Phone Cases
・ Designs： 4 designs per talent
・ Supported Models： AirX, SolidX, SolidSuit, Clear, JellyTint, Mod NX
・ Compatible with a wide range of iPhone and Android models
・ Variants： Standard / MagSafe Compatible
・ Price： From  (Standard) /  (MagSafe)AquaStand MagSafe Water Bottles
・ Designs： 3 designs per talent
・ Bottle Types： Stainless Steel (L) 700ml / Tritan (L) 800ml / Stainless Steel (M) 480ml
・ Price： From Limited-Time Preorder Bonus PeriodsShishiro Botan： July 25, 06:00 AM – August 27, 10:00 AM (EDT)
Momosuzu Nene： August 1, 05:00 AM – August 27, 10:00 PM (EDT)
Mori Calliope & Ninomae Ina’nis： August 8, 00:00 AM – August 27, 10:00 PM (EDT)All items are available for preorder only. Shipping times may vary by product and will follow the order in which purchases are made.Exclusive Tiered Preorder Gifts
Spend  on a single talent’s collection before , and receive  (3 designs total, randomly shipped, no selection allowed).
Spend  on a single talent’s collection before , and receive the full set of 3 acrylic stands, plus an  and limited-edition collectible card.* The tote bag and card are limited-quantity bonuses available while supplies last. Acrylic stands are time-limited bonuses and will be granted to qualifying purchases made before 5:00 AM (EDT) on August 27, 2025.
* Purchases for each talent are counted separately. Spending across different talent lines cannot be combined. In case of returns, all gifts must also be returned.Orders over  qualify for free shipping.Discount codes cannot be applied to orders containing talent collaboration items.Purchase both a phone case and an AquaStand bottle from the talent collection to enjoy up to 30% off the bottle.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive production and RHINOSHIELD are expanding their collaboration with the new “holonatsu Paradise” collection, starting August 8!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250808-hololive-production-and-rhinoshield-are-expanding-their-collaboration-with-the-new-holonatsu-paradise-collection-starting-august-8/</link><author>os_pr</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 8 Aug 2025 08:55:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[August 8, 2025, Tokyo, JAPAN – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) has announced that hololive production will be expanding its collaboration with RHINOSHIELD to include eight additional talents. The “holonatsu Paradise” collection will feature seasonal designs and limited-time gifts. Sales will begin on August 8th and run until August 27th, 2025.Quantities are limited — be sure to order early to support your oshi in style!RHINOSHIELD x hololive production “holonatsu Paradise” collection is here!The new summer collection features eight talents from hololive Gen 0 and hololive English -Promise-, bringing a burst of energy to the summer season. The collaboration introduces all-new, officially licensed summer-themed phone accessory designs — each one crafted to celebrate the unique charm of every talent. To supercharge your summer, fans can unlock special preorder perks available for a limited time only. Whether you’re cheering for your oshi or collecting them all, this is the ultimate summer drop no hololive fan should miss.hololive Gen 0 and hololive English -Promise- Assemble for an Unforgettable Summer!The RHINOSHIELD x hololive production “holonatsu Paradise” collection features eight talents:
・ hololive Gen 0: Tokino Sora, Robocosan, AZKi, Sakura Miko, Hoshimachi Suisei
・ hololive English -Promise-: IRyS, Ouro Kronii, Hakos BaelzEach talent will appear in exclusive summer-inspired designs across multiple RHINOSHIELD product categories, including impact-resistant phone cases, AquaStand MagSafe water bottles, AirPods cases, and GRIP O phone grips. Every design blends character details with seasonal flair, delivering accessories that are stylish, collectible, and functional — all officially licensed and compatible with a wide range of iPhone and Android devices, including MagSafe.“holonatsu Paradise” collection LineupImpact-Resistant Phone Cases
・ 2 designs per talent
・ Supported Models: AirX, SolidX, SolidSuit, Clear, JellyTint, Mod NX
・ iPhone and Android compatible (full list on website)
・ Variants: Standard / MagSafe Compatible
・ Price: From $39.99 (Standard) / $52.99 (MagSafe)AquaStand MagSafe Water Bottles
・ 1 design per talent
・ Bottle Types: Stainless Steel (L) 700ml / Tritan (L) 800ml / Stainless Steel (M) 480ml
・ Price: From $49.99
・ 1 design per talent
・ 1 design per talentExclusive Tiered Preorder Bonus GiftEvent Period: August 8th to August 27th, 2025, 5:00 AM (EDT)Event Rules: Spend $60 on any single talent’s collection before the deadline to receive a limited-edition screen cleaning cloth featuring that talent.Bonus Gift: One RHINOSHIELD x hololive production screen cleaning cloth.*1 design per talent; limited to one cloth per qualifying transaction.Event Period: August 8th to August 27th, 2025, 5:00 AM (EDT)Event Rules: Spend $119 on any single talent’s collection before the deadline to receive both the screen cleaning cloth and an exclusive frameless collectible art print.Bonus Gift: One RHINOSHIELD x hololive production screen cleaning cloth and one RHINOSHIELD x hololive production frameless collectible art print.*1 design per talent for each item; limited to one bonus set per qualifying transaction.[Bonus Terms & Conditions]Bonus items are available while supplies last.
Purchases for each talent are tracked separately — totals cannot be combined across different talents.
If a qualifying order is returned, all bonus items must also be returned.Purchase Bonus Campaign & Bundle Discounts DetailsCampaign Period: August 8th to August 27th, 2025, 5:00 AM (EDT)
Free Shipping: Available for orders over $50
Discount Codes: Not applicable to orders containing talent collaboration items
Buy one talent’s phone case + AquaStand to receive up to 30% off the AquaStand
Buy one talent’s phone case + GRIP O to receive 5% off the GRIP O]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>AZKi × Maaya Uchida Collaborative Song “Sekai no Iro” Released Digitally on Thursday, August 7!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250807-01-182/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 7 Aug 2025 12:00:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Motoaki Tanigo) has announced the digital release of “Sekai no Iro,” the theme song for the animated promotional video of the virtual world project Holoearth, which became available at midnight (JST) on Thursday, August 7, 2025.■ HOLOEARTH animated PV “Now, discover your other world.”This promotional video, produced by WIT STUDIO, embodies the concept for the world that Holoearth aspires to create.
The featured theme song, titled “Sekai no Iro” (Colors of the World), is performed in collaboration between AZKi and Maaya Uchida.
In addition to the rich harmony woven by these two artists, this release also includes solo versions for a 4-track collection.
Title： Sekai no Iro
Artists： AZKi, Maaya Uchida
Lyrics： Haruka Kato
Composition： Haruka Kato, Nozomi Tanabe
Arrangement： Nozomi Tanabe■ Track list
1.Sekai no Iro
2.Sekai no Iro (AZKi solo ver.)
3.Sekai no Iro (Maaya Uchida solo ver.)
4.Sekai no Iro (Instrumental)■ Sales format
Digital distribution■ Date of availability
August 7, 2025 (Thu)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive production Returns to Anime NYC 2025!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250806-01-181/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 6 Aug 2025 00:55:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Tokyo, JAPAN — COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo, Japan, CEO: Motoaki Tanigo) announced today that hololive production will be at Anime NYC 2025 from August 21st – 24th at Javits Convention Center in New York City.hololive production booth at Anime NYC 2025 Overview
August 21st- 24th, 2025
Javits Convention Center
445 11th Ave, New York, NY 10001hololive production booth Streaming Activities
hololive productions talents are back at Anime NYC! Visit our booth (#1710) and enjoy convention-exclusive live interactions together with our talents from hololive, hololive Indonesia, hololive English, hololive DEV_IS, and HOLOSTARS English. The list of participating talents will be announced through social media at a later time.
Guests at Anime NYC will get the chance to sing in front of their oshis!
As a feature program for the booth streaming activities, convention guests may perform hololive production songs to a judging panel of three discerning talents, who will give them a score based on whatever wild, fun metrics they may decide.hololive production Stamp Rally
Stamp cards will be distributed at the booth, and attendees can collect stamps by visiting the booths of our hololive Meet partner companies. Depending on the amount of stamps collected, participants who collect stamps on their card may be eligible to receive prizes!Special Gifts and Freebies
・ Memorial Stamp
・ hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME English Edition Exclusive PR Card with hololive STAGE World Tour ‘25 -Synchronize!- Key Visual
・ hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME CatalogOur time schedule and other booth program details will be announced at a later date.
Please check our official X account for the latest information!https://x.com/hololive_EnCome see, experience, and enjoy hololive production talents at the hololive production booth at Anime NYC 2025!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive production Returns to Anime NYC 2025!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250806-hololive-production-returns-to-anime-nyc-2025/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 6 Aug 2025 00:55:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Tokyo, JAPAN — COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo, Japan, CEO: Motoaki Tanigo) announced today that hololive production will be at Anime NYC 2025 from August 21st – 24th at Javits Convention Center in New York City.hololive production booth at Anime NYC 2025 Overview
August 21st- 24th, 2025
Javits Convention Center
445 11th Ave, New York, NY 10001hololive production booth Streaming Activities
hololive productions talents are back at Anime NYC! Visit our booth (#1710) and enjoy convention-exclusive live interactions together with our talents from hololive, hololive Indonesia, hololive English, hololive DEV_IS, and HOLOSTARS English. The list of participating talents will be announced through social media at a later time.
Guests at Anime NYC will get the chance to sing in front of their oshis!
As a feature program for the booth streaming activities, convention guests may perform hololive production songs to a judging panel of three discerning talents, who will give them a score based on whatever wild, fun metrics they may decide.hololive production Stamp Rally
Stamp cards will be distributed at the booth, and attendees can collect stamps by visiting the booths of our hololive Meet partner companies. Depending on the amount of stamps collected, participants who collect stamps on their card may be eligible to receive prizes!Special Gifts and Freebies
・ Memorial Stamp
・ hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME English Edition Exclusive PR Card with hololive STAGE World Tour ‘25 -Synchronize!- Key Visual
・ hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME CatalogOur time schedule and other booth program details will be announced at a later date.
Please check our official X account for the latest information!https://x.com/hololive_EnCome see, experience, and enjoy hololive production talents at the hololive production booth at Anime NYC 2025!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Death Stranding 2&apos;s vtuber cameo is only the beginning of more anime girls appearing in your favorite games, Hololive CEO says - PC Gamer</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi-AFBVV95cUxNY2gtUFNnLXY2YWZrY2dSYVNEcTlLVGxHekRramZIVGx0TDQ2SURnbXBLRTdmN2FlV0ltNThsc19lbVhVT2NmdlJsZHNQSk40c2JDbjhNMFBycXliMm8tc3F3X2J4ekxaTGZCenEzRU1BdlFCYWM1amlIMnpZakJKS2hjR2RfY0hoQWhpM3gyczNxSkZ1dlY5NWVqaFVJUTh1Uk9uWlEtcGNITUx3SVh5N2VhN1pndjN0S3dOUkJ6VUo2cUx5NEY2YUNYRjgtZHhYY0FTOG0wSk1xYnVaNlJnUGJkVFROMnJ1N2otWjhoNDRlS2JzQTFlTQ?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 1 Aug 2025 23:10:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive production x Wei Chuan Dragons Collaboration Game hololive night Grand Debut at Taipei Dome! - Hololive</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi2gFBVV95cUxNRDZSaktBYU96Q19lem9PNUMySWV3c2ktLXpXM2YxX296aFM5LS01eGFad2drZGk1OXlkOXQ5VUU1MG0wVU5hX0M0YjA5aGZ4T2FXWXVGTDhKT0Q0Vm9mNEJweDBOMmg4dWRwZmIzZUVkaTJtSW44bDhFWHFCd05yam5jcjMwb2kyTGlYb0cyaGlhZGphSGtkMDlqa2h2NUVQaFhKRFYzdUVkY2paRnV0UEpvbmRZZTVoN2JyZDJJc24ySTVqeE1JV1hfVHhjQ0M5QlVZeTVYMWJEZw?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 1 Aug 2025 07:10:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive production x Wei Chuan Dragons Collaboration Game hololive night Grand Debut at Taipei Dome!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250801-02-9/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 1 Aug 2025 05:55:44 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Get ready to party for three straight days at Taipei Dome, from August 29 to 31! hololive production has officially announced its first-ever crossover collaboration with professional baseball team Wei Chuan Dragons. From August 29th to 31st, the two will team up for a three-day themed hololive night event at Taipei Dome.This exciting fusion of sports and VTubers promises fans a brand-new way to experience baseball. With exclusive collaboration merchandise, special cheering content, and a variety of event-only perks, it’s set to become one of the hottest and most talked-about events of the summer.Three Epic Days, Three Cheering Festivals: Get Ready for Nonstop Fan Fever!During the event, four members from hololive English— Fuwawa Abyssgard, Mococo Abyssgard, Gigi Murin, and Raora Panthera— will be cheering on the fans through exclusive video messages. Throughout the games, the audience will hear pre-recorded rally up announcements, bringing the stadium’s supportive energy to an all-time high.The venue will feature songs performed by all four members, including the Wei Chuan Dragons’ theme tracks “Goal For One” and “沒有Dragons就不能活” accompanied by live cheerleading dance performances. This one-of-a-kind audiovisual experience fuses the virtual and the physical, creating a cross-dimensional wave of fan support like never before.This special collaboration also features exclusive character illustrations and chibi artwork for the event created by Luun, a talented illustrator and manga artist from Friendly Land Creative.A variety of event-limited merchandise will be released, including collaboration jerseys, acrylic stands, T-shirts, cheering towels, cushions, and a limited-edition iPASS card. Each item has been carefully designed to combine the spirit of the Wei Chuan Dragons with the unique charm of hololive members, stylish, practical, and crafted especially for fans.Additionally, select food items sold at the venue during the event will come in limited-edition packaging. For more details and the latest updates, be sure to follow the Wei Chuan Dragons official fan page.To thank fans for their enthusiastic support, this cross-industry collaboration will feature a “Super Fan Exclusive Set” — a must-have bundle of hololive production cheering items, all in one package! The set includes four exclusive collaboration items: “Cheering Happi Coat”, “Special ID Holder”, “Cheering Sticker & Clapper Set” and ”Cheering Towel.” All items are limited in quantity and will be available by pre-order only.Pre-order details will be announced on the official Wei Chuan Dragons fan page, and once they’re gone, they’re gone. Dedicated fans won’t want to miss this chance!Passionate Cheers x Virtual Charm — Let’s ignite the stadium with our voices this summer!As a token of appreciation for our fans’ passionate support, exclusive entry gifts will be available on all three event days with a unique surprise awaiting you each day!・ On August 29th, attendees will receive a collaboration postcard
・ On August 30th, attendees will receive a transparent bookmark
・ On August 31st, attendees will receive a holographic commemorative ticketThese three exclusive commemorative gifts over three days and available only while supplies last.For event details and ticketing information, please visit the official Wei Chuan Dragons website.・ Event Dates: August 29th (Fri) – August 31st (Sun), 2025
・ Location: Taipei Dome]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Relive the Magic of hololive night 2025!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250731-01-179/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 01:46:33 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[On July 5, 2025, the much-anticipated second collaboration between hololive production and the Los Angeles Dodgers took place in Los Angeles, California at the Dodger Stadium!Starring Ninomae Ina’nis, IRyS, and Koseki Bijou from hololive English, the event was full of exciting activities that ran in tandem with the game — which included a live sing-a-long of “Take Me Out to the Ball Game” during the 7th inning stretch, unique hype videos, and a special first pitch by YAGOO himself!Aside from in-game features, attendees were also able to enjoy pre- and post-game activities, such as an unprecedented world-first VTuber livestream to and from Dodger Stadium. It was a night to remember for both fans of hololive and the L.A. Dodgers!The game started with YAGOO taking to the field to throw the first pitch. Mascot characters Subaru Duck and UDIN also made an appearance on the field, watching over YAGOO as he threw the ceremonial first pitch.Soon after, Ninomae Ina’nis, IRyS, and Koseki Bijou greeted hololive production and Dodgers fans alike with the iconic phrase said before every Dodger game – “It’s time for Dodger baseball!”  And with that, the game between the Los Angeles Dodgers and the Houston Astros began!As the match continued, exclusive hype videos from the three talents were broadcast to the stadium, encouraging fans to show their support for the Dodgers. At the 7th inning stretch, all three talents led the crowd in a passionate performance of  the classic baseball anthem “Take Me Out to the Ball Game”. The passion was certainly felt, as the crowd’s  cheers echoed throughout the stadium at the encouragement of Ninomae Ina’nis, IRyS, and Koseki Bijou.But outside of the “in-game” entertainment, guests were able to indulge in a range of activities for a full ‘hololive’ experience. Attendees received special hololive night trading cards upon entry, this time featuring Ninomae Ina’nis, IRyS, and Koseki Bijou dressed for the occasion in their very own Los Angeles Dodgers uniforms. The line for attendees to get their hands on these exclusive trading cards stretched well into the parking lot, showing just how much enthusiasm there was for the return of this collaboration.Located around the stadium were various photo spots for attendees to take pictures with the featured talents in the form of life-sized cutouts with themed backgrounds. Subaru Duck and UDIN also made a special appearance for photos. Fans in their commemorative jerseys, cosplays, and casual wear stood in line to take pictures with their favorite talent, memorializing  the moment in the form of a photograph.There was no shortage of special merchandise to purchase! Commemorative towels, lanyards, stickers, T-Shirts, can cooler, and acrylic stands themed after the event were available to purchase at the stadium. The collaboration merchandise features all three featured talents in Los Angeles Dodgers signature blue and white branding, capturing the spirit of the team with hololive production talents together. And just like the line for the trading cards, the merchandise booths were packed with eager fans looking to get their hands on these goods.For those that purchased popcorn or soda (or a beer) to enjoy at the game, special commemorative cups and popcorn buckets were distributed to attendees. Each of these items featured unique packaging with illustrations of Ninomae Ina’nis, IRyS, and Koseki Bijou in their uniforms.To wrap up the collaboration event, a special Post-Game Special Program was held on the field.
As fans stepped onto the field, Ninomae Ina’nis, IRyS, and Koseki Bijou appeared on the big screen, and the world’s first ever VTuber live stream to and from Dodger Stadium began!
Fans all around the world were able to join in the Post-Game Special Program in real time alongside the audience at Dodger Stadium!The experience included interactive segments such as a “Staring Contest”, where talents competed with fans on the field in a game of endurance, and “WHO’s Got the MOVES?!” dance challenge where attendees danced along to the choruses of beloved hololive production songs.But that’s not all! Throughout the night, surprise videos messages from hololive English -Myth-, hololive English -Promise-, hololive English -Advent-, and hololive English -Justice- kept the energy high with their cheer.Towards the end of the event, highlight videos from previous hololive English concerts and concert events were shown, leading up to performances of songs like “Connect the World,” “Breaking Dimensions,” and “Our Bright Parade”.
The energy among the fans reached its peak as the event drew to a powerful and unforgettable climax.The night ended in excitement, with fans of both the Los Angeles Dodgers and hololive experiencing the best of both worlds.Date: July 5th, 2025 4:15 PM (PDT)
Venue: Dodger Stadium (Los Angeles, CA)
Ninomae Ina’nis / IRyS / Koseki Bijou
#hololiveDodgers]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Check Out Kureiji Ollie’s Answers to Fan Questions from the holoplus AMA!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250731-02-8/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 15:00:43 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[To celebrate Kureiji Ollie’s appointment as the new holoplus Official Ambassador, we hosted a special AMA (Ask Me Anything) event on holoplus on July 1st, where fans had the chance to send in their questions directly to Ollie!In her signature energetic and chaotic style, Ollie took the time to answer many questions with plenty of charm, wit, and unexpected twists! Her responses are as wild and delightful as you’d expect… and definitely worth checking out!If you missed the AMA, or just want to relive the fun, be sure to take a look at her answers below!Here are Kureiji Ollie’s Answers to Your Questions
I think it was the first fes that I’ve participated in- I was proud of myself when I sang with Haachama-senpai! I still get compliments for that one performance, and I’ll use it as my biggest milestone ever!
Believe it or not, there has never been a Halloween-themed collab before! I’m not only talking about the dead beings, but also the demons, succubuses talents we have in hololive! So I’d like to do a hololive Halloween special one day! 👀✨️
It was during a viewer-participation among us stream, somebody suggested the name and I thought it’d be funny to name him Udin lololol Funfact tho! I was originally about to name him Josephine!👀
I don’t have much stories for FLOWGLOW but I did went on a date with Chihaya! 🎧🔧 She was the kouhai yet she was the one taking care of me when I was at Japan, she even gave me a brief explanation for Gundam! As for Justice, and I won’t stop talking about this, was when Gigi and Cecilia were in their own world eating strawberry daifuku 🍓🌷 (lowkey ship them)
I want to play more with the ReGLOSS members! I’ve only ever collabed with Ririka once, I want to collab with the other ReGLOSS members too!
BIG NO. LET ME BE THE ONLY ZOMBIE THANK YOU VERY MUCH 👁👁🧟‍♀️
That we have an annual company party with every talent and every staff like in those idol animes- I’ve realized we don’t do that cause everyone is too busy 🥲
Very fun! I’ve never felt more alive! Even though I’m a zombie, hehe
Me but with big boobs.
I’m not that loud anymore, I speak English most of the time, and I’m not always horny I promise 🥹🥹
If I don’t work then I can’t pay bills, as simple as that uwu
I usually just stop when it starts straining me~ Knowing when your streaming limit is very important! Better to rest for a day than be burnt out for a whole month 👍✨️
I feel like if I auditioned now then I wouldn’t be able to make it KSKSKSKKSK the level of entertainment needed to pass auditions is CRAZY (no pun intended) and I’ve always felt lucky that I managed to get in when I had little very little experience 👀 As for ambassadors hmmmmm I think we’ll just have to wait and see~!!
I’ve said this a lot on stream and I won’t ever stop recommending Yogyakarta! It’s a province with more Indonesian cultures and is budget-friendly, even for Indonesians! ✨️
There’s also Lembang, it’s high in the mountains and it has beautiful scenery and lots of tourist spots! It’s definitely a local go-to 🌄✨️
Someone who’s professional but also friendly! Having too much of one of these qualities makes it a bit hard for me to lead/follow, so definitely someone that has a good balance in between!👍
Blue Prince! I’ve been wanting to play it but I keep forgetting 😩
My family was financially in the gutters and I had to share a meal with 4 of my family members… I couldn’t do the things that I wanted because there was no money for it, and I had a student loan with my uncle. The only thing I did was study and survive. Being in hololive changed my whole life, and my family’s too. I get to do the things I want and get an income out of it- I wouldn’t trade it for anything in the world 🫶💞
As a fan-turned-idol, I like how I’m able to see what both worlds look like- I love how I can nerd out with fans and also work towards the same goals with my beloved hololivers 🫶💖
I visioned myself just playing games, now I’m performing for world tour 👁👄👁 I honestly don’t know what the future holds~
Schedules and staying relevant is hard- You can’t come up with banger tweets everyday and there’s so much more to vtubing than just streaming so it gets hard 😭😭
This is pretty much impossible, but I kinda want to see hololive making its own anime series 👀
Wanting to go to hololive pop-up stores/collab cafes
I’ve always wanted to be a voice actor, but I couldn’t be one so VTuber is kinda my next best thing 👉👈
I’m optimistic that it’ll only grow bigger from now! hololive has also been cooking so many innovations behind the screen, so I’m confident to say that maybe we’ll be as well-known as Hatsune Miku! 🔥🔥
There’s a solo concert that I really want to do, but I think that’s still a long way for me!
I mostly remember the down parts, there was actually a time where I would cry on membership streams for a whole year every week lol (I’m all fine now tho! :DDD) And I think my peak is actually right now?! I’ve beem provided so many great opportunities, holoplus include 🥹🫶💞 (thanks holoplus team 🫰) As for nendoroids and figmas, we’ll just have to be patient! It takes two to tango and hololive is doing their best to get us the nendos! ✨️✨️
Someone who makes other people happy by doing what they love 💖
1. holoplus is a space where you could oshikatsu TO THE MAX with fan focused features and the latest oshi news! 2. I hope more people will use holoplus more because it’s honestly so convenient! Also I hope that the features that are being cooked gets released soon uashdvaudva the team is working sooo harddd❤️‍❤️‍
AMOGUS
The hololive song that I listen to the most has to be “A Horny Money World”!! I’ve been listening to it ever since Marine-senpai’s live 🔥🔥
It’s still my proudest piece yet! My hololive Medllie (Medley + Ollie)✨️✨️ It’s my gratitude for hololive fans and the hololive talents that kept on inspiring me 💞💞
Mau jadi ambassador UNIQLO, sama-sama merah uwu
Kanata-senpai’s “Bessekai” is my ultimate favorite, it’s so beautiful and delicate, the lyrics are relatable for me and I find it poetic and beautiful 💙
It was a recent stream, but I really like the Valentine’s stream I did this 2025! The one with the maid competition! It was so fun to plan something so simple yet so fun! It doesn’t have the most views, but I felt nothing but joy for that one stream~
Okay IMAGINE THIS: ✨️A BACKSCRATCHER IN THE FORM OF OLLIE’S ARM✨️ hehe~ My zomily gave me this idea and I’d LOVE for this to happen 🥹🥹💞 *winkwonkmanagementpleaseletthisbeathing
Reine is the “putri merak yang tertiup angin”, meaning she’s a peafowl princess blown from the wind, so I think it’d be SICK to make a fan (literal fan) merch for her! 🌬💨🍃
Everyone’s faces and reactions, of course! Seeing you guys are what I’m most excited about 🫰💞💞 (setidaknya bisa lihat muka)
IS THAT EVEN A QUESTION⁉️⁉️💖💞❣️🌷🔥✨️🎉💃
Being a vtuber is COSTLY; even as a corp Vtuber, I put out so much of my savings for projects like 3D Lives, original songs, collab projects, etc! So make sure you’re doing this because you like Vtubing. Please don’t pressure yourself to make covers or big projects if you’re not emotionally, mentally, or financially prepared. You don’t need to rush, things takes time, so be kind to yourself and your wallet.
✨️THEIR WITTINESS✨️ When Vtubers know the perfect things to say on the perfect time, that’s the ideal Vtuber~ A few examples are Laplus and Fubuki-senpai!
I’ll be frank, the bar is VEEEEERYYYY high right now… The only tip that I can give you is if you have a talent/personality that hololive doesn’t have yet! Let’s say for example uh… An opera singer?
My first ever work from holoplus was to give them ideas and suggestions on what the talents/fans would maybe like to see in holoplus! This QnA is actually my second work as the ambassador, and we’ll have plenty of fun things prepared in the future!
There’s so many questions asking what I’m most excited for and I can’t actually tell you guys cause it’s going to be a surprise 👀
Things aren’t always that complicated, slow down and take your time processing everything uwu (I was very impatient back then)
This is a tough one 🤔 I’ve had my dream collab with Indomie/PopMie, so I never really thought about it! But if I had to shoot for the sky… CROCS!! I love wearing Crocs!! :DDD
Dulu Ollie dipaksa harus tinggalin mimpi Ollie hanya karena nggak mampu… Pas denger audisi Vtuber, bagi Ollie itu bagaikan kesempatan terakhir Ollie untuk wujudin mimpi- jadi Ollie kejar terus sampe dapet pokoknya!!!
I feel like we can determine the vector by considering “does this degrade my oshi” and “will this offend anyone else than my oshi”! It might be a hardline to read especially if you’re trying to do an edgy joke, so I usually rewrite my jokes so that it’s a lot more seiso!
Different types of music inspires me in different ways! As for lately, I’ve been inspired by cute-kawaii pop songs! 🫶🌷🍓✨️
Lucu aja AOWKOWKWOWKWOK
Internet connections/obs dying 🥲 I also hate it when I get one-guyed, I hate myself whenever I fall for it 😭😭
I dream of a collab with JaidenAnimations (now that she’s also a vtuber!), maybe a Pokémon collab?? uuuuuuu that’d be great 🥹🥹
Cyndaquil LOVE 🫶🔥
I don’t know if other countries have this or not, but we have QRIS where we pay everything with a QR code 📲 And I think we use QR codes for a lot of stuffs! Social media, restaurant menus, transactions, etc! Pretty handy! OH and we also rent powerbanks in malls so that’s a win too~
I understand 😭😭 Mostly because textbook Indonesian and daily Indonesian are completely different 😭😭 My tips is to have conversations or listen to a lot of Indonesian conversation! SHOCK THERAPHY BABY 🔥🔥 That’s how I forced myself to speak Japanese when I didn’t know the language!
I’m flattered omg??? 😭😭 Thank you, I’m glad you see me as a nice person 🥹🥹 It’s weird giving out advice for kindness, but I usually treat people the way I want them to treat me- so because I’m a needy girl then I try to provide as much care to the people around me! If I were having a bad day, I for sure would love to have someone to cheer me up 🫶
I think you’re talking about kanjis, and the advice that I got from my JP senpais is: don’t sweat the kanjis! JP peeps have trouble with kanjis too wwwwwww But definitely start slow, if you haven’t had your hiragana down then try writing two full pages of 1 letter every single day! That’s how I learned Japanese, and even Arabic! It’s tedious, but this method makes hiragana/katakana stick to me faster!
Honestly, it’ll be easier to learn Japanese once you have the basics down! Start by learning hiragana, and if you’re feeling it, you can try katakana too! After you learn the alphabets, learn how to use Japanese particles like を, に, で, の, は, が etc! I suggest studying from Kirakira nihongo! It’s very easy to follow! After that, just practice your Japanese with a friend or watch JP media without relying on subs! That’s how I learned them! :DDD
Pertanyaannya bikin greget ya- hmm… Boneka Miteiru Jumbo dari Shirakami Fubuki, karena bisa jadi bantal buat ditidurin-
WATCHING VTUBERS FOR 7 YEARS⁉️⁉️ YOU’RE 14⁉️⁉️⁉️🤯🤯 WOW– UM– I really hope you’ve been watching the family-friendly talents kEKW You’ve been watching hololive longer than I have, so I think you should have a proper idea of what hololive looks for in a talent! A lot of factors play into the audition, but what matters is how determined you are in becoming one of us!! ✨️ ONLY audition when you’ve reached age requirement tho, okay?
That’s not the only thing we see 👁👁
I DID………. But then I realized how expensive that would be so I scratched the idea hehe
Pssst don’t tell them but ummm… It’s Kiara-senpai and FUWAMOCO 👉👈💖
amiiiiiiiiin 🙏
Rather than having all of the MMDs public, I think it’s best to do whatever makes the talents happy! Whether they want their MMDs public, or if they want it private 🫶❣️
Like, comment, follow, subscribe~ (no like for real dO IT NOW)
Laplus, I’ve noticed that she’s just so unapologetically her around everyone- She brought a toy horse back stage during holofes for good luck-
Definitely Ina! And always will be Ina! WAH
Elizabeth because she is SUCH a gentlewoman UGHHH💖💖💞💞
I’m sorry Shiori but I stan BloodRaven 💄🎼🫶💖 I’ve carried Kobo plenty of times so yeah!
Roboco, Akirose, Subaru (Choco-sensei is curved but something about Subaru-senpai’s hips got me 😳😳), Marine, Watame I guess?? (gen 4 only has cute members now), Botan, Lui, Ririka, Chihaya, Moona, Reine, Zeta, Kiara, Kronii, Nerissa, Raora- phewww those are my opinions!
It was the holoplus team that reached out to me first and offered me this amazing opportunity! Having given this honorable role, I aspire to invite the community towards a more OSHIKATSU community space and make connections between fans and talents! (I’ll drink water now hehe thank you)
holoplus is honestly an app that I’ve been dreaming of existing (and I’m not saying this because I’m the ambassador hehe) Our focus gets scattered when using other social medias because of outside interest and recommended posts, while in holoplus, we get to entirely invest our focus to hololive! I don’t have to open the hololive schedule website to check for streams, I could do it in holoplus! If I want to know the latest news like new outfits or even 3D Lives, holoplus got me covered! It’s honestly so convenient, I’m just waiting for my own official holoplus account so that I could just start posting here adsfgfhjisheb
Ollie ingin lebih banyak berinteraksi dengan kalian para fans! Waktu jadi ambassador holomeet, Ollie nggak terlalu banyak bekerja- jadi kali ini Ollie pengen lebih aktif lagi!
I’ve given all my ideas to the holoplus team already and a few of them they are already working on so I’ll let this be a surprise for now~
YES
To drag all of you and use this superior app MWAHAHHAHAHAH
WHY WOULD I THINK TWICE ABOUT BECOMING THE AMBASSADOR OF THE HOLOLIVE OSHIKATSU SOCIAL MEDIA??? IT WAS AN IMMEDIATE YESSSS
Um… Blend in… Yeah…
Pros, you’re already dead so nothing kills you and you can pop your head whenever! 🧟‍♀️✨️ Cons, body parts are basically rotting so it’s prone to illnesses and injuries 💦
CYBOOOOORGGG YEAHHHH LASER EYESSSSSSS 🔥🔥🔥
1000 BAJILLION DOLLARS🤑🤑
I’ve always loved Elephants!🐘💖
“Shampoo… *screams at the sight of soap*”
Hard question because every vocaloid song is so good- But the first song that popped in my head was “Neko Neko☆Super Fever Night” because it’s just so hype and I LOVE listening to the niconico utaites singing it together 🐱🐾 Favorite composer is DECO*27! He was the one who made my entire childhood with all his songs, so when I sang the chorus for ZOMBIE it was like a dream come true!!🥰🥰
INAZUMA ELEVEN ⚽️⚡️
Does Raimon Eleven from Inazuma Eleven count-
I was actually shocked that everybody was so supportive! I was ready for people to ramble at me about diet plans and work-out tips- but everybody embraced the chubby belly?!?!?😳😳
Boring answer: I like spending time with friends and family; Other answer: Stalk fan’s twitter accounts
I love comfy and long dresses; I’ve been looking into modern hanfus and traditional qipaos lately!
Tshirts at home- Just Tshirts uwu
Golf is something that I’ve been dying on trying! You just hit a ball and walk with your friends across the field-
Aquariums for sure! It’s just somehow more romantic~
🫂
I’m sorry Shiori but I stan BloodRaven 💄🎼🫶💖 I’ve carried Kobo plenty of times so yeah!
I’ll be so honest with you guys I don’t wishlist or check for sales in Steam at all 😭😭 I usually just buy whatever the other members are playing 🥹🥹
If you’re going to Jakarta, please please PLEASE wear a facemask 😭😭
I guess it’d have to be a Yakitori! It’s basically just a chicken skewer, so I grade them the same level as Satay!🍢
I like anything doughy! Like cake batter ice cream!
It came after I accidentally mistook chocomint ice cream for matcha, my world completely CHANGED
Indomie! :DDD
I’ve never tried it! But I did had a funny story regarding it, apparently a few content creators mistook me for a Philipino and thought that my concept was a knock on Jollibee skskksksks
I’d take them to a Padang Restaurant! They serve a bunch of menus at once even before you order, I think that would be an experience!
Relax and be confident! You just have to look cool to convince the HR team!
No, I’m Indonesian and cheese is so expensive owo
YASSSS
LITERALLY PLEASE INVITE ME TO ANY HAWAII CONVENTIONS I WOULD LOVE TO GO 😭😭
Swiss has been in my bucket list for sooo longg
A glass cabinet!
I’m so bad with horror games KSKSKSKKSKS, but I’m surprisingly unfazed with horror movies/series!
I tried practicing with it but there never was a good moment to actually use it so I just rusted uwu
A lot actually! I get to constantly talk about holoplus, advertise the f out of it, even make streams using holoplus! That’s a plan for another day though~
holoplus is scarily advanced, there’re so many language options, they have channels for different type of posts you want to see, and everything loads like SUPER FAST??? It’s honestly so insane-
This is so embarrassing to answer, but the team said something along the lines of “Ollie is the perfect ambassador and we are confident that you can help us connect to the fans all over the world” uuuuuuu ///////////
Canggih sedap skuy skuy cukurukuk
I might be more active here than in other social medias in the future KEK
I actually love when there’re posts where you guys start discussing and replying to each other, though it’s been really quiet in here… 👀
Not gonna lie, when they first shared the idea of holoplus to the talents, I thought that it’d be hard to achieve because this is essentially making their own social media- so I was actually super surprised at how well made holoplus came to be! Color me surprised when holoplus actually cooked and served! The team did SUCH A GREAT JOB!!!!!
Themed UI would be cool no?! Imagine an Ollie-themed holoplus when you open the app!!!!✨️✨️
Dark mode is always a go-to~
I think it’d be pretty rad if we could connect and multistream our streams in holoplus! Maybe the people watching from holoplus can send in cute stickers on stream or something!
Custom hololive production talents notification sounds! This might sound simple, but if we were to involve all of the talents… Hmm…
I’m so blessed and honored to be trusted with such an amazing role TTTT The team is also so nice to me it’s just so fun being an ambassador!! <3Join the holoplus Community!holoplus offers an extensive variety of content, including original content unique to holoplus that can be enjoyed by everyone, as well as exclusive information in collaboration with large-scale events!Join and take part in building a community for all fans!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Smilegate Unveils Chaos Zero Nightmare OST &quot;OVER//RIDE,&quot; Performed by hololive English - Yahoo Finance</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAFBVV95cUxPQ3pSUG5mMTdqTHEyaXozQlBSbXplb0VDYUt0SkwtWXpuMVhfZmxkaU80NTlMWmxma0RKdE1pdVRPcmlGV0FYcFo3RGg1ajJXRjJmWTNYSWVZZUdxSmYxc2dnZDZSTU1KWlBPM3F0QW5HWGNGWDNHZFE3UUdZMTF6RGk4bEo5V0xFVFhjTw?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How VTuber Agencies Like VShojo and Hololive Are Changing the Idol Game - Rolling Stone</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxQVDVLSTdzeG52cW0xYXFLNWladUxMNm1LV0diYkJpR2JYZGZsWW1qZS04eGNtX1RjclE5UFN1TFg4MDctTGUxZlJ2czdsNHB4VDJVeXNUMHYzNzhCWlpDOE1fRUdwdDk1MzdVVTNKSU1YTENzM3ptVFJnZXlid0txdDVqM3FrMG1LUzY2aDJaUkRPTFFwUVlnVjhObFMtWk5YVlo5em55M1kwVzhlWC12aVIyVjY2em8?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 14:26:41 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hololive and Dodgers create a home for queer fandom - Los Angeles Blade</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimwFBVV95cUxOSlZxMkhYaE9lZFllZEc5bG1NSzNJdUZzdGt4cjlCOFdpXzNNNEl2ZmQ5M2RiMVVmbTRIZi1iSmpNUVVnMXNWUmpubEdLMk5Xa2pwLUdWbWxZZkhoZlVSUm03WGk1b3MtVS1CUjEzMm1JWHJsY1p3eDhqV29yc0ozN2ZBSEJ6VkxBWE1TbE9fRjVYMldHVWZ6MW9tYw?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 19:48:44 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hololive Night Pulls Huge Grand Slam at Dodgers Stadium - Anime News Network</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMi6AFBVV95cUxPZnJBekYyQ09NOUlIRHRTa0xmSFdzQ1U3RXpacEYwNlZmYi1GQS1Wb2I4eUhZOE1wbC1qYWtFVVlud3UwSFpkclZVbWJYTTlPTUd1T0ZhVjlfSkZzcjYxSXc2RDZxN0dMaHhCS1ZOVzd2c0NJeUkybTEyWnZxWFNGRzBOZFZKMEctVEZ2dC1ZVWE1LW1ydlFVczNJTDA2b2JaMk1mUXBQV0puQW5xMXJkSjR2UGVjVXhYRE9OdXJ0dHo5WmJjdGFrSjJMYlZldG1aUEJnQjBtQVgtQklEem9JQ3JqUmdPb0d5?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 16:34:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive GoroGoro Mountain launches this month - Niche Gamer</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiekFVX3lxTFBWLVFIbHhLY1NUUkVjS2tTUTE3bmg3REwyTXFZSEVvcmx6QkxLZUNLd1d5SENLem5KakpkdEdveGd0c0Y3bVdZX09penIwdTBISm9lN0ZvZ0MyVEU2ZDZWZHdHOGVUbWVkN2k2d1R1X0tVRkRwd1g0YmZB?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 13:31:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mori Calliope and Nerissa Ravencroft from hololive EN to release original theme song for Chaos Zero: Nightmare - Hololive</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXEFVX3lxTE1oRk0tRk1TMFdHY2lIODdqdjA2bnNReUpKMGdPVFBzWTBweWlLelNpVXJxUzRWZmxEUFJPR2tQVkpWYWx2RlJiRXZfSi16RkxjWUlBQ3JIWlhXb3g4?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 06:02:49 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Do VTubers Face &apos;Income Inequality&apos; From Fans? One Study Tackles the &apos;Wealth Gap&apos; in VTubing - VICE</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxOWXdNcWtjbDlJR0xMR0lzVmxDcmJBVUozRVp6ZTRnc1hBWlQ1SE5rcy0xWHI1ekRvN1FPWTZobXFhR21FaDVnTUwxbVVEOG1pRmpTMF9wMllsTHRkZmZ3NncyTnpuc0pYc1huaDY5OTVJeDhtLWVNeFJJWWdvVVE2UDhvUmZULW1EOTMxanVGQ2ZNM1FQNnktUDMxNVFEUVFHZTZTTy0zS01hN1MydTMxZHhyaG1aYnJqS2MwXw?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 18:35:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Smilegate enlists Hololive stars for Chaos Zero Nightmare theme song - DBLTAP</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinAFBVV95cUxOTXRXWWwyNW5OX3E4X2xvRklETWJnSkl6M1h6WUMxNWhxbjZIU3lMUWMwLTFPbHhLOTNwWnBqVTVkUEc5UThqLUVIekZUN3NBeXh4cnU4NXNQczg5VnV3cF9RTmFiUVhIMjdEaGlYODNnOHZSaXZoaXFFbE5fYkIyM3NrVWZ3b282R3dQend4VkNkQ3FWQnJIZkRCSVk?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mori Calliope and Nerissa Ravencroft from hololive EN to release original theme song for Chaos Zero: Nightmare</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250710-01-178/</link><author>os_pr</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 01:00:14 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[July 10, 2025, Tokyo, Japan – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) has announced the pre-registration launch of Smilegate Megaport’s upcoming title Chaos Zero: Nightmare, developed by Super Creative, began on July 9, 2025 (Wed).
Alongside the announcement, a special collaboration with hololive EN talents Mori Calliope and Nerissa Ravencroft has also been revealed.Set in a dark fantasy universe consumed by an unknown force called “Chaos,” Chaos Zero: Nightmare offers a unique collectible RPG experience that blends strategic character development with rogue-lite elements. The game is directed by Kim Hyeong-seok, the creator of Epic Seven, and is Super Creative’s next-generation IP.To celebrate the launch, a powerful duet track titled “OVER//RIDE”, performed by Mori Calliope and Nerissa Ravencroft, will be released on July 18 (Fri). The song fuses the rich atmosphere of the game’s dark setting with the compelling voices of the two artists.A special Game Version MV will also be released alongside the song.For more information and updates, please visit the official website and social media platforms listed below.Chaos Zero: Nightmare – Official Links]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>holonatsu Paradise</title><link>https://hololive.hololivepro.com/en/events/holonatsu-paradise/</link><author>maki</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 9 Jul 2025 11:00:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive.hololivepro.com/en">hololive Events</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hololive VTubers make a special appearance at the Astros vs. Dodgers series - Annenberg Media</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivAFBVV95cUxNb0NtZXNMTW5ibWxVc3BTcXhRR1V4dTI4UThmWFppUjYxeU94WkdtdWVIdlIxeERxMDVWR1ZUWHdrYUZ5Q3JzcEJhU2lEOXdia0ZZMEpsZS04NVJCWUNwQzN3UXRfdS02X3I0b3pvUldIam9ZN2YzZk1wUWlUeW5FYm9sNVMyZEJmYUFSVDh3dnNvSmpWcWlOWGlwQmVoRVpEWmZ2d2dmSmJEeWNoVEV3UDlDbkJaVXppY3Q1MA?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 8 Jul 2025 22:28:21 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>holonatsu fair will be held in multiple stores and official online shop!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250709-01-177/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 8 Jul 2025 15:00:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A special fair in collaboration with “holonatsu Paradise” will be held from Wednesday, July 9th!
During the campaign period, for every 2,000 yen (including tax) purchase of hololive-related products at select shops, you will receive a special postcard* featuring hololive talents in their original summer outfits!
At the official online shop, for orders that include eligible products totaling 3,000 JPY (tax included) or more, the usual shipping fee of 1,000 JPY will be reduced by half to 500 JPY.*The postcard design lineup will vary depending on which store you buy.[August 1st (Fri) – August 20th (Wed)]
hololive production official shop in Tokyo Station
hololive production official shop in Osaka Umeda[August 1st (Fri) – August 31st (Sun)]
All animate stores in Japan (excluding animate Online Shop)
Kotobukiya Akihabara Store
Kotobukiya Tachikawa Main Store
Kotobukiya Namba
AKIHABARA GAMERS Flagship Store
GAMERS NAGOYA
GAMERS HAKATADuring the campaign period, for orders that include eligible products totaling 3,000 JPY (tax included) or more, the usual shipping fee of 1,000 JPY will be reduced by half to 500 JPY.
Please also note that “Premium Talent Merch” is excluded from this campaign. If the order includes at least one of the relevant products, the campaign will not be applied.Some horonatsu goods will be available for sale!Novelties for purchasers：For details of novelties, please visit the campaign website of each store (except hololive production official shop).]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hololive Night returns to Dodgers Stadium with VTuber livestream for Shohei Ohtani - gamesbeat.com</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxPYjFjQXRHcFB6bjZvSFZ6Z2ZuQ3JHb2Fybi1Hb254X1plM0s4VnFUZ0k2bHBLMklsRkR4SHhVWW91dnRFTDY5aWswMmRWbkc0WmhfVmppR29VRnl0S0F3VWw2c3NzRThkZG1nN3pjbE1ZamFzX1AwXy0yQ2RMOTZZa0lGUEoyajJCa19yY1FiRFZiWGtkcUhLaDUtblF5Nm9aOW5rMXdHOXM?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sun, 6 Jul 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Doki Dreamers × HOLOSTARS English -TEMPUS- “Sweet Love” Collection Available!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250704-01-176/</link><author>os_pr</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 4 Jul 2025 01:00:41 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[July 8, 2025, Tokyo, Japan – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) has announced that the Doki Dreamers × HOLOSTARS English -TEMPUS- “Sweet Love” product collection is available for purchase.The Doki Dreamers × HOLOSTARS English -TEMPUS- “Sweet Love” collection is the first product collaboration project between HOLOSTARS English -TEMPUS- and artist-driven merchandise brand Doki Dreamers. The product collection features a lineup of baking-themed accessories, including a cookie-style button, a chocolate-style keychain, an enamel pin, a collection of “cheki”-style photo cards, and a beautiful poster featuring each of the HOLOSTARS English -TEMPUS- talents.
The Doki Dreamers × HOLOSTARS English -TEMPUS- “Sweet Love” collection merchandise is available on the Doki Dreamers online shop from June 20, 2025 from 10:00 AM (PDT), and will be available at ANIME Impulse Orange County in Anaheim, CA on August 30th and 31st, 2025.
For more information, please visit the official Doki Dreamers social media accounts and official website.Doki Dreamers × HOLOSTARS English -TEMPUS- “Sweet Love” collection
・ Cookie button pins
・ Photo cards
・ Key Visual posterOnline Shipping
Shipping from: Washington State, USAShipping is subject to availability. Orders containing backlogged products may be delayed. Orders may be cancelled any time prior to shipping.Doki Dreamers strives to connect the dreams of creators with the hearts of fans, celebrating their communities and making memories together. Their shop specializes in creating high quality products for VTubers and their communities. Each product is made with the belief that merchandise should be as colorful and unique as the talents themselves, and be a fun way to celebrate and share love for a community.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>VTubers are descending on L.A. with multiple concerts - Los Angeles Times</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxOamswT1BpX0NIUHRnWnpwby1NOWt0c0IwLVpJU3BhMWMwWF9BZUtON0lTem9qem5Yd05zVk1HRDBIWkF1UGtuckw2QVU1emtfRVlYMG1TaC15OTMwVjFHN1ctMlFQTDJuREtndkhBdXZrVDBJNUh3Smg4OHd5a0s2bUZuRnhKNDZlYmo5bU9YVTRkUQ?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 3 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>GHOST X GHOST Teams Up with Mori Calliope Again for a PORTRAIT OF DEATH drop! | hololive production - Hololive</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXEFVX3lxTFBCNkpxb3Z2REhJdnZwVWZ1THV2NnpleklrbkxTUGtHaU9ibm5ibGhzUVFLam9SWHZKRVpfYVRYRFA5RjZJdjlqWDlmT0pPOF93VEg1NENaUlEySGtT?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 3 Jul 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>GHOST X GHOST Teams Up with Mori Calliope Again for a PORTRAIT OF DEATH drop!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250703-01-175/</link><author>os_pr</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 3 Jul 2025 01:00:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[July 3, 2025, Tokyo, Japan – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) has announced another collaboration between GHOST X GHOST and Mori Calliope of hololive English of hololive production. Following the success of the previous Metalcropolis collaboration, they will launch a new limited-edition series titled .Taking some inspiration from Alphonse Mucha and the desire to showcase talents in a new way the GHOST X GHOST team have created an unexpected and unique design in the PORTRAIT series. Illustrator Florian Bertmer brings Mori Calliope to life in a design that fuses elegance with ominous grace befit for the reaper’s apprentice.“We’re stoked to work with Calli again, and we hope you’re ready to face her PORTRAIT OF DEATH.” the GHOST X GHOST team shared.The Mori Calliope – Portrait of Death series includesLong-Sleeve T-Shirt – $45 
Printed on Comfort Colors “pepper” long-sleeved t-shirt and features printed sleeves.White Variant T-Shirt – $30 
Available for PREORDER for 24-hours only! Features metallic silver ink.Standard & Long-Sleeve T-Shirts: 
Pre-orders open Tuesday, July 2nd at 5 PM PDT and close Friday, July 25th at 12 PM PDT.
Extremely limited—preorders are available only for 24 hours! 
From July 2nd at 5 PM PDT to July 3rd at 5 PM PDT.Whether you’re a fan of Mori Calliope or love art and fashion, don’t miss the  series—check it out now!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive English Teams Up with Kura Sushi USA for an Exclusive Summer Collaboration! - Hololive</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXEFVX3lxTE1CMU01R0NnZmJaS29Fa3dTLTVfdDhnWGV3MDFMV3pJOU9hRHNLdS1yOWJwejZubFcycTlNUkJJZEVvS3l1bEhrdzVvZDFfQkw4Y1A5QVY0S2p0QmNZ?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 2 Jul 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hololive reveals Kura Sushi collab with limited-time VTuber menu and merch - Dexerto</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxQMU9WdWxtWDk2V2dOUURvaFhzbDBCUzdUQmFJaGU1cXJUXy02NjdlVFpicndxb1RCUEwtVEdkdFZSLXZ3cUhISXhTdnFZQnZtdjdObGotX1hsM29WdzlDQTJKTU8tY003dE4weE9Nb09RQmtmbms4N0lLbVRPUVU4V21nTjBTMjdXNWdhLXZoUEU0UkN4UDNfMC1TbkY3aVhmdWlJR3V6ZUJscXBERWNyLTdzTnVhcXhnWTBFV2F3?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 2 Jul 2025 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>HOLOSTARS English to Host a Welcome Giveaway Campaign in Celebration of New Social Media Accounts!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250702-01-174/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 2 Jul 2025 01:00:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) has announced a HOLOSTARS English Welcome Giveaway campaign in celebration of two new official social media accounts.The followers’ welcoming giveaway, taking place on X, Instagram, and TikTok, will last from July 1st until July 23rd JST, with a total of 30 winners across the three campaigns.Nine of these lucky winners will be eligible to receive three 3D Acrylic Stands of their choice from HOLOSTARS English -TEMPUS- or HOLOSTARS English -ARMIS-, while 21 winners will be eligible to receive one holoEmblem Pin Badge of their choice, also from HOLOSTARS English -TEMPUS- or HOLOSTARS English -ARMIS-.HOLOSTARS English Welcome Giveaway
July 1st 10:00AM – July 23rd at 1:00PM JST
30 winners across 3 social media platforms will be contacted on July 25th at 12:00PM JST.*Followers must participate with a public account that can accept private messages for a chance to win.
– The user must be following the official HOLOSTARS English X account.
– The user must give the giveaway post a Like.
– The user must give the giveaway post a Repost.
3D Acrylic Stands of the Winner’s Choice (Qty:3) : 3 winners
holoEmblem Pin Badge of the Winner’s Choice (Qty:1) : 7 winners
– The user must be following the official HOLOSTARS English Instagram account.
– The user must give the giveaway post a Like.
– The user must comment on the giveaway post with three oshimarks of their favorite talents.
3D Acrylic Stands of the Winner’s Choice (Qty:3) : 3 winners
holoEmblem Pin Badge of the Winner’s Choice (Qty:1) : 7 winners
– The user must be following the official HOLOSTARS English X account.
– The user must give the giveaway post a Like.
– The user must comment on the giveaway post with three oshimarks of their favorite talents.
3D Acrylic Stands of the Winner’s Choice (Qty:3) : 3 winners
holoEmblem Pin Badge of the Winner’s Choice (Qty:1) : 7 winners]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive English Teams Up with Kura Sushi USA for an Exclusive Summer Collaboration!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250702-01-173/</link><author>os_pr</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 1 Jul 2025 23:55:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[July 2, 2025, Tokyo, Japan – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) has announced that hololive English of hololive production is collaborating with Kura Sushi USA. The exclusive campaign is running from July 1st until July 31st, 2025.hololive English × Kura Sushi: Exclusive Collab Experience Across the U.S.!A limited-time campaign is rolling out at Kura Sushi locations across the U.S. from July 1st to 31st, featuring three hololive English talents — , , and ! Don’t miss out on this exciting experience, with specially crafted menu items and immersive in-store elements designed for fans and food enthusiasts alike.Kura Sushi USA x hololive English Exclusive Sushi DishesEnjoy three original dishes inspired by Ninomae Ina’nis, Ouro Kronii, and Gigi Murin! is honored with the Spicy Crunchy Squid, featuring squid tempura topped with spicy mayo, eel sauce, and bonito flakes over Kura’s specialty sushi rice. influence comes to life in the Tuna with Avocado Cream Cheese, which pairs soy-marinated tuna with avocado and cream cheese over Kura’s specialty sushi rice. is represented by the vibrant Salmon & Tamago Spicy Roll, made with spicy salmon and tamago atop a shrimp mayo roll finished with panko crunchy flakes.Exclusive hololive English × Kura Sushi USA Goods to Complement the Culinary Experience!Kura Sushi USA x hololive English bottle set
Available starting July 1st, 2025 for , while supplies last.*1 design in total; limited to three per party. Available for purchase in-restaurant only.Kura Sushi USA x hololive English cooling towel and carrying case set
Available from July 21st with a minimum spend of  in-store at participating locations, while supplies last.*1 design in total; limited to three per party.Get Immersed in the Summer Festivities at hololive English Themed Stores!Participating Kura Sushi USA locations will feature hololive English themed in-store decorations throughout the duration of the promotion, transforming the dining experience into a fully immersive, fan-centric celebration.“We’re incredibly excited to partner with hololive English for our first U.S.-based VTuber collaboration,” said , President and CEO of Kura Sushi USA, Inc. “This campaign offers a one-of-a-kind experience that blends fan culture with Kura’s passion for innovation and fun.”About Kura Sushi USA, Inc.Kura Sushi USA, Inc. is a technology-enabled Japanese restaurant concept with over 76 locations across the United States. Known for its revolving sushi bar experience and commitment to quality ingredients, Kura Sushi USA is a subsidiary of Kura Sushi, Inc., which has operated in Japan for over 45 years since 1977.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>New Hololive Event Gives Ouro Kronii &amp; Friends Stunning Makeovers for Limited Edition Release - Comic Book Resources</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidEFVX3lxTFA3NEw4bG5DOEpQRXB4eFpGbUFJVklzM1JhdFQzTUZ0TEE0NThaTzB2alZrVmVzZnNSQURXemNoWWlybkYwXzhrb2Y2aVBTNU13RDAwdjhVMVlXQmlJeHlPdi0wT2lqT0FaQWxDQlRMdFgxVkNS?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 1 Jul 2025 00:05:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>