<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>hololive</title><link>https://asideaside.github.io/feed/</link><description></description><item><title>常闇トワ＆獅白ぼたんのサイン入り色紙が当たる！『灰仭巫覡』新PV＆オリジナルソング公開記念キャンペーン開催</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/towabotan/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 4 Sep 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan site (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[大暮維人先生が描く人気漫画『灰仭巫覡（カイジンフゲキ）』のオリジナルソングと新PVの公開を記念し、2025年9月5日より豪華プレゼントキャンペーンがスタートしました。新PV公開！常闇トワ＆獅白ぼたんが歌うオリジナルソング2025年9月3日、講談社の「マガジンチャンネル」にて『灰仭巫覡』の新たなプロモーションビデオが公開されました。このPVのために書き下ろされたオリジナルソング『君と明かした夜』は、ホロライブ所属の人気VTuberである常闇トワさんと獅白ぼたんさんが歌唱を担当。今回の発表を記念して、抽選で1名様にが当たるキャンペーンが開催されます。『灰仭巫覡』公式X（旧Twitter）アカウント（@KAIJINFUGEKI_WM）をフォロー ※「#灰仭巫覡PV公開」「#カイジンフゲキ」のハッシュタグが付いたポストが目印です。 2025年9月5日（金）0:00 〜 2025年9月14日（日）23:59まで 利用規約に同意し、日本国内にお住まいで郵便物・宅配物の受け取りが可能な方。注意事項：色紙には当選者の宛名が記載されます。当選者にはXのダイレクトメッセージにて連絡があります。 『灰仭巫覡』コミックス第1巻から第5巻まで好評発売中です。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【速報】戌神ころね、ホンダのeスポーツ大会アンバサダーに2年連続で就任！→本人も「よろしくお願いします」と意気込み「世界の戌神」「今年もきた！」</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/korone-22/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan site (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[人気VTuberグループ「ホロライブ」所属の戌神ころねさんが、本田技研工業（Honda）が主催するeモータースポーツのグローバル大会「Honda Racing eMS 2025」の公式アンバサダーに、昨年に引き続き就任したことが発表されました。このニュースに、ファンからは「2年連続はすごすぎる！」「今年も応援します！」といった声が相次いでいます。「Honda Racing eMS」は、世界3地区（アジア・オセアニア、米州、欧州・中東・アフリカ）のトップドライバーたちが地域最速の座をかけて競い合う、本格的なeモータースポーツのグローバル大会です。戌神さんは「Honda Racing eMS 2024」でもアンバサダーを務めており、今回で2年連続という大役を担うことになります。ゲーム実況で人気を誇る戌神ころねと、世界のHondaとのコラボが再び実現しました。2025年8月26日、Honda Racing eMSの公式X（旧Twitter）アカウントが「━ Honda Racing eMS 2025 開催 ━ 昨年に続き『戌神ころね』が公式アンバサダーに！」とポストし、戌神さんのアンバサダー就任を正式に発表。あわせて、されるという大会スケジュールも公開しました。この公式発表に対し、戌神さん本人も自身のXアカウントで「今年もアンバサダーを務めさせていただきます！よろしくお願いします」と引用ポストし、就任への意気込みを表明しました。この就任のニュースに、ファンからは「世界のHondaに認められた女、戌神ころね」「ころさんの影響力すごい！」「これを機にレースゲームに挑戦してみようかな」など、驚きと喜びのコメントがありました。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ3期生、Kアリーナ横浜で2DAYSライブ開催決定！「#きゅるるん大作戦」チケット受付開始</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/arena/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:56:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan site (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[「ホロライブ」所属の3期生（兎田ぺこら、不知火フレア、白銀ノエル、宝鐘マリン）によるライブイベント「hololive 3rd Generation Live #きゅるるん大作戦 〜最強アイドル、推すしかないでしょ〜」を、に「Kアリーナ横浜」にて開催することを発表しました。本ライブは、「ホロライブ」所属の3期生4名が出演するライブイベントです。本日10月19日（日）21:00より、現地会場指定席チケットの1次先行（hololive FANCLUB先行 / 抽選）が開始されるとともに、「ABEMA」「SPWN」「ZAIKO」にて配信チケットの販売も開始されました。チケット情報などライブの最新情報は、下記特設サイト及び開催概要をご確認ください。hololive 3rd Generation Live #きゅるるん大作戦 〜最強アイドル、推すしかないでしょ〜 概要 hololive 3rd Generation Live #きゅるるん大作戦 〜最強アイドル、推すしかないでしょ〜 主催：カバー株式会社 兎田ぺこら 不知火フレア 白銀ノエル 宝鐘マリンDAY1 ： 2026年1月17日（土） 開場 16:30 / 配信開始 17:30 / 開演 18:00DAY2 ： 2026年1月18日（日） 開場 15:30 / 配信開始 16:30 / 開演 17:00 Kアリーナ横浜 （〒220-8507 神奈川県横浜市西区みなとみらい6丁目2−14） 最寄り駅 〇新高島駅 みなとみらい線4臨港パーク口より徒歩5分 〇みなとみらい駅 みなとみらい線2いちょう通り口より徒歩12分 ※お1人様2枚までお申し込み可能です。 ※チケット氏名印字あり。■1次先行（hololive FANCLUB先行 / 抽選）受付期間：2025年10月19日（日）21:00 ～ 2025年10月29日（水） 23:59当選確認期間・入金期間：2025年11月5日（水）15:00 ～ 2025年11月9日（日）23:00※お申し込みには、hololive FANCLUBへの入会が必要となります。※別途手数料（先行サービス料440円、システム利用料330円、電子チケット利用料110円）がかかります。受付期間：2025年11月13日（木）21:00 ～ 2025年11月23日（日）23:59当選確認期間・入金期間：2025年11月28日（金）15:00 ～ 2025年12月1日（月）23:00※別途手数料（先行サービス料440円、システム利用料330円、電子チケット利用料110円）がかかります。受付期間・発券開始：2025年12月14日（日）12:00 ～※別途手数料（システム利用料330円、電子チケット利用料110円）がかかります。 2025年10月19日（日）21:00 ～ 2026年2月18日（水）20:00 公演終了後、公開準備ができ次第アーカイブ視聴可能となり、2026年2月18日（水）23:59 まで何度でもご視聴いただけます。 ※2026年2月18日（水）23:59 を過ぎると、アーカイブ視聴中でも視聴できなくなります。 ※プラットフォームごとに別途手数料が発生する場合があります。本公演開催に合わせ、本日10月19日（日）よりhololive 3rd Generation Live #きゅるるん大作戦 〜最強アイドル、推すしかないでしょ〜のライブグッズが解禁されました。 2025年10月19日（日）21:00 ～ 2025年11月25日（火）18:00 まで販売期間や注意事項・詳細は、公式HPの販売ページなどをご確認ください。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>「一番くじ ホロライブ ～Villain Style～」が2026年1月10日より発売決定！</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/%e3%80%8c%e4%b8%80%e7%95%aa%e3%81%8f%e3%81%98-%e3%83%9b%e3%83%ad%e3%83%a9%e3%82%a4%e3%83%96-%ef%bd%9evillain-style%ef%bd%9e%e3%80%8d%e3%81%8c2026%e5%b9%b41%e6%9c%8810%e6%97%a5%e3%82%88%e3%82%8a/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 9 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan site (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[VTuberグループ「ホロライブ」の新たな一番くじ、「一番くじ ホロライブ ～Villain Style～」の発売が決定しました！今回のテーマは「Villain Style」。いつもとは一味違った、ダークで魅力的なホロライブメンバーの姿が描かれることが期待されます。ファンにとっては見逃せないラインナップとなりそうです。 一番くじ ホロライブ ～Villain Style～ 2026年01月10日(土)より順次発売予定]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ときのそら、史上最大規模のワンマンライブを東京国際フォーラムで開催決定！「夢が叶った！」「絶対行く！」とファン歓喜</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/sora-18/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 9 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan site (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブプロダクション所属のVTuber「ときのそら」さんが、自身の活動史上最大規模となるワンマンライブの開催を発表。　ホロライブ0期生としてVTuberシーンの黎明期から業界を牽引してきた「ときのそら」さんが、にて、ワンマンライブ「New Year’s Party 2026『Dreams in Motion』」を開催することを発表しました。ときのそらさんにとって史上最大規模となる本公演でSNSではファンから「国際フォーラムはすごすぎる！」「そらちゃんの夢がまた一つ叶う瞬間に立ち会えるなんて…」といった歓喜の声が相次ぎました。“そらとも”と共に描く「Dreams in Motion」今回のライブは、ときのそらさんが毎年開催している恒例のニューイヤーパーティ、通称「そらぱ」の特別版。公演タイトルの「Dreams in Motion（ドリームズ・イン・モーション）」には、夢に向かって歩み続けるときのそらさん自身と、その姿を見守り、応援し続けるファン＝“そらとも”の想いが込められているとのこと。本公演は、昼公演＜Day＞と夜公演＜Night＞の2部構成で開催。それぞれ異なる演出が期待されています。チケットは、最前エリアが確約され、Tシャツや無線制御ペンライト、限定ボイスなどの豪華特典が付いたSS席（¥18,800）から、学生にも優しい学割チケット（¥5,150）まで、幅広い券種が用意されています。また、遠方のファンに向けた配信チケットも販売され、こちらも限定グッズ付きのプランが用意されるなど、すべての“そらとも”が楽しめる配慮がなされています。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>星街すいせい、新曲「月に向かって撃て」が新作アニメ『真夜中ハートチューン』OPテーマに決定！</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/suisei-49/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 6 Jan 2026 00:53:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan site (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ所属のVTuber、星街すいせいの新曲「月に向かって撃て」が、2026年1月より放送開始となるTVアニメ『真夜中ハートチューン』のオープニングテーマ（OP）に決定したことが発表されました。本日、TVアニメ『真夜中ハートチューン』の公式X（旧Twitter）アカウント（@anime_mayochu）にてPV第2弾が公開され、あわせて主題歌情報が解禁となりました。星街すいせいが歌う「月に向かって撃て」が、本作のオープニングを飾ります。なお、エンディングテーマ（ED）はSoalaさんの「声の軌跡」に決定しています。TVアニメ『真夜中ハートチューン』は、2026年1月6日(火)23時より、カンテレ・フジテレビ系全国ネット“火アニバル!!”枠、BS朝日ほかにて放送開始予定です。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ、年末恒例のカウントダウンライブ開催決定！ 発表に「これがないと年越せない！」</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/holo-5/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan site (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[VTuber事務所「ホロライブプロダクション」は9月5日、公式X（旧Twitter）にて、年末恒例の大型ライブ『hololive production COUNTDOWN LIVE 2025▷2026』を、2025年12月31日（水）に開催することを発表した。この待望のニュースに、ファンからは「やっぱりこれがないと年は越せない！」「全編無料はありがたすぎる」といった喜びの声が殺到している。年末の風物詩！所属タレントがほぼ総出演する豪華ライブホロライブプロダクションが毎年大晦日に開催するカウントダウンライブは、所属タレントが一堂に会する、まさしく”お祭り”と呼ぶにふさわしい一大イベントだ。ホロライブ、ホロスターズの所属タレントのほぼ全員が3Dで出演し、オリジナル曲やこの日限りの特別ユニットによるパフォーマンスを全編無料で配信。年々スケールアップする圧巻のクオリティと、幸福感に満ちた演出で世界中のファンを魅了してきた。昨年開催された『hololive production COUNTDOWN LIVE 2024▷2025』では、60名を超えるタレントが出演。バラエティ企画満載の『ゆくホロくるホロ』からライブ本編へと繋がる構成で、ファンを飽きさせない工夫が凝らされていた。今年も同様の形式が期待されており、どのタレントがどんな楽曲を披露するのか、期待が高まっている。この発表に、ファンからは「うおおおお！今年も来た！生きる理由をありがとう！」「毎年クオリティが上がり続けてるから今年も楽しみすぎる」「全編無料…？ホロライブの福利厚生、手厚すぎ！」「大晦日の予定、即決しました」といった歓喜のコメントが殺到。また、「推しと推しのユニットが見たい！」「今年はどんな絡みがあるかな？」など、具体的なパフォーマンス内容を予想し、胸を膨らませる声も多く見られた。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>NePoLaBo Live Photo Contest Results</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/nepolabophotoresult/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 10:01:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Greetings from the Holoearth Management Team!We are pleased to announce the results of the photo contest for the December 21, 2025 virtual concert “NePoLaBo Live re:VISION Holoearth Live.”
Thank you for the many great submissions! All of the entries that conveyed the love for NePoLaBo and the passion of the performance moved the entire staff.After a careful review, the winning entries that shone especially brightly have been selected and are presented here.
They are also posted on bulletin boards in Alternative City in Holoearth, so be sure to check them out!This composition, emphasizing the bond between Nene and all the Nekko fans, captured our hearts!This shot powerfully captures the charm of Nene the idol!Polka is looking at me! This shot really shows the sense of presence that makes you feel you are really there with the talent!It is moving to see Polka giving such an intense, passionate performance before her fans!A focus on Lamy unique to viewing in Holoearth! The sense and creativity here are amazing!A stunningly beautiful shot packed with Lamy’s beauty and cuteness!A cute, dynamic shot capturing the ever-energetic Botan! Very kawaii!Botan locking eyes with her sharp, cool gaze! Absolutely captivating!This shot perfectly captures the close bond between the four members of NePoLaBo!Another brilliant shot that makes you feel the charm of the four as performers!Holoearth Tourism Agency Honorable MentionAlthough it did not meet certain entry requirements and could not be selected, we were blown away by this unique composition idea and decided to give it an honorable mention!
(The honorary mention is featured only in this article.)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Mining Base Reveals hololive English Collaboration Gaming PC Collection</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20251229-mining-base-reveals-hololive-english-collaboration-gaming-pc-collection/</link><author>Horii</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 07:50:57 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[December 29, 2025, Tokyo, JAPAN – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) has announced a new merchandise collaboration with Mining Base Co., Ltd in partnership with hololive production, featuring talents from hololive English -Myth- and hololive English -Promise-.This collaboration introduces a special series of hololive English collaboration PC products, combining Mining Base’s advanced PC hardware expertise with designs inspired by the worlds and personalities of hololive English talents. Each item is crafted to deliver both high performance and strong visual presence, staying true to Astromeda’s concept of “gaming PCs designed to be displayed.”The lineup includes a wide range of items, from fully built PCs to customizable accessories, allowing fans to enjoy the collaboration at multiple levels.For more information, please visit Mining Base’s official website and social media platforms.
7 models × 2 versions: Myth / Promise
Mini Rubber Type
(Each available in Myth / Promise designs)・ Interchangeable Panel Sets
2 types: Myth / Promise
2 types: Myth / Promise
From December 29, 2025 to December 29, 2026
Available exclusively in JapanAstromeda is a gaming PC brand launched in 2018, created to redefine the image of gaming PCs as part of interior design rather than devices hidden under desks. From its early days, Astromeda gained attention for its industry leading illuminated designs, transforming the conventional perception of gaming PCs as plain and invisible.In recent years, Astromeda has actively developed collaboration models with various IPs, popular anime, and game titles, leveraging its unique design philosophy and craftsmanship. These special edition PCs, carefully designed to reflect each collaboration’s world and aesthetic, have received high praise from fans.With the concept of “a gaming PC you want to place on your desk,” Astromeda continues to focus not only on performance, but also on the value of visual appeal, aiming to make everyday PC life more enjoyable and more personal.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>New Year Period Holoearth Service Inquiries &amp; Creator Item Review Hours</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/businessdays/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 08:41:51 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Greetings from the Holoearth Management Team!Holoearth support hours during the New Year period will change as follows regarding Holoearth service inquiries and the Creator item review process.
Closed between Dec 30, 2025 – Jan 4, 2026.
(Responses will resume in order from Jan 5, 2026.)
Item reviews will continue during this period
(Some items may take additional time to process.)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive production COUNTDOWN LIVE 2025▷2026 × Holoearth Special Guests Announcement</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/countdown2025guest/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 08:10:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Greetings from the Holoearth Management Team!Natsuiro Matsuri, Otonose Kanade, Kikirara Vivi, and Rindo Chihaya will appear as special guests for “hololive production COUNTDOWN LIVE 2025▷2026 × Holoearth,” to be held in Holoearth on December 31, 2025.
Be sure to enjoy the watch party with the talents in Holoearth!
(Schedule is subject to change.)
Anyone can join in the festivities for free by downloading and installing Holoearth.
(Note: Holoearth is available only for Windows.)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dec 31 COUNTDOWN LIVE Watch Party &amp; Kyo-no-Miyako Reopening Announcement</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/countdown2025/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 08:09:41 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Greetings from the Holoearth Management Team!The event “hololive production COUNTDOWN LIVE 2025▷2026,” presented by hololive production on December 31, 2025, will also be streamed within Holoearth.
Enjoy watching the show together and spend the final moments of 2025 in Holoearth!
(Schedule is subject to change.)
Anyone can join in the festivities for free by downloading and installing Holoearth.
(Note: Holoearth is available only for Windows.)Starting at 18:00 (JST) on Sunday, December 28, 2025, Kyo-no-Miyako will reopen for a limited time.
New additions include photo spots and a large theater screen for simultaneous viewing.
At the shrine filled with a New Year’s atmosphere, be sure to draw an “omikuji” fortune and try your luck for 2026.
(Schedule is subject to change.)New Shop: “Gofukuya Tsubaki”A new avatar fashion shop, “Gofukuya Tsubaki,” will open in Kyo-no-Miyako.
Enjoy the New Year in Holoearth wearing gorgeous outfits inspired by traditional Japanese aesthetics.
(Schedule is subject to change.)・Gofukuya Tsubaki Luck Haori (Cr)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Luck Haori (Yel)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Luck Haori (Blu)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Luck Dress (Cr)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Luck Dress (Yel)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Luck Dress (Cyn)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Underwear (Blk)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Underwear (Gry)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Underwear (Blu)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Leggings (Bn)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Leggings (Gry)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Leggings (Ecru)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Setta (NvyCr)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Setta (BnOr)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Setta (NvyBlu)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Sandals (Cr)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Sandals (Yel)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Sandals (Cyn)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Gloves (Blk)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Gloves (Pewt)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Gloves (Nvy)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Fur Scarf (Nat)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Fur Scarf (Ecru)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Fur Scarf (Pr)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Kanzashi (Cr)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Kanzashi (Yel)
・Gofukuya Tsubaki Kanzashi (Cyn)New Avatar Customization OptionsNew avatar customization options including hairstyles and face accents will be added.
Hairstyles and face accents can be unlocked at the Salon & Clinic “ALT BEAUTYS.”
December 28, 2025 (Sun) from 18:00 (JST)
(Schedule is subject to change.)Hair (Bangs)
・Casual Rough Bangs
Hair (Back)
・Curly Side Tail
・Asymmetrical Long Curl
・Asymmetrical Outward Curl
Face Accents
・PlumTo celebrate the reopening of Kyo-no-Miyako, a new gesture, “Omairi” (shrine visit), will be gifted to users.
During the event period, simply log in to Holoearth to receive it in the gift box of the HoloPhone menu (H key).
Note: This is the same gesture that was available previously.
(Schedule is subject to change.)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>『セガNET麻雀 MJ』「ホロライブ」の「博衣こより」さんとコラボ！“第3回ホロライブCUP”開催</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000007046.000005397.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/5397/7046/5397-7046-b8620a5b479667137fa8a41b4be63193-669x230.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 19:37:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>NePoLaBo 3D Archive Special Session: “NePoLaBo Live re:VISION Holoearth Live”</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/nepolabo-livesp/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:19:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Watch the 3D Archive With NePoLaBo!Greetings from the Holoearth Management Team!The virtual concert “NePoLaBo Live re:VISION Holoearth Live,” which was held in Holoearth on December 21, is available as a 3D archive.Cast: hololive 5th Generation “NePoLaBo” (Momosuzu Nene / Omaru Polka / Yukihana Lamy / Shishiro Botan)A special 3D archive viewing session has been officially announced, where you can attend the concert once again! In this session, hololive 5th Generation “NePoLaBo” (Momosuzu Nene / Omaru Polka / Yukihana Lamy / Shishiro Botan) will appear in Holoearth and participate together with everyone.Join the event once again—together with NePoLaBo!Watch together with NePoLaBo!3D Archive Special Session: “NePoLaBo Live re:VISION Holoearth Live”Date & time(Schedule is subject to change.)An “Urya-oi!” Event Together with NePoLaBo!During this special 3D archive session, to celebrate the release of Momosuzu Nene’s all-out “wotagei” “Urya-oi!” gesture, a special event will be held where everyone joins together with the NePoLaBo members to fill the venue with chants of “Urya-oi! Urya-oi!”.Everyone together, let’s go!
“Urya-oi! Urya-oi! Urya-oi! Urya-oi!”Feel free to practice in advance!Missed the show? Experience the Magic With the 3D Archive!With the 3D archive, where the entire venue has been preserved, you can relive the concert experience. View it from any angle in 360 degrees, focus on your oshi, take photos, and re-live your favorite moments.If you already purchased an ID Holder, you can participate again; if you do not yet have one, you can attend by purchasing it.Perhaps that certain someone may even casually drop in at some point, too…?
Be sure not to miss out on the 3D archive!
Dec 21, 2025 (Sun) 21:00 – Jan 4, 2026 (Sun) 23:59.
(1) 8:00〜 (2) 12:00〜 (3) 19:00〜 (4) 21:00〜 (5) 23:00〜Watch Anytime During the Archive Period with the SPWN / ZAIKO Streaming ArchiveIf you are unable to attend in Holoearth, the stream archive is available with SPWN or ZAIKO!
3,500 yen (tax inclusive)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The “Urya-oi!” Wotagei Gesture Performed by Momosuzu Nene at NePoLaBo Live is Now on Sale!</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/uryaoi/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 09:26:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[“Urya-oi” Wotagei Gesture Now Available!Greetings from the Holoearth Management Team!The virtual concert “NePoLaBo Live re:VISION Holoearth Live,” held on December 21 in Holoearth, is currently available as a 3D archive experience.Cast: hololive 5th Generation “NePoLaBo” (Momosuzu Nene / Omaru Polka / Yukihana Lamy / Shishiro Botan)We are excited to announce the release of the “Urya-oi!” “wotagei” gesture that Momosuzu Nene performed during the special Holoearth-exclusive post-performance segment!This gesture was made possible in response to requests from the NePoLaBo members during the show, and recreates Momosuzu Nene’s all-out wotagei performance.Missed the show? Experience the Magic With the 3D Archive!With the 3D archive, where the entire venue has been preserved, you can relive the concert experience. View it from any angle in 360 degrees, focus on your oshi, take photos, and re-live your favorite moments.If you already purchased an ID Holder, you can participate again; if you do not yet have one, you can attend by purchasing it.Perhaps that certain someone may even casually drop in at some point, too…?
Be sure not to miss out on the 3D archive!
Dec 21, 2025 (Sun) 21:00 – Jan 4, 2026 (Sun) 23:59.
(1) 8:00〜 (2) 12:00〜 (3) 19:00〜 (4) 21:00〜 (5) 23:00〜Watch Anytime During the Archive Period with the SPWN / ZAIKO Streaming ArchiveIf you are unable to attend in Holoearth, the stream archive is available with SPWN or ZAIKO!
3,500 yen (tax inclusive)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ver. 1.2.0.1 Release Notes</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/ver1201_updatenotice/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 08:11:41 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Greetings from the Holoearth Management Team!Holoearth was updated on December 23, 2025.■ 
Fixed an issue where the error that shows when trying to enter a full room is no longer displayed when entering a busy room.■ Simple Semi-Wide Headband (Blk) fix
Fixed an issue where Simple Semi-Wide Headband (Blk) appeared as white.■ The transparency settings configuration in Creator Tools for UGC items are not properly reflected on the in-game items.
■ During night time some furniture items and monsters appear completely black.These two issues will be fixed at a later date.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>“Cosmic Wonderful Tour! -Christmas Remix-” Digital Release Announcement</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/cosmicwonderfultour/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 05:23:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Greetings from the Holoearth Management Team!The song “Cosmic Wonderful Tour! -Christmas Remix-“—first performed for “NePoLaBo Live re:VISION Holoearth Live”—was released digitally at midnight JST on December 23!Title: Cosmic Wonderful Tour! -Christmas Remix-
Artists: hololive 5th Generation
Composition: Takuya Sakai
Arrangement: Hylen (Hifumi,inc.)■
Digital distribution■
Midnight (JST) December 23 (Tue), 2025]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>年末特別企画「アベマでホロライブ2025 ～年末過去ライブ一挙放送12時間SP～」を12月28日（日…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000002477.000064643.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/64643/2477/64643-2477-cf87981025d62d4f9b72facd6ac225ba-1500x844.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:53:59 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Breaking Report: “NePoLaBo Live re:VISION Holoearth Live” Held! Concert Footage, 3D Archive, and Outfits Now on Sale!</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/nepolabo-liverepo/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 09:03:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Holoearth-exclusive segmentFrom here on is a special segment only for those who joined via Holoearth.
While savoring the afterglow of the performance, everyone also enjoyed a commemorative group photo session.The first song, “Hyper Jumpin’,” and MC Part 1 are available as a free preview on YouTube.
Be sure to check it out!Outfits worn by the four NePoLaBo members are now available!
In addition to the NePoLaBo Live Celebration T All Members Ver. designed by NePoLaBo,
the “Pathfinder Outfits” inspired by the four members are also now on sale.
・NePoLaBo Live Celebration T All Members Ver. (No Signature)
Dec 21 (Thu), 2025 from 20:00 (JST)
・Pathfinder Jacket SE Momosuzu Nene
・Pathfinder Jacket SE Omaru Polka
・Pathfinder Jacket SE Yukihana Lamy
・Pathfinder Jacket SE Shishiro Botan
・Pathfinder Sneakers SE Momosuzu Nene
・Pathfinder Sneakers SE Omaru Polka
・Pathfinder Sneakers SE Yukihana Lamy
・Pathfinder Sneakers SE Shishiro BotanKeep the sparkle of that night with you forever.
The concert key visual is now available as an acrylic panel and acrylic stands.The NePoLaBo Live items from Holoearth have taken physical form in the real world.
Be sure to get yours and relive the excitement of the event.
Price
3,300 JPY each (tax inclusive).Acrylic Stand (Momosuzu Nene, Omaru Polka, Yukihana Lamy, Shishiro Botan)
Price
2,420 JPY each (tax inclusive).Relive the Experience With the 3D Archive!Rejoin the live through the fully-preserved 3D archive of the concert space.Since it can be viewed from any angle in 360 degrees, you can enjoy perspectives you normally would not get to experience, focus on your favorite member, take photos, or re-live moments that caught your attention.Those who have already purchased an ID Holder can participate again.
If you do not yet have an ID Holder, you can join by purchasing one.You might even see that oshi casually “drop in” sometime…
Do not miss out on the 3D archive!
Sunday, December 21, 2025, 21:00 – Sunday, January 4, 2026, 23:59
(1) 08:00~ (2) 12:00~ (3) 19:00~ (4) 21:00~ (5) 23:00~Watch the Stream Version on SPWN or ZAIKOIf you cannot attend in Holoearth, you can watch the archived stream on SPWN or ZAIKO.
3,500 JPY (tax inclusive)Support Campaign NePoLaBo Live Photo ContestFor “NePoLaBo Live re:VISION Holoearth Live,” screenshots & social media posts are fully welcome.
Share your perfect captures with us!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dec 22 Avatar Item Restock Notice</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/restocking251222/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 08:24:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This is the Holoearth Management Team.Certain avatar fashion items were restocked on December 22, 2025.
Active Summer Goggles Set (Blu)
ALTERMODE Wide Leg Shorts (Vlt)
ALTERMODE Wide Leg Shorts (Bn)
Night Town Gothic Pants (Blk)
ALTERMODE Boots (Wh)
Smart Town Use Dual Bars (Slv)
Smart Town Use Dual Bars (RedGld
Night Town Gothic Gloves (Wh)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>『セガNET麻雀 MJ』「ホロライブ」の「AZKi」さん、「ラプラス・ダークネス」さんとコラボ！ “…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000007021.000005397.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/5397/7021/5397-7021-f8e5bfd64cf2daacbb421f9163ef2f3e-669x230.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 18:26:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>『Dinkum（ディンカム）』Steam ウィンターセール2025に参加！</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000360.000082433.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/82433/360/82433-360-78e6362202884ce9fc4de3f04c2ca33b-1920x1080.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 18:26:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ×ドゥームズデイ：ラストサバイバー コラボイベントを開催！AZKi・雪花ラミィと一緒にゲー…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000534.000020234.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/20234/534/20234-534-556b2a7afc9e009ec82919f7a7e06860-1920x1080.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 18:26:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ReGLOSS 1st Live “Flashpoint” のオフィシャルレポート公開！@有明アリー…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000001209.000030268.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/30268/1209/30268-1209-997315e486c110c940d8705a6e32280d-1920x1080.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 18:26:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>OTAKU x hololive English Advent VS Justice Collaboration Merchandise Launch</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20251219-01-214/</link><author>Horii</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 08:50:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[December 19, 2025, Tokyo, JAPAN – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) has announced a new merchandise collaboration with OTAKU in partnership with hololive production, featuring talents from hololive English -Advent- and hololive English -Justice.This collaboration introduces a brand new lineup of premium merchandise inspired by the concept of “hololive English Advent VS Justice,” designed to celebrate the unique personalities and worlds of the participating talents. Every item has been carefully crafted with exceptional quality.Products will be available for purchase and ready to ship from launch, while apparel items will be listed as pre-sale, with shipping scheduled for May 2026.For more information, please visit OTAKU’s official website and social media platforms.December 19, 2025 (9:00 AM EST) to December 31, 2025 (11:59 PM EST)Available worldwide (excluding mainland China)
OTAKU is a lifestyle brand dedicated to creating high quality merchandise inspired by global fandom culture. With a strong focus on craftsmanship and design, OTAKU aims to deliver products that fans can proudly display and enjoy in their everyday lives.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Nintendo Switch™︎『ホロライブごろごろマウンテンDX』発売開始！年内は10%OFF！…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000066.000104705.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/104705/66/104705-66-de51d0fa5abaf1014d77a3573a2e5ef3-1920x1080.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:46:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>&quot;推し&quot;とシンクロするオンクレバトル『バウンティハンターズ』、「ホロライブ」人気VTuberとの配信…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000023.000121280.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/121280/23/121280-23-a7c76734099873a0672779d2230335df-1500x1200.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:46:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>GRAPHT、「獅白ぼたんとクリスマス闘night Ⅱ」に協賛 2WAYアケコンボタンやスウェットな…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000052.000162957.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/162957/52/162957-52-3f2f05f1d977ff0fa4eca6f71e58b3eb-1920x1080.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 17:46:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ver. 1.2.0.0 Release Notes</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/ver1200_updatenotice/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 10:06:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This is the Holoearth Management Team.Holoearth was updated on December 18, 2025.Items & Customization OptionsThe following avatar fashion items were added.●Hats
・Happy Holidays Santa Hat (Red / Blu / Wh)●Tops
・Happy Holidays Santa Top (Red / Blu / Wh)●Bottoms
・Happy Holidays Santa Skirt (Red / Blu / Wh)●Socks
・Happy Holidays Thigh-Highs (RWh / Blk / Wh)●Shoes
・Happy Holidays Santa Boots (Bn / DkBn / Wh)●Eyewear
・Happy Holidays Santa ‘Stache Specs
・Mysterious Gothic Asym Mask (Blk / Wh / Pr)
・Mysterious Gothic Bat Specs (Blk / Pr / Wh)●Neck Accessories
・Happy Holidays Plaid Scarf (Gn / Blu / RWh)●Gloves
・Happy Holidays Santa Gloves (Red / Blu / Wh)●Hair Accessories
・Happy Holidays Hair Bow (Red / Blu / Wh)
・Mysterious Gothic Skel Hand (Wh / Blk / Red)
・Mysterious Gothic Bat Bow (Blk / Red / Vlt)The following customization options were added.●Hair (Bangs)
・Side-Swept Bangs●Hair (Back)
・Compact Short●Contacts
・Christmas
・Pastel Heart Heterochromia
・Pastel Heart Pink
・Deep Sea
・Bat Gothic●Face Accents
・Spider Web
・Spade
・Club
・Holly
・Snowflakes
・Colorful Stars
The following templates were added to Holoearth Marketplace.・Basic Santa Top (Red / Blue / White)
・Basic Santa Skirt (Red / Blue / White)
・Basic Santa Hat (Red / Blue / White)New text plates were added.・Christmas Text Plate 1 × 3
(Merry Xmas / Merry Christmas! / So awesome / It’s here! / Yaaay!)■Avatar Item Inventory Restock
A portion of avatar items were restocked.
・ALTERMODE Newsboy (Bn)
・
・
・
・Prem. Winter ’24 Beret (Wh)
・ALTERMODE Coat (Bg)
・ALTERMODE Jacket (Blk)
・Active Summer Half Jacket (Pk)
・Active Summer Half Jacket (Blu)
・Active Summer Short Jacket (Gn)
・Active Summer Short Jacket (Pk)
・Active Summer Short Jacket (Blu)
・Smart Town Use Off-Shoulder (Pk)
・Smart Town Use Off-Shoulder (Blu)
・Active Summer Underwear (Gry)
・Active Summer Long Underwear (Or)
・Active Summer Long Underwear (Gn)
・Active Summer Long Underwear (Pr)
・Night Town Gothic Lingerie (Blk)
・Night Town Gothic Lingerie (Wh)
・Pastel Spring Underwear (Pk)
・ALTERMODE Tri Joggers (Blk)
・ALTERMODE Wide Leg Shorts (Vlt)
・Active Summer Cargo Shorts (Blk)
・Active Summer Cargo Shorts (Wh)
・
・Active Summer Leggings (Blk)
・Active Summer Leggings (Wh)
・Night Town Gothic Shorts (Blk)
・Prem. Winter ’24 Skirt (Nvy)
・ALTERMODE Asymmetric Socks (Yel)
・ALTERMODE Asymmetric Socks (Pk)
・ALTERMODE Asymmetric Socks (Bg)
・Prem. Winter ’24 T. Socks (Nvy)
・ALTERMODE High Tops (Blk/Or)
・ALTERMODE High Tops (Wh)
・ALTERMODE Boots (Wh)
・Active Summer Mid-Tops (Yel)
・Active Summer Mid-Tops (Pk)
・Active Summer Mid-Tops (Blu)
・Active Summer High-Tops (Yel)
・Active Summer High-Tops (Blu)
・Smart Town Use Trim Boots (Pk)
・Night Town Gothic Heels (Blk)
・ALTERMODE Tri Shades (Or)
・ALTERMODE Tri Shades (Blu)
・Casual Town Use Glasses (Blk)
・Smart Town Use Wellingtons (Clr)
・Smart Town Use Wellingtons (Blu)
・Smart Town Use Dual Bars (Slv)
・Smart Town Use Dual Bars (RedGld)
・Night Town Gothic Gloves (Blk)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Guide: Getting the Most Out of Events in Holoearth!</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/guide2/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 07:00:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Hi there!
This is Anna Rocca from the Holoearth Tourism Agency.For today’s guide, I will introduce ways to better utilize Holoearth to improve your experience for NePoLaBo Live—enjoy using event items and gestures with everyone to really liven up the show!Please continue reading to be fully prepared for the day of the event!I will cover the following four categories this time:1. Interacting with other users with gestures.2. Using penlights with gestures.3. Adjusting options settings for a better experience.4. Using Photo Mode and participating in the photo contest.5. Adjusting “Visuals” for a better experience.One way to communicate with other users in Holoearth is with gestures.
Press and hold the B key to open the gesture setup screen.Click “Edit gestures” to display a list of gestures you have purchased, then drag and move the ones you want to set.You can set up a total of 9 sets of gestures, each using the F1-F8 keys, so try switching between them depending on the situation.You can wave penlights by combining them with gestures. You can set penlight items you have purchased in the hotbar at the bottom of the screen to make them faster to use.After doing this, click the shortcut button or press the corresponding keyboard number to use it.By combining it with gestures such as those in the “Hype Up” series, you will be able to wave the penlights.Adjusting audio settings is also useful for making the most out of a concert experience.
Press the Esc key to open the global options menu, then check the Sound section.By adjusting the Media volume, you can change the volume of the performance.
Set it to a level that feels comfortable for you and enjoy the show!For NePoLaBo Live, photography is allowed. You will want to capture a special memory of your own, right?Press P to switch to Photo Mode. Since you can shoot from many different angles, it offers more flexibility than a standard screenshot.Also, a photo contest is planned for the NePoLaBo Live!
Try posting your best shots on X with the hashtag #NePoLaBoHoloearthLive.
Your photo might be featured on the official website, or you could even receive a special gift…
For more details, check the URL below!Here, you can toggle features like “NaviRobo Display,” “Other Users’ Actions” (such as poppers or fireworks), and adjust the number of player models rendered in the area.
Enjoy the performance in a way suited just for you!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ファミリーマートは「衣食住」に”遊”を掛け合わせた「あそべるコンビニ」にチャレンジ 『ファミフェス2…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000002115.000046210.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/46210/2115/46210-2115-f09739e9df328640dc958094dd275ca6-3900x2600.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:45:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>推しと迎える特別な聖夜──荒野行動×ホロライブXmasコラボ開催！</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000589.000071247.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/71247/589/71247-589-98fbb847fc7b11a22f01e6ab388c169e-1920x1080.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:45:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Perfect for Christmas! New Fashion Items &amp; More Announcement</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/ver1200-update/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 09:08:03 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Greetings from the Holoearth Management Team!Holoearth is scheduled to be updated to ver. 1.2.0.0 on December 18, 2025.
The update will take place with maintenance scheduled as follows.
(Schedule is subject to change.)Continue reading for more details.New fashion items will be available at the fashion shop ALTERMODE.
Look forward to new outfits perfect for the Christmas and holiday season, as well as new accessories with an air of mystery.
Dec 18 (Thu) after maintenance.
(Schedule is subject to change.)
・Happy Holidays Santa Hat (Red / Blu / Wh)
・Happy Holidays Santa Top (Red / Blu / Wh)
・Happy Holidays Santa Skirt (Red / Blu / Wh)
・Happy Holidays Thigh-Highs (RWh / Blk / Wh)
・Happy Holidays Santa Boots (Bn / DkBn / Wh)
・Happy Holidays Santa ‘Stache Specs
・Mysterious Gothic Asym Mask (Blk / Wh / Pr)
・Mysterious Gothic Bat Specs (Blk / Pr / Wh)
・Happy Holidays Plaid Scarf (Gn / Blu / RWh)
・Happy Holidays Santa Gloves (Red / Blu / Wh)
・Happy Holidays Hair Bow (Red / Blu / Wh)
・Mysterious Gothic Skel Hand (Wh / Blk / Red)
・Mysterious Gothic Bat Bow (Blk / Red / Vlt)New fashion templates will be added to Holoearth Marketplace.
Dec 18 (Thu) after maintenance.
(Schedule is subject to change.)
・Basic Santa Top (Red / Blue / White)
・Basic Santa Skirt (Red / Blue / White)
・Basic Santa Hat (Red / Blue / White)“Holoearth Marketplace” is a service where users can create and sell digital fashion items and chat stickers in Holoearth.See details here.New Avatar Customization OptionsNew hairstyles, contacts, and face accents will be added after maintenance.Contacts can be purchased via the HoloPhone shop (H key).
Hair and face accents can be unlocked at the ALT BEAUTYS styling salon & clinic in Alternative City.
Dec 18 (Thu) after maintenance.
(Schedule is subject to change.)Hair (Bangs)
・Side-Swept Bangs
・Compact Short
・
・
・
・
・
・
・
・
・
Face Accents
・
・
・
・
・
・
・
・
・
・Text plate items will also be added that include phrases.
Dec 18 (Thu) after maintenance.
(Schedule is subject to change.)
・Christmas Text Plate 1 × 3
(Merry Xmas / Merry Christmas! / So awesome / It’s here! / Yaaay!)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Holoearth First-Timers &amp; How to Participate in NePoLaBo Live</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/guide/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 03:19:35 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Hi there!
This is Anna Rocca from the Holoearth Tourism Agency.With the upcoming virtual concert “NePoLaBo Live re:VISION Holoearth Live” on Sunday, December 21, 2025, I put together a brief guide for those who are new to Holoearth or who may be unfamiliar with how to use the service.Please continue reading to be fully prepared for the day of the event!To participate in the NePoLaBo Live concert in Holoearth, there are four things you will need to do, as listed below!1. Download for PC (Windows).
2. Register an account with Google or Apple ID.
3. Purchase the “NePoLaBo Live re:VISION ID Holder” item in the shop in Holoearth.
4. Enter the “NePoLaBo re:VISION Holoearth Live” area in Holoearth after 18:00 (JST) on Dec 21 (Sun).All that is needed to use Holoearth is a PC (Windows). No VR equipment is required.
See the download page for PC spec requirements.
Holoearth is only available for Windows.Feel free to use the following as a detailed reference guide for how to use Holoearth and participate!1: Installing Holoearth & Account CreationThe Holoearth application must first be downloaded and installed before using the service.Download the Holoearth launcher from the download pageDownload the Holoearth Launcher from the download page and install it.After installing the launcher, launch it via the “Holoearth Launcher” icon that was created.Click “Install” to begin the installation of the main Holoearth application.
After installation, this button will become the “Start” button.
When an update is available, the same button will change to “Update.”Launcher Installation TroubleshootingClick the gear icon in the upper right to open the launcher options menu, then choose “Support” from the menu and then “Open Log Folder” for the relevant error code that can be used when submitting a help inquiry.Account Creation & Logging InOnce installed, the launcher will display a “Start” button, which will open your web browser.If you do not yet have a Holoearth account, you will be prompted to create one, using either a Google account or Apple ID.Then, agree to the Terms of Service and Privacy Policy and click Register to finish and log in.Afterward, when Holoearth is installed and launched correctly the title menu will show the animated PV, “Now, discover your other world,” and prompt you to “CLICK TO START.”On starting Holoearth for the first time, you will be asked to create your own avatar.
Choose from a range of eyes, hairstyles, build options, skin tones, and more to create an avatar to your liking.
You can change your avatar freely in Holoearth later, so feel free to think more about it later!After creating an avatar and entering Holoearth, you can control your avatar using a mouse and keyboard.The above controls can also be confirmed in-app via the HoloPhone menu (H key) by selecting “Help.”■ Character movement
Move your avatar with WASD.Change camera angle with the mouse.■ Camera manipulation
Zoom with the mouse wheel.
Right click & drag to rotate your avatar.■ Opening menus
Esc brings up the global settings menu.
H opens the HoloPhone menu.
Tab opens inventory.4: Purchase the ID Holder ItemIt is necessary to purchase the in-app “NePoLaBo Live re:VISION ID Holder” in order to participate in NePoLaBo Live.
1. Choose Shop from the HoloPhone menu.
2. Purchase the event ID Holoder item.
Note: This item is also included in the NePoLaBo Cheer Set bundles.After purchasing, you will be able to enter the concert venue in Holoearth.
Note:5: How to Move to the Live Venue on Dec 211. Press H to bring up the HoloPhone menu and select “Change Area.”2. From the Area List, select the “Holoearth Live” area and click “Go.”Those who purchased the ID Holder will be able to also participate in the 3D archive after the first showing.Explore the event from different angles, take photos, and relive your favorite scenes.
The 3D archive is shown at certain times of day during the archive viewing period according to the following daily schedule:Daily showtimes (JST) between Dec 21, 21:00 (JST) – Jan 4, 23:59 (JST)
(1) 08:00~ (2) 12:00~ (3) 19:00~ (4) 21:00~ (5) 23:00~Note: The 3D archive may be played via the event venue screens for activities such as talent watch parties.6: More Tips for a Better ExperienceBy hitting the minus (“-“) key, you can hide the entire UI hud display to get an unobstructed view of the concert!And that wraps it up for getting started with Holoearth and participating in NePoLaBo Live. Next time, I will share tips on how to get the most out of the Holoearth concert experience, so please look forward to it!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ReGLOSS 初の単独ライブの感動を、全国のカラオケルームで！JOYSOUND「みるハコ」で1月1…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000002784.000004747.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/4747/2784/4747-2784-6be1698ac2cff1501b794adee44f0f8a-900x506.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:21:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Beard Papa’s × hololive English -Justice- Collab Begins in the United States from January 3, 2026</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20251216-01-213/</link><author>Horii</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:50:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[December 16, 2025, Tokyo, JAPAN – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) is pleased to announce a collaboration between hololive English -Justice- and world-famous fresh and natural cream puff chain Beard Papa’s. Beginning January 3rd, 2026 for a limited time, U.S. Beard Papa’s locations will debut four talent-inspired cream puffs, each themed after a member of the hololive English -Justice-.“We’re thrilled to collaborate with hololive English -Justice- on bringing the talents to life through our handcrafted cream puffs,” said Mark Nathan, Marketing Director of Beard Papa’s. “Fans love the creativity and personality of hololive’s talents, and this collaboration allowed us to create completely new flavors guided by each member’s input, while maintaining Beard Papa’s signature quality.”For more information, please visit Beard Papa’s official website and social media platforms.Limited-Edition Cream Puffs made together with hololive English -Justice-During the collaboration, fans can try Beard Papa’s iconic freshly baked puffs paired with flavor profiles crafted to reflect the personalities, color palettes, and motifs of each talent. These limited-edition flavors will be available for purchase at participating Beard Papa’s stores nationwide.Every flavor was developed with input from the talents themselves, resulting in cream puffs that authentically capture each member’s unique style and character. The flavors and puffs are as follows:A striking pink-raspberry chocolate shell with Oreo crumble and blue nonpareils, reflecting Elizabeth’s bold flair and engaging presence.A bright, refreshing matcha-white chocolate dip topped with soft mini marshmallows, capturing Cecilia’s calm, green aesthetic and happy energy.Rich dark Belgian chocolate custard paired with handmade orange crumble and finishing chocolate, inspired by Gigi’s bright colors and fun energy.A strawberry-vanilla crumble coating crowned with a disc-chocolate “hat,” reflecting Raora’s charisma and playful charm.Collector Combo Sets for a Unique Fan ExperienceTo complement the four limited-edition hololive English -Justice- talent’s cream puffs, fans can also purchase exclusive collaboration sets available in three formats.
The 4-Piece Set includes one of each talent flavor paired with a 4-sticker collectible pack featuring the hololive English -Justice- members.For guests looking to enjoy more, the 6-Piece Set includes all four talent puffs plus two Original Beard Papa’s cream puffs and comes with an exclusive acrylic keychain available only through this set.For the ultimate collector, the 12-Piece Set features two full 6-packs and is bundled with a limited-edition collaboration tote bag, making it the premium option for fans and families alike.The Beard Papa’s x hololive English -Justice- Collaboration Puffs will be available for a limited time at all participating Beard Papa’s locations across the U.S. Online orders will be available through the Beard Papa’s official app, website, and delivery partners in select markets.Originally founded in Osaka, Japan in 1999, Beard Papa’s has grown into a global dessert phenomenon known for its crisp shell, fluffy choux pastry, and all-natural cream fillings made fresh daily. With locations across the U.S. and over 550 stores worldwide, Beard Papa’s continues to delight fans with seasonal flavors, creative collaborations, and its signature tagline — “World’s Best Cream Puff.”]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>雪花ラミィと明利酒類が共同開発した「微発泡 雪夜月」がIWC2025でシルバーメダル受賞。受賞とシリ…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000067.000025633.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/25633/67/25633-67-1ca43e3ba655dddf4c43d3e0ad61da24-2500x1667.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:57:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>「コカ・コーラ」 当たり付ボトルが登場</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000001071.000001735.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/1735/1071/1735-1071-5f797215a31931ac01f35dbc4404d92e-1145x717.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:57:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ5期生が12月21日にホロアースでバーチャルライブ「ねぽらぼライブ re:VISION H…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000001208.000030268.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/30268/1208/30268-1208-b5755c552ba8933174a0bd8219c741eb-1920x1080.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:44:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブプロダクションがコミックマーケット107出展決定！</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000001205.000030268.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/30268/1205/30268-1205-63d17df1c6d5cf64882fc4e640de2266-1920x1080.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 15:44:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>NePoLaBo Live Photo Contest Announcement</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/nepolabophoto/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 06:36:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Greetings from the Holoearth Management Team!For the “NePoLaBo Live re:VISION Holoearth Live” virtual concert on December 21, 2025, we will hold a photo contest.We invite all to take in-app photos of hololive 5th Generation “NePoLaBo” (Momosuzu Nene / Omaru Polka / Yukihana Lamy / Shishiro Botan) from various angles, and be sure to share your very best shots!NePoLaBo Live Support Campaign: Photo Contest!For “NePoLaBo Live re:VISION Holoearth Live,” screenshots & social media posts are fully welcome.
Share your perfect captures with us!Top entries will be featured on the official website and receive NePoLaBo Live commemorative merch.
Selected posts will also be showcased on the official X account during the contest.
1. Hide “NaviRobo” and “Usernames” in the Options menu.
2. Capture in 1920×1080 (Full HD) or higher.
3. Post your screenshots on X with the hashtags (no entry limit!):
English: #NePoLaBoHoloearthLive
Japanese: #ねぽらぼホロアースライブTake as many as you like! Replay the concert anytime in the 3D archive (requires purchase of the ID Holder).Note:
・Turn “Motion Blur” off in Options (Esc key) to prevent photos from showing blur.
・In the concert venue you can use the O key shortcut to adjust the number of character models rendered and toggle other users’ effects (such as fireworks and poppers) ON/OFF. This helps reduce system load and offers more flexibility when taking photos.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>[12/29 Revision: Time Extension] Announcement: “NePoLaBo Live re:VISION Holoearth Live” on Dec. 21</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/nepolabo-live/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 13:06:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Greetings from the Holoearth Management Team!On December 21, 2025 (JST) members of hololive 5th Generation (Momosuzu Nene / Omaru Polka / Yukihana Lamy / Shishiro Botan) will hold a special virtual concert: “NePoLaBo Live re:VISION Holoearth Live.”Become a virtual avatar and share the same space and experience as the NePoLaBo members.
With a 360° front-row seat, choose any viewpoint and get up-close for an immersive concert experience where the talents are right before you within reach.After the show, relive the magic again with a 3D archive that fully preserves the entire concert space.
All you need is a PC (Windows)—To coincide with the event, items such as member-themed accessories, penlights, and text plates will also be sold. Additionally, as part of a support campaign for the event, we plan to hold a photo contest, countdown campaigns, and more!Event name: “NePoLaBo Live re:VISION Holoearth Live”
Cast: Momosuzu Nene / Omaru Polka / Yukihana Lamy / Shishiro Botan
Hashtag: #NePoLaBoHoloearthLive
Date & time: Sunday, December 21, 2025 from 19:00 (JST)About re:VISION Holoearth LiveParticipating in the Holoearth Live event requires a Windows PC with Holoearth installed and a registered account, as well as the in-app item “NePoLaBo Live re:VISION ID Holder.”Equipping your avatar with the “NePoLaBo Live re:VISION ID Holder” will grant access to the concert venue.[Exclusive Bonus Only for Holoearth]After the show, you can join a special Holoearth-exclusive segment—a unique opportunity to share the afterglow with NePoLaBo.Following the first showing, relive the concert in the 3D archive, where the entire event space is preserved. Explore the event from different perspectives, take photos, and relive your favorite scenes.The 3D archive will be held according to the designated daily schedule.Note:
Holoearth is available only on Windows.
In the concert venue you can use the O key shortcut to adjust the number of character models rendered and toggle other users’ effects (such as fireworks and poppers) ON/OFF. This helps reduce system load and offers more flexibility when taking photos.Due to popular demand, the event date has been extended to January 21, 2025 (Wed) at 23:59 (JST).
NePoLaBo Live re:VISION ID Holder
(Only one purchase per account.)・Participate in the “MC Special Segment” after the show.
・Relive the show with the 3D archive afterward.
・This is the same item included in the special sets below.
・1,500 HoloCoin (Premium)Bundled sets of items for cheering on NePoLaBo members will also be for sale.
This value set lets you purchase items such as penlights and mascot character hair accessories together.Due to popular demand, the event date has been extended to January 21, 2025 (Wed) at 23:59 (JST).
4,500 HoloCoin (Premium)
・NePoLaBo Live re:VISION ID Holder (single purchase only)
・Penlight Momosuzu Nene Type A (single purchase only)
・Nekko Hair Accessory
・NePoLaBo Live Celebration T Momosuzu Nene Ver. (Signed)
・NePoLaBo Live re:VISION ID Holder (single purchase only)
・Penlight Omaru Polka Type A (single purchase only)
・ZA-IN Hair Accessory
・NePoLaBo Live Celebration T Omaru Polka Ver. (Signed)
・NePoLaBo Live re:VISION ID Holder (single purchase only)
・Penlight Yukihana Lamy Type A (single purchase only)
・Yukimin Hair Accessory
・NePoLaBo Live Celebration T Yukihana Lamy Ver. (Signed)Cheer Set Shishiro Botan
Set details
・NePoLaBo Live re:VISION ID Holder (single purchase only)
・Penlight Shishiro Botan Type A (single purchase only)
・SSRB Hair Accessory
・NePoLaBo Live Celebration T Shishiro Botan Ver. (Signed)Holoearth Live Event Time ScheduleFirst showing: Sunday, December 21, 2025 from 19:00 (JST).Daily showtimes (JST):
(1) 08:00~ (2) 12:00~ (3) 19:00~ (4) 21:00~ (5) 23:00~This performance is pre-recorded.Screenshots from the entire performance may be posted on social media.Videos from the free portion (the first song and its MC) may be uploaded to YouTube. For other social media platforms, video posts are limited to within 30 seconds with no audio.The 3D archive may be played via the event venue screens for activities such as talent watch parties.
Due to the nature of this content, which allows users to freely control the camera, it is produced in accordance with international safety standards and guidelines regarding visual display (such as flicker frequency and changes in brightness levels).
However, certain user actions may still produce unexpectedly strong visual stimuli. In particular, individuals with a history of photosensitivity (such as photosensitive epilepsy or light-induced sensitivity), those who are sleep-deprived or unwell, and minors should avoid the actions listed below and exercise caution when viewing this content.
Rapid and intense camera movements—such as panning quickly from side to side, tilting up and down, or repeatedly zooming in and out—may cause fast motion across the screen and strong flickering.Sudden Approaches to Light Sources
Suddenly moving the camera close to bright lights used in the live performance (such as stage lighting, lasers, fireworks, or effects), or filling the screen with a bright light source, may cause abrupt changes in brightness.
If you experience strong visual stimulation, dizziness, nausea, convulsions, or any vision abnormalities while viewing this content, stop immediately, look away from the screen, and take a break. If symptoms do not improve, promptly seek medical attention.Please view this content at your own risk with thorough understanding of the above potential hazards. We kindly ask for your understanding and cooperation to ensure safe usage.
Mirrored streaming of this performance is strictly prohibited. Uploading videos of the paid portion of this performance (after the first song and its MC) to social media or YouTube is prohibited.Watch via Streaming Ticket
SPWN, ZAIKO
Dec 11 (Thu), 2025 22:00 – Jan 21 (Wed), 2025 22:00 (JST)
Until Wednesday, January 21, 2026 at 23:59 (JST)
3,500 JPY (tax inclusive)This will be a video stream provided through SPWN and ZAIKO. Holoearth’s in-app features will not be available.The archive will be available for viewing once it is prepared following the performance. During the archive viewing period the show can be viewed any number of times.As soon as the archive viewing period ends the archive footage will no longer be accessible.An additional handling fee of 220 JPY will apply when purchasing this ticket.YouTube Free-to-View SegmentThe opening portion of the live show will be streamed for free on YouTube. Videos from the free segment (the first song and its MC) may be posted on YouTube.
For other social media platforms, video posts are limited to 30 seconds or less with no audio.Limited-Time Digital MerchandiseDue to popular demand, the sales period has been extended to January 21, 2025 (Wed) at 23:59 (JST).
・NePoLaBo Live Celebration T Momosuzu Nene Ver. (No Signature)
・NePoLaBo Live Celebration T Omaru Polka Ver. (No Signature)
・NePoLaBo Live Celebration T Yukihana Lamy Ver. (No Signature)
・NePoLaBo Live Celebration T Shishiro Botan Ver. (No Signature)
・Nekko Hair Accessory
・Yukimin Hair Accessory
・Penlight Momosuzu Nene Live ver.
・Penlight Omaru Polka Live ver.
・Penlight Yukihana Lamy Live ver.
・Penlight Shishiro Botan Live ver.
Note:
Penlights are held in both hands when used.
These items cannot be used in the Simulation Room or My Space.
・Momosuzu Nene re:VISION Outfit Acrylic Stand (L)
・Omaru Polka re:VISION Outfit Acrylic Stand (L)
・Yukihana Lamy re:VISION Outfit Acrylic Stand (L)
・Shishiro Botan re:VISION Outfit Acrylic Stand (L)
・NePoLaBo Live re:VISION Key Visual Acrylic Panel
・For Momosuzu Nene
・For Yukihana LamyNew Items for Hyping Up the Show!
From Dec 11 (Thu), 2025 at 21:30
(Schedule is subject to change.)
・Penlight Momosuzu Nene Type A
・Penlight Omaru Polka Type A
・Penlight Yukihana Lamy Type A
・Penlight Shishiro Botan Type A
Note:
Penlights are held in both hands when used.
These items cannot be used in the Simulation Room or My Space.
・Momosuzu Nene Text Plate 1 × 3
(Nenechi / Kon-Nene~! / Waku Waku! / Energy Drink! / HAAAN)
・Omaru Polka Text Plate 1 × 3
(Polka / Omarun / Where’s Polka? / Otsu-Pol / POLMAO)
・Yukihana Lamy Text Plate 1 × 3
(Lamy-chan / Kon-Lamy~ / Otsu-Lamy~ / Can’t love! / Stooop)
・Shishiro Botan Text Plate 1 × 3
(Shishiron / GG / La-lion♪ / Sasu-Shishi / poi)
・NePoLaBo Momosuzu Nene Pose
・NePoLaBo Omaru Polka Pose
・NePoLaBo Yukihana Lamy Pose
・NePoLaBo Shishiro Botan Pose
From Dec 18 (Thu), 2025 after maintenance.
(Schedule is subject to change.)
・Christmas PoppersConcert event shirts will take shape in the real world.
The Live Celebration T-shirts, designed by NePoLaBo in Holoearth, are now available on Amazon!
They are unique items that connect two different worlds: the virtual and the real.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>“NePoLaBo Live re:VISION Holoearth Live” Special Website Launch!!</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/sppage/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 12:37:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[We launched a special website for the upcoming “NePoLaBo Live re:VISION Holoearth Live”!The official English hashtag is #NePoLaBoHoloearthLive.Here, you can view information and important notices about the performance, including how to participate and more.
Please check each page for details.We will also be sharing new updates in the future, so be sure to bookmark the site!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>年末年始はホロライブと！全編無料の「hololive production COUNTDOWN LI…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000001204.000030268.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/30268/1204/30268-1204-11ff57f494cc55388d93373796758d1f-1920x1080.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:48:51 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>NePoLaBo Major Announcement in Holoearth on Dec. 11</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/nepolabo_announcement/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 10:00:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Greetings from the Holoearth Management Team!On the day of the event, NePoLaBo members will appear in Holoearth as themselves and deliver a special announcement. (Please note this announcement will be featured in Japanese.)
“NePoLaBo Major Announcement in Holoearth”
(This is a revised date & time.)
Anyone can join in the festivities for free by downloading and installing Holoearth.
(Note: Holoearth is available only for Windows.)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive announces huge slate of free events for the 2025 holiday season</title><link>https://essential-japan.com/news/hololive-announces-huge-slate-of-free-events-for-the-2025-holiday-season/</link><author>Charlotte Davis</author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://cdn.essential-japan.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/HOLOLIVE-2025-26-FREE-EVENTS-00.webp" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://essential-japan.com/?s=hololive">hololive articles from Essential Japan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Cover Corporation has officially unveiled its comprehensive schedule for the 2025-2026 holiday season, headlined by a massive free countdown concert and the return of the fan-favorite New Year's Eve variety program.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>「hololive production OFFICIAL POP UP SHOP」東京駅一番街にて…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000001206.000030268.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/30268/1206/30268-1206-bc53667bf0071fe88094b9b0ad7497fb-1920x1080.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 8 Dec 2025 14:19:59 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>VTuber事務所「ホロライブプロダクション」全体イベント《hololive SUPER EXPO …</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000001203.000030268.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/30268/1203/30268-1203-1bcbdf7eefc78dc22a5a140adc465686-1920x1080.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 8 Dec 2025 14:19:59 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ × 一番くじ 1月10日よりヴィランスタイルの限定グッズ登場!</title><link>https://collabo-cafe.com/events/collabo/hololive-ichiban-kuji-villain-style2025-add-info-lineup/</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 8 Dec 2025 12:37:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://collabo-cafe.com/?s=Hololive">hololive collabs in Japan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[「ホロライブ」× バンダイスピリッツが手掛けるくじグッズ「一番くじ ホロライブ Villain Style」が、2026年1月10日より全国の量販店などにて順次発売。白上フブキ・大神ミオ・角巻わため・獅白ボタンらの描き下ろしイラストを使用した一番くじ限定グッズが多数ラインナップ!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive SUPER EXPO 2026 Supported By BANDAI &amp; hololive 7th fes. Ridin’ on Dreams Supported By LAWSON</title><link>https://hololive.hololivepro.com/en/events/hololivesuperexpo2026/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 8 Dec 2025 10:50:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive.hololivepro.com/en">hololive Events</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Overview of “hololive SUPER EXPO 2026 Supported By BANDAI”hololive SUPER EXPO 2026 Supported By BANDAI
Organizer: COVER Corporation
Platinum Sponsorship: BANDAI CO.,LTD.#hololivefesEXPO26March 6 – 8, 2026
9:00 AM – 6:00 PM (JST) (Last Entry: 5:00 PM (JST))* Times are the same for all 3 days.Makuhari Messe International Exhibition Halls 4-8 & Makuhari Event Hall
2-1, Nakase, Mihama-ku, Chiba-city, 261-8550 JapanOverview of “hololive 7th fes. Ridin’ on Dreams Supported By LAWSON”hololive 7th fes. Ridin’ on Dreams Supported By LAWSON
Organizer: COVER Corporation
Platinum Sponsorship: Lawson, Inc.#hololivefesEXPO26・ hololive STAGE1: March 6, 2026
Doors Open: 5:00 PM (JST) / Performance Starts: 6:30 PM (JST)・ hololive STAGE2: March 7, 2026
Doors Open: 11:30 AM (JST) / Performance Starts: 1:00 PM (JST)・ hololive STAGE3: March 7, 2026
Doors Open: 5:00 PM (JST) / Performance Starts: 6:30 PM (JST)・ hololive STAGE4: March 8, 2026
Doors Open 11:30 AM (JST) / Performance Starts: 1:00 PM (JST)Makuhari Messe International Exhibition Halls 1-3
2-1, Nakase, Mihama-ku, Chiba-city, 261-8550 JapanVENUE / LIVESTREAM TICKETS]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>