<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>aside&apos;s newsfeed</title><link>https://asideaside.github.io/feed/</link><description>Liveboat RSS Feed</description><item><title>Doki Dreamers × HOLOSTARS English -TEMPUS- “Sweet Love” Collection Available!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250704-01-176/</link><author>os_pr</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 4 Jul 2025 01:00:41 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[July 8, 2025, Tokyo, Japan – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) has announced that the Doki Dreamers × HOLOSTARS English -TEMPUS- “Sweet Love” product collection is available for purchase.The Doki Dreamers × HOLOSTARS English -TEMPUS- “Sweet Love” collection is the first product collaboration project between HOLOSTARS English -TEMPUS- and artist-driven merchandise brand Doki Dreamers. The product collection features a lineup of baking-themed accessories, including a cookie-style button, a chocolate-style keychain, an enamel pin, a collection of “cheki”-style photo cards, and a beautiful poster featuring each of the HOLOSTARS English -TEMPUS- talents.
The Doki Dreamers × HOLOSTARS English -TEMPUS- “Sweet Love” collection merchandise is available on the Doki Dreamers online shop from June 20, 2025 from 10:00 AM (PDT), and will be available at ANIME Impulse Orange County in Anaheim, CA on August 30th and 31st, 2025.
For more information, please visit the official Doki Dreamers social media accounts and official website.Doki Dreamers × HOLOSTARS English -TEMPUS- “Sweet Love” collection
・ Cookie button pins
・ Photo cards
・ Key Visual posterOnline Shipping
Shipping from: Washington State, USAShipping is subject to availability. Orders containing backlogged products may be delayed. Orders may be cancelled any time prior to shipping.Doki Dreamers strives to connect the dreams of creators with the hearts of fans, celebrating their communities and making memories together. Their shop specializes in creating high quality products for VTubers and their communities. Each product is made with the belief that merchandise should be as colorful and unique as the talents themselves, and be a fun way to celebrate and share love for a community.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>&apos;Rift of the Necrodancer&apos; Introduced Me to HoloLive Music… And I Think I Love It? Help? - VICE</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitgFBVV95cUxNci1YdGxnVl9OcWVDbTFMWTZPUFktbkpmTXJFMkpuOFNiMXVSeU5Ic0h5b2U4eW8tZUtpeGhsT1J6WGpWNm9zdDA5TmxTQjBhTkdGc0wyQm5IRUxHeE5wdjVsMmlJTW51dWptMlU0dUpTMWRSbE1mdm9OSUFwUU5mZkVMSGRuNktiRFY5NERTY2wyc3c2QUdSYkxXd1QyQmJ3d04tQjRVeDB6S1dQaVQybmRaTUJfUQ?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 3 Jul 2025 21:19:44 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【25年11月】グッズ予定まとめ</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/goods-nov25/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Thu, 3 Jul 2025 14:20:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>VTubers are descending on L.A. with multiple concerts - Los Angeles Times</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxOamswT1BpX0NIUHRnWnpwby1NOWt0c0IwLVpJU3BhMWMwWF9BZUtON0lTem9qem5Yd05zVk1HRDBIWkF1UGtuckw2QVU1emtfRVlYMG1TaC15OTMwVjFHN1ctMlFQTDJuREtndkhBdXZrVDBJNUh3Smg4OHd5a0s2bUZuRnhKNDZlYmo5bU9YVTRkUQ?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 3 Jul 2025 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ENG | オタ活 vlog 》星街すいせい展覧会☄️SUISEI ARCHIVES行った日🤍アニメイトもぶらり🎧</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rLVqNAgFM8s</link><author>Riko-m</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/rLVqNAgFM8s?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 3 Jul 2025 09:55:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCm4-UmTD1TbYd7V0PBpKVbA">Riko-m</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ご視聴いただきありがとうございます🤍
久々のオタ活満喫できて楽しかったぞ~~~！！！


✧ 翻訳・文章添削
Mちゃん

✧ BGM
   / @Amagashi_music
   / @nogika_chaba  
   / 効果音ラボ様

#星街すいせい #HoshimachiSuisei #SUISEIARCHIVES 
 #オタ活 #Hololive]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>GHOST X GHOST Teams Up with Mori Calliope Again for a PORTRAIT OF DEATH drop! | COVER Corp. - カバー株式会社</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXkFVX3lxTE5uek9SS2FmTF9iS0NtTWlCcGl1S1pqc2NnOXVGVFp2bE1Bd2ZOVmxIVHlHVlFndVFhQWkwX0l6QWJXTWRhZDBqdVRYVGhLV09vYlVNcEF4MGR1M0JWd1E?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 3 Jul 2025 08:42:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Going to LA - Airport Stream</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y_29HKdC9p4</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/y_29HKdC9p4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 3 Jul 2025 04:32:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[⭐ Please follow and support! 
⭐ フォローとサポートはこちらへ！
⭐ 팔로우와 후원은 여기로!
Twitter - https://twitter.com/hwikkyofficial
Patreon - https://www.patreon.com/hwikky
ko-fi - https://www.ko-fi.com/hwikky
StreamLabs - https://streamlabs.com/hwikky/tip

#hololiveEN #hololivedodgers 
#AX2025 #FantasticReality
#hololive #ホロライブ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>GHOST X GHOST Teams Up with Mori Calliope Again for a PORTRAIT OF DEATH drop! | hololive production - ホロライブプロダクション</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiugFBVV95cUxNNDRoVWlVT2FaaG5DVWx2YnJ4ZWdZVkdia3JjQS1UOW9BeFhVZE9pTEdENjRtVVF2ckp1Y0pESm42WGhVY0M2Wmxhd3BKSGhKVjBpWGhEd1Jidi1CVDU4NFh2SndqVkZSUW15aFA0SnRpSEVaNUdnUDg5Q3J0aWlhdGxZSEZCTmYyQUZRVUJpQ0pnQ2huelVad0pCQUVMZDhNYXl6MzlOQTR4c1g4TGFndWlYSzNxN2xweXc?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 3 Jul 2025 03:22:19 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>AVIOT to Open Pre-Orders for hololive English -Advent- Collaboration True Wireless Earbuds on July 2 - The Outerhaven</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiyAFBVV95cUxNSnY4dDdIeUE5N29SOURFdUJMTTkyaFYzVXA3WlZZQzYzb2luSWtla0V2UVk3cG81eWVqWTFLX21PQXpGSm93Wld6bkpkRHptY3dxdkdWUTN2SllXNndPU2R5NTNJaHotZ0ZyTDduUUY0MjlTTWhUblJZUFMtV0UzMU1HbzNmLTNlR1VUYnFSZ0JGZXlYMHAtQkQ5N2NtYm9TYkNxbmRBUkNWbDhBcFBacjZTQ0l2Vk1icHhvRmVPZnRTTWYwa0lqbA?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 3 Jul 2025 03:02:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Delivering New Experiences to Fans While Empowering Talent – Inside COVER’s Licensing Business</title><link>https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en/list/2390</link><author>cover_yamaguchi</author><category>COVER</category><pubDate>Thu, 3 Jul 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en">COVEREdge Magazine</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[I began my career at a major entertainment company right after graduating, involved in a range of areas like music and talent management. After that, I changed to an entertainment company called Tokyo Otaku Mode where I first started working with 2D content and gained experience as a buyer and a licensee as well as managing partners, which is actually the opposite of the role I have now.After I left Tokyo Otaku Mode, I was job hunting when a friend introduced me to COVER. At that time, I had already accepted an offer from another company, but my friend strongly encouraged me to meet with Mr. Tanigo, saying what an interesting person he is and how much I should really talk to him. So I decided to go ahead and meet with him.Back then, I honestly had no intention of joining, and I was pretty skeptical about VTuber culture in general and looking back now, I realize I probably came across as quite dismissive during my conversation with him. Mr. Tanigo shared his strong passion for hololive production and explained his long-term vision in detail when we sat down and talked. He spoke about how genuinely believes more than anyone else in the potential of hololive production and its talents, and he described exactly what he felt was needed to help that potential grow. Hearing his views made me start to feel that maybe I could contribute to this vision as well, and that I wanted to take on the challenge together, which is what ultimately inspired me to join the company. At the time, Mr. Tanigo was actually looking for someone with experience in product planning and development, but during our conversation, he asked me, “How would you feel about looking after licensing? You’re great at talking with people, and I have a feeling this could really suit you,” which led to me being given the opportunity to lead the launch of the licensing business.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>GHOST X GHOST Teams Up with Mori Calliope Again for a PORTRAIT OF DEATH drop! - hololive.hololivepro.com</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaEFVX3lxTE1WQUE1eTVmZEI0bEt0cVBwT1d4aElzaTFJZWVIQkJPdWxMbl90dnBUX29NS0Q4RmFYT0xkb29HVnp4VGdnR1h3cXhGNllORDJNbzNJeXRKcDJBXzZaN0NycWZmRkRtdDJ5?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 3 Jul 2025 02:41:17 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive English Teams Up with Kura Sushi USA for an Exclusive Summer Collaboration! | COVER Corp. - カバー株式会社</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXkFVX3lxTFB5VV96MVo5SUdaX2VVOEN1dE95aUx4SWJJUGFXMUhvZEhnXy02OEs0R1BZUnljNUxKb0Z1V3VDT0lnVUF3aE4zTWxUd0ZoTF9PT3ZEdERld1FNMjFTb0E?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 3 Jul 2025 01:25:34 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>GHOST X GHOST Teams Up with Mori Calliope Again for a PORTRAIT OF DEATH drop!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250703-01-175/</link><author>os_pr</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 3 Jul 2025 01:00:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[July 3, 2025, Tokyo, Japan – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) has announced another collaboration between GHOST X GHOST and Mori Calliope of hololive English of hololive production. Following the success of the previous Metalcropolis collaboration, they will launch a new limited-edition series titled .Taking some inspiration from Alphonse Mucha and the desire to showcase talents in a new way the GHOST X GHOST team have created an unexpected and unique design in the PORTRAIT series. Illustrator Florian Bertmer brings Mori Calliope to life in a design that fuses elegance with ominous grace befit for the reaper’s apprentice.“We’re stoked to work with Calli again, and we hope you’re ready to face her PORTRAIT OF DEATH.” the GHOST X GHOST team shared.The Mori Calliope – Portrait of Death series includesLong-Sleeve T-Shirt – $45 
Printed on Comfort Colors “pepper” long-sleeved t-shirt and features printed sleeves.White Variant T-Shirt – $30 
Available for PREORDER for 24-hours only! Features metallic silver ink.Standard & Long-Sleeve T-Shirts: 
Pre-orders open Tuesday, July 2nd at 5 PM PDT and close Friday, July 25th at 12 PM PDT.
Extremely limited—preorders are available only for 24 hours! 
From July 2nd at 5 PM PDT to July 3rd at 5 PM PDT.Whether you’re a fan of Mori Calliope or love art and fashion, don’t miss the  series—check it out now!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive English Teams Up with Kura Sushi USA for an Exclusive Summer Collaboration! - ホロライブプロダクション</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiwwFBVV95cUxNUF9McFhQNFMtSzIxdWE2c3ZidWJoT3NHa0hxcHJ0NmtVdy1UMS13TmFBelQ2bmp1bU0xUHdmYS1ZeC1mUWExR0JJZkdVRE4wUXZPM3JWVnU3QndqcTZuU3cxM1ZLRnVDS1BQYXRsYzRTbWhGYWpCOHlQQm11MVV2WFJERHBMMi1wd1hVaDk1UDdRdTBuNmNZVlpNcW1wcmFtbmxoYU5wVDFMZG1IRjlmT2FFazMwRmlGUl9Od1ZuMmptV1E?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 2 Jul 2025 02:35:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>HOLOSTARS English to Host a Welcome Giveaway Campaign in Celebration of New Social Media Accounts!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250702-01-174/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 2 Jul 2025 01:00:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) has announced a HOLOSTARS English Welcome Giveaway campaign in celebration of two new official social media accounts.The followers’ welcoming giveaway, taking place on X, Instagram, and TikTok, will last from July 1st until July 23rd JST, with a total of 30 winners across the three campaigns.Nine of these lucky winners will be eligible to receive three 3D Acrylic Stands of their choice from HOLOSTARS English -TEMPUS- or HOLOSTARS English -ARMIS-, while 21 winners will be eligible to receive one holoEmblem Pin Badge of their choice, also from HOLOSTARS English -TEMPUS- or HOLOSTARS English -ARMIS-.HOLOSTARS English Welcome Giveaway
July 1st 10:00AM – July 23rd at 1:00PM JST
30 winners across 3 social media platforms will be contacted on July 25th at 12:00PM JST.*Followers must participate with a public account that can accept private messages for a chance to win.
– The user must be following the official HOLOSTARS English X account.
– The user must give the giveaway post a Like.
– The user must give the giveaway post a Repost.
3D Acrylic Stands of the Winner’s Choice (Qty:3) : 3 winners
holoEmblem Pin Badge of the Winner’s Choice (Qty:1) : 7 winners
– The user must be following the official HOLOSTARS English Instagram account.
– The user must give the giveaway post a Like.
– The user must comment on the giveaway post with three oshimarks of their favorite talents.
3D Acrylic Stands of the Winner’s Choice (Qty:3) : 3 winners
holoEmblem Pin Badge of the Winner’s Choice (Qty:1) : 7 winners
– The user must be following the official HOLOSTARS English X account.
– The user must give the giveaway post a Like.
– The user must comment on the giveaway post with three oshimarks of their favorite talents.
3D Acrylic Stands of the Winner’s Choice (Qty:3) : 3 winners
holoEmblem Pin Badge of the Winner’s Choice (Qty:1) : 7 winners]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive English Teams Up with Kura Sushi USA for an Exclusive Summer Collaboration! | NEWS | hololive official website - hololive.hololivepro.com</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaEFVX3lxTE1KQ0lKYkdVZ3JRaXJobTBsdmhVOC1VYzlGekNCb0x2UmVocjhNTUhxcDdCbWl2a0wzanRtWlZrU2h3azVxc0hxRE1rdEQyX0JlQTFEUHVETmhTYUF6ZDdVcmFTSUZtMUlJ?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 2 Jul 2025 00:46:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive English Teams Up with Kura Sushi USA for an Exclusive Summer Collaboration!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250702-01-173/</link><author>os_pr</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 1 Jul 2025 23:55:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[July 2, 2025, Tokyo, Japan – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) has announced that hololive English of hololive production is collaborating with Kura Sushi USA. The exclusive campaign is running from July 1st until July 31st, 2025.hololive English × Kura Sushi: Exclusive Collab Experience Across the U.S.!A limited-time campaign is rolling out at Kura Sushi locations across the U.S. from July 1st to 31st, featuring three hololive English talents — , , and ! Don’t miss out on this exciting experience, with specially crafted menu items and immersive in-store elements designed for fans and food enthusiasts alike.Kura Sushi USA x hololive English Exclusive Sushi DishesEnjoy three original dishes inspired by Ninomae Ina’nis, Ouro Kronii, and Gigi Murin! is honored with the Spicy Crunchy Squid, featuring squid tempura topped with spicy mayo, eel sauce, and bonito flakes over Kura’s specialty sushi rice. influence comes to life in the Tuna with Avocado Cream Cheese, which pairs soy-marinated tuna with avocado and cream cheese over Kura’s specialty sushi rice. is represented by the vibrant Salmon & Tamago Spicy Roll, made with spicy salmon and tamago atop a shrimp mayo roll finished with panko crunchy flakes.Exclusive hololive English × Kura Sushi USA Goods to Complement the Culinary Experience!Kura Sushi USA x hololive English bottle set
Available starting July 1st, 2025 for , while supplies last.*1 design in total; limited to three per party. Available for purchase in-restaurant only.Kura Sushi USA x hololive English cooling towel and carrying case set
Available from July 21st with a minimum spend of  in-store at participating locations, while supplies last.*1 design in total; limited to three per party.Get Immersed in the Summer Festivities at hololive English Themed Stores!Participating Kura Sushi USA locations will feature hololive English themed in-store decorations throughout the duration of the promotion, transforming the dining experience into a fully immersive, fan-centric celebration.“We’re incredibly excited to partner with hololive English for our first U.S.-based VTuber collaboration,” said , President and CEO of Kura Sushi USA, Inc. “This campaign offers a one-of-a-kind experience that blends fan culture with Kura’s passion for innovation and fun.”About Kura Sushi USA, Inc.Kura Sushi USA, Inc. is a technology-enabled Japanese restaurant concept with over 76 locations across the United States. Known for its revolving sushi bar experience and commitment to quality ingredients, Kura Sushi USA is a subsidiary of Kura Sushi, Inc., which has operated in Japan for over 45 years since 1977.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Skebリクエストありがとうございました⚜️🐾 #illustration #イラスト #skeb #aftereffects #animation #shorts #vtuber</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/12y5V40dc40</link><author>Riko-m</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/12y5V40dc40?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 1 Jul 2025 20:00:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCm4-UmTD1TbYd7V0PBpKVbA">Riko-m</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】AZKi New EP『Re:Start』『Re:Birth』：25年11月5日発売【店舗特典まとめ】</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/azki-restart-rebirth/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Tue, 1 Jul 2025 19:29:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[□封入特典・『Re:Start』アクリルスタンド・『Re:Start』ロゴラバーストラップ・hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME PRカード hBP01-044 「AZKi」]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>New Hololive Event Gives Ouro Kronii &amp; Friends Stunning Makeovers for Limited Edition Release - Comic Book Resources</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMidEFVX3lxTFA3NEw4bG5DOEpQRXB4eFpGbUFJVklzM1JhdFQzTUZ0TEE0NThaTzB2alZrVmVzZnNSQURXemNoWWlybkYwXzhrb2Y2aVBTNU13RDAwdjhVMVlXQmlJeHlPdi0wT2lqT0FaQWxDQlRMdFgxVkNS?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 1 Jul 2025 00:05:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How (NOT) to Build a PC 【 HYTE Suisei PC Case Unboxing &amp; Review 】</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6RhVQQm7YZA</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/6RhVQQm7YZA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 23:54:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[☄️ Hoshimachi Suisei PC Case + Keycap & Desk Pad Bundle Pre-order NOW
👉 Get yours here (please): https://hyte.co/hwikky-hololive

⭐ Please follow and support!
Twitter - https://twitter.com/hwikkyofficial
Patreon - https://www.patreon.com/hwikky
ko-fi - https://www.ko-fi.com/hwikky

#PR #HYTE
#hoshimachisuisei #星街すいせい
#hololive #ホロライブ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Talking FANTASTIC REALITY Concert w/ MARIYA 💒 from V4Mirai ( + hwikky LA Trip)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6mC0gxQNr-U</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/6mC0gxQNr-U?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 21:11:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[✨ Fantastic Reality presented by IRIAM
🗓️  July 3rd 2025
📍 Vermont Hollywood, Los Angeles
🎫 Get your Tickets HERE: https://www.eventbrite.com/e/fantastic-reality-presented-by-iriam-tickets-1378432060399

- Featuring Ironmouse, KAF, Mint Fantôme, Kou Mariya and many more + LIVE (and virtual) BAND Performance
- Produced by Kou Maryia, StarlightDaryl Emerging Technology Company, Bulldog DM, and Rust

(btw, I am not sponsored or anything, I just think what they are doing is cool lol)

⭐ Please follow and support! 
⭐ フォローとサポートはこちらへ！
⭐ 팔로우와 후원은 여기로!
Twitter - https://twitter.com/hwikkyofficial
Patreon - https://www.patreon.com/hwikky
ko-fi - https://www.ko-fi.com/hwikky
StreamLabs - https://streamlabs.com/hwikky/tip]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hololive Vtubers and Kura Revolving Sushi Bar Event Detailed - Siliconera</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxNQTJKcm4tek5XaDhXZnNoZjUwdjZOeDJscHJDU0hlbXR2QVN1bDRWSjVUN0drMl90UzcyZjcwWmszeEw5bExjS2xwblFJU2ZWY1Y3bFhHVU5lMm9jM3JxT01sazdpbUJxNklZRGwxLWVSeXR3RTNEYnBMc2liazk1M1RPa1FhQjJ2clN3Z3d0c0pIUQ?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Former Hololive star Gawr Gura returns as independent VTuber Sameko Saba - spilled.gg</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqgFBVV95cUxPcTg0QVVybFBpaElBaF9WQnQ2VjZpQ0lVYi1jRlpSSzBQVFF4M0hHbWhHSmpHNi1YczZLMXZyaXZRYlNTbW5ZTmJaZTdSRG9Nc3pyNkU0WG0yUHBYam5XN2QxbU9xemZWTVpncTZ1M3d1bndUX3A1Qlp2R1FzclpRVndyQmVOTC1tX210bmZwaktzSTdST2xUb0MySHBaZUFIRjEweElVMVdadw?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 18:17:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Bacardi&apos;s Music Video for “Sunburst” Featuring hololive&apos;s Houshou Marine Released - anitrendz.net</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitwFBVV95cUxPT2lEN1ZGdXBNR01qVTJOY3BJbHlqSEVQZktuS2J2eXdYMHdPTXFKVGZ0eU02bGtQQnp6ZWphTHJSR0U1UVZrdXVDZDNnR1Z4NUlqbVBBSi1YcjRnRDN3aEJtdDFtYTFVdXdidnJTZ1k1RXZ4NmdaN2tRY3JIZnNOaFY1QURQSmlNd29mX01mdkxtdkR4R1AtRkJaSVJxbkdRcTF1SVMzOGJnWjBEUEdjS19ZbkRsVVk?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 13:07:57 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive Night Returns to Dodgers Stadium on July 5 - anitrendz.net</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxNdzlzRDJOSVhteXY2MThaZndFWVkyYVUxTjA1NHFOdXhjd3VQdGF4bGx1d3RmeWhPbnpETG1INlRIMkNSdnVKZ3F0M2UyRlFrTVIzYlVFUEYxMXdQT2JhUG9sWjFNV3VVT3oxWkc3dHNzQmhKc2I5YVN4ejhyUGhZZS1SMTFhZTN3OXNFVFJibm43YTRY?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 13:02:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hololive English -Advent- Pop-Up Shop Coming to Anime Expo 2025 - Anime Corner</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxNZm1HazI2S0VZMWxlbS1UNkQ1c3VJalRIbFltelhETlo5RVJPeEduXzFzclVobmFCN2lmRnZLeHktcTdiSXdLTEFGNTRHQlJ1MExLSi1tY190NlZoWXQ1SjlqeHJNREFZaGhVVExtVnM1VGx3ZmhFckVfZmtOcVJQenBNZGJyNFV2bUNReVdn?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 13:17:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>They Went All Out for Wuthering Waves&apos; 1st Anniversary in Japan</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KDtmZualF9k</link><author>Linsaloty</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/KDtmZualF9k?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 03:00:33 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9lFqIDTZbjTwoiPGoBG_zw">Linsaloty</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Find me on X: https://twitter.com/linsaloty

▼Related Videos▼
I Went to the Wuthering Waves Collab Cafe in Japan [ENG/中文/日本語]: https://youtu.be/ROCVMU1qlc4

▼Related Links▼
Official site: https://wutheringwaves.kurogames.com/jp/main/news/detail/2680

Timestamps
0:00 - Intro
1:09 - Promotions around the station 
2:23 - Life size Inferno Rider statue
3:13 - Entering the venue
5:00 - Message board
5:17 - Collab perfume
5:52 - Fanart area
6:38 - Goods area
7:47 - Food and drink
8:13 - Panels
8:48 - Male Rover piano performance
12:25 - Wall of Cartethyia
12:56 - Mini games
15:57 - Cosplays (and getting headpatted and bonked)
18:05 - Cosplay parade show
22:46 - Goods sample
23:34 - Goods from the event
29:25 - Goods from Amiami
32:18 - Final thoughts

Cosplayers information: (Ctrl+F character name for quick search!)

桃戸もも(Male Rover)
X: https://x.com/tmmt_san
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/tmmt_cosplay/
Other socials page: https://lit.link/en/momotocosplay

百莉ゆり(Shorekeeper)
X: https://x.com/_lilyur1
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/0o.lilyur1/

あまに(Roccia)
X: https://x.com/kujoamani
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/amani_cos/
Other socials page: https://linktr.ee/kujoamani

びぃと。(Brant)
X: https://x.com/hata_beats999
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/hatano_beat999/?igsh=ZWptYnQxc2NmbHBx&utm_source=qr%2F#
Other socials page: https://lit.link/en/999beat999

紅羽りお(Cartethyia)
X: https://x.com/riotarou12
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/riotarou12/
Other socials page: https://lit.link/en/riotarou12

箱ネコ(Fleurdelys)
X: https://x.com/hakonyanya
Booth: https://hakonyanya.booth.pm/

みぃこ(Ciaccona)
X: https://x.com/mmm_mii_
Youtube: https://www.youtube.com/c/MiicoTV

あーちょ(Zani)
X: https://x.com/A_d185a
TikTok: https://tiktok.com/@pink185a
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/arkham_acho/

すずら(Phoebe)
X: https://x.com/suzuran_ro
Youtube: https://www.youtube.com/@suzuran_tube

切切キリコ(Cantarella)
X: https://x.com/celia_aya
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/kiriko_celia/
Other socials page: https://linktr.ee/kiriko_celia

し季(Carlotta)
X: https://x.com/Shikiii_vvv

あるく(Margherita)
X: https://x.com/i__fu93/media
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/i__fu93/
Other socials page: https://lit.link/en/aruku0903

雪村ユノ(Female Rover)
X: https://x.com/yukimuraYY2
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/yukimurayy/
TikTok: https://www.tiktok.com/@yukimurayy
Other socials page: https://lit.link/en/yukimuraYY

マオ/Mao(Changli)
X: https://x.com/maoam_cs/media
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/maoam_cs/

海ノ塩 あいす(Yinlin)
X: https://x.com/c_saltiiice
Youtube: https://www.youtube.com/@sea_saltice2864
Other socials page: https://lit.link/en/seasaltice

デデ(Xiangli Yao)
X: https://x.com/DE_895
Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/de_895_/#

BGM: 
"Cradle" by https://www.youtube.com/@KyattoWorks
"Party Time" by https://www.youtube.com/@KyattoWorks
"Moonside Howling" by https://www.youtube.com/@KyattoWorks
"Goodnight" by https://www.youtube.com/@KyattoWorks
"Shower" by https://www.youtube.com/@KyattoWorks
"Get Ready" by https://www.youtube.com/@KyattoWorks

#WutheringWaves #鳴潮]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Saba Debut Watchalong 🐟</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iIz6xbrCAZ4</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/iIz6xbrCAZ4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 11:42:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[🐟 Saba Debut Stream Link: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pYVEIX7nSEs

⭐ Please follow and support! 
⭐ フォローとサポートはこちらへ！
⭐ 팔로우와 후원은 여기로!
Twitter - https://twitter.com/hwikkyofficial
Patreon - https://www.patreon.com/hwikky
ko-fi - https://www.ko-fi.com/hwikky
StreamLabs - https://streamlabs.com/hwikky/tip]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>“hololive English -Advent-” POP UP SHOP Arrives at Anime Expo 2025 - The Outerhaven</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimAFBVV95cUxPcXViOUV5OXZQTnhzMW1wVUlidkJMSlZHS2t2cDJxNlgwM05mdktqSjQyLUYwb3oxNGo4NHpQVGVzSVQ3ZDdRR1c1UklhMTUyYzlncUNOZlJZeE1kRDFXLWQwWmQzWlg5eHViU3hNWERMQ0pnbk9aOEE1MEZ3QzZuaEZhLXhSa0tOY3pLVHBqeUQwUDdDMXNsQQ?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 11:00:52 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【再販・予約受付中】hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME オフィシャルサイコロ Light Blue &amp; Black</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/holoca-official-dice-marker/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 08:25:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[︎発売日：・24年11月1日（初販）サイズ：約1.8×1.8×1.8 cm/個水色1個、黒色1個【関連】hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME オフィシャルマーカーセット Lite：25年9月19日発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/official-marker-lite/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 08:22:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[︎発売日：25年9月19日カバー株式会社が企画・開発をするTCG「hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME」公式サプライシリーズからゲーム中に使用するダメージマーカーとSP推しスキルマーカーをセットにした商品が登場！昨年発売した「オフィシャルマーカーセット」よりお求めやすい価格になっております。【セット内容】ダメージマーカー：100=6個、50=8個、10=18個　SP推しスキルマーカー＝1個　【製品素材】アクリル　]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【7月4日予約開始】『hololive Meet』2025 アンバサダー オリジナルグッズ</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/hololive-meet2025/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 03:40:41 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[桃鈴ねね / 音乃瀬奏 / ベスティア・ゼータ / 古石ビジュー / 荒咬オウガ（ホロスターズ） / オクタビオ（ホロスタEN）︎海外向け販売：Anime Expo2025（ロサンゼルス）にて販売予定（25年7月3日〜6日）︎日本向け販売：25年8月中発売hololive Meet  アンバサダーグッズはこちら]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】魔法少女ホロウィッチ！コミックス第1巻：25年8月19日発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/holowhich-01/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 03:09:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[発売日：8月19日収録内容：第一章「はじまりの魔法編」を収録]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】POP UP PARADE 夏色まつり：25年12月発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/pup-matsuri/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 03:02:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[※期間中は必ずご予約できます。※上記期間をもって販売予定数が決定し、以降は予定数に達し次第受付終了※GOODSMILE以外の通販サイトでは数に限りあり]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Cover x Epic Games: Exploring New VTuber Horizons with Unreal Engine</title><link>https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en/list/2320</link><author>cover_hirata</author><category>COVER</category><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en">COVEREdge Magazine</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Managing Director: Takayuki KawasakiCustomer Success Director: Noriaki ShinoyamaIkko Fukuda, Director and CTO Tsuyoshi Okugawa (Manager/Graphics Engineer), Art Engineering Team, Technology Development Division, Creative Production Department Akitsugu Hirano (Lead Engineer), Development Team #3, Technology Development Division, Creative Production DepartmentHyogo Ito (3D Designer), Unreal Engine Development Team, Technology Development Division, Creative Production Department  Noriyuki Hiromoto (Graphics Engineer), SPARK inc.Pursuing Realism and Living Up to Talent Expectations:How VTuber Live Technology is Evolving with Unreal Engine I recently watched the one-and-a-half year anniversary live performance from ReGLOSS using Unreal Engine and the quality was incredibly high, genuinely moving me. Could you walk us through what led to the decision to incorporate Unreal Engine into this livestream, and how the technology behind your livestream has evolved over time?Thank you very much. Music livestreams for hololive production originally began with the use of motion capture VR equipment. At the time, there were many limitations in terms of hardware and available space, and from a technical standpoint, it was quite difficult to handle longer streams. When it comes to graphics, improvements haven’t been just one giant leap forward, but rather from steady, incremental progress over time. What’s particularly worth noting is that this evolution hasn’t been driven by technology alone – it’s also thanks to the ever-improving skills of our on-site team members who handle lighting and camera work, as well as the increasing expertise of our production staff.As we continued to evolve our production, we still felt there were limitations in our ability to recreate a true sense of presence and immersion to capture the sheer amount of information and realism that a live concert delivers and translate that in a virtual space. While grappling with those challenges, I happened to see the  demo for Unreal Engine 5 released by Unreal Engine, and I was blown away by the sheer volume of detail, making me excited if we were able to use it for our livestreaming. These days, even individual creators are able to produce high quality content using Unreal Engine, so given this shift, we felt it was essential for us as a company to move quickly and begin offering livestreams powered by Unreal Engine as well. That’s why we made the decision to speed up our timeline and adopt the technology so soon. How has the response to the livestream powered by Unreal Engine been from fans and talents?One of the major reasons we adopted Unreal Engine was to better support our talents – to help bring to life performances and expressions they envision. As we gave them progress reports throughout the production process, we could sense their growing excitement – a feeling of “we may finally be able to do the things we weren’t able to before.” In fact, we’ve already received numerous requests from other talents saying they’d love to do a livestream using Unreal Engine as well. Being able to provide an environment where we can meet those expectations is incredibly meaningful.  The high quality in graphics really surprised and excited fans and talents, even prompting lively discussions on social media, with people speculating about what might be possible with the Unreal Engine. What really stood out among fan reactions was how attentive they were to technical details and how often they would comment on them. We even got comments from those with seemingly quite specialized knowledge noting the incredible use of skeletal mesh for the water effects for instance. It was really encouraging for us to see that level of engagement. Internally, we also treated this as a kind of technical showcase and gave non-engineering staff the opportunity to experience the live environment built with Unreal Engine. It was great to see so many people take interest and participate – even those without a technical background.I know we have started using Unreal Engine for music livestreams, but it was originally developed as a game engine. In Japan, what kinds of fields is Unreal Engine currently being used in?In Japan, it has been strongly adopted by television broadcasters in particular. Unreal Engine is highly valued in such environments for its efficiency and speed, qualities that are especially important in the fast-paced world of regular programming and drama production.  For example, it’s been used in a variety of settings, including shoots for NHK’s historical dramas that use LEDs and commercial network productions, as well as in virtual studios for visual effects work. Recently, stylized expressions () – including toon shading () – have become increasingly common in the anime production field as well. Unreal Engine is now being used in a wide range of visual and broadcast productions, and the number of projects adopting it continues to grow significantly.Note 1: “Stylized” refers to expressing objects or characters in a unique design or applying a consistent visual styleNote 2: “Toon shading” is a technique used to make 3DCG look like hand-drawn illustrations or cel-style animation.In television and other video production on-site, deadlines tend to be very tight, and in the past, there were only a limited number of iterations () possible. But with real-time rendering, teams can now immediately check the results of their work, making it possible to produce higher-quality content more efficiently. The video industry has long made use of dedicated software and middleware, but the biggest advantage of Unreal Engine is that it provides an environment where high-quality visuals can be created in real time. In addition to Unreal Engine itself, we also provide an ecosystem that includes assets like Megascans (), allowing even small teams to produce high-quality content.Note 3: Iteration refers to a development cycle often used in software development and project management, where design development and testing are repeated in short intervalsNote 4: Megascans is a high-quality 3D asset scans library offered by Quixel. It features physically-based rendering with faithfully captured high-resolution details. These assets can be directly exported into Unreal Engine.In fields like video and anime production, Unreal Engine can dramatically streamline the traditional workflow. In fact, directors or supervisors can even build scenes directly in the editor without needing a storyboard. The ability for users to work in a pipeline that closely resembles real-world production has significantly improved trial-and-error speeds – something that many professionals have found especially valuable.Blending Photorealism and Anime: Engineers’ Innovative Approach to Unreal EngineThis was your first time implementing Unreal Engine, but could you tell us about the technical challenges you faced and any creative solutions you came up with when using it for your livestream?For this project, I oversaw development direction, and the biggest benefit we saw from adopting Unreal Engine were in the lighting quality and the overall production speed. The lighting design was completed in just a few weeks, which is an incredibly fast turnaround, and the final visual output far exceeded our expectations in terms of expression. Although, bringing together the photorealistic visuals that Unreal Engine excels at with the anime likeness of the hololive talents into the same space did require a great deal of technical ingenuity.  I was in charge of graphics, and the most challenging part for me was finding the right balance between a sense of realism and an anime-style aesthetic that would look visually appealing in a video. We put a lot of effort into blending the talents naturally into the environment, especially in how they interacted with the background, by implementing a “holo-color grading system” and creating a custom post-effect volume, separate from Unreal Engine’s standard post-effects. This setup allowed us to apply grading () separately to the talents and the background, and then apply master grading on top of both. It also allowed us to separately adjust the color grading of the talents and the background based on parameters like the time of day and weather changes as well as made it possible to naturally blend the stylized talents into a photorealistic background. Note 5: “Grading” refers to the process of adjusting colors, tones and contrast in a video to create a particular atmosphere or visual world.We also had to get creative with Lumen, Unreal Engine’s global illumination system. Using the default Lumen settings made the talents appear overly three-dimensional – almost like figurines – so we adjusted the lighting to tone down that sense of depth while still retaining the ambient lighting of the environment. I contributed to the project mainly by modifying the engine including developing existing character shaders and implementing post-effects. One of the key challenges was figuring out how to faithfully translate our existing character expressions into Unreal Engine. That simply wouldn’t have been possible without making modifications to the engine. Because Unreal Engine’s G-buffer couldn’t fully accommodate the range of expressions we needed, we implemented a few workarounds including quantizing and compressing the data, and extending the system to allow constant buffers to be added per material.In environments with such a large number of lights active at once, the standard lighting caused the cel-shaded appearance talents to break up a bit. To address this, we implemented a custom lighting system specially for those talents and thanks to this, we were able to maintain consistent anime-style shading even in scenes with more than 50 real-time light sources.We also addressed translucency by rendering the relevant materials in a separate buffer using multipass rendering, which allowed us to have deferred lighting for translucent materials. : G-buffers store geometric information about objects in a scene, such as normal vectors, albedo (surface color) and depth information. By using a G-buffer, rendering performance can be improved, and more complex lighting calculations can be performed efficiently. ▼Expressions that use over 50 light sources in real timeI am in charge of talent-related development, focusing on ways to introduce outlines into talent expressions.There are two ways of doing this, either with push or post outlines, and we have to make detailed adjustments so that we can switch between the two as necessary depending on how close the camera is. During the live performance, as a production changes from evening to night as time elapses, we adjusted the color grading in real time using Sequencer () for each time period, so that the talents’ movements appear natural. For normal vectors, we originally used SDF textures to control the shading, but this didn’t suit environments with multiple lights and some appearances ended up being less than ideal, so instead of using SDF textures (), we switched to controlling it with vertex normal, which produced far more beautiful shadows. Note 7: Sequencer is an editor for creating cut scenes. A series of scenes can be created by putting cameras and characters onto a timeline.Note 8: A type of texture for 3D shapes that uses SDFs (Signed Distance Fields), which can make shape outlines look very smooth by saving the space between an object’s position and a shape, and stronger textures for objects that enlarge/shrink and animations.SDF textures are effective when there is one source of light, but when multiple light sources hit an object, we get bands that we don’t want. For example, when there is an overlap of SDF textures from light that hits from both the left and right, unnatural 2D bands appear creating an unintentional anime likeness. Therefore, we reverted back to a method of editing vertex normals like those used in fighting video games where anime-like characters appear, which we thought made sense for environments with multiple light sources. Also, similar to live music concerts, there were camera exposure issues, where talents are too bright when a spotlight, like a real camera at a concert, hits them, or too dark when the exposure is adjusted. In order to address such issues, we introduced a system that corrects exposure for each camera using a MIDI controller. We needed to calculate outline extrusion to align with camera angles, because live cameras use 200mm or 300mm telephoto lens settings. We use the Live Link plugin () with our cameras, but this time, we also used the FreeD protocol ( to link our Panasonic camera remotes so we could control the virtual cameras to make it feel like an actual live broadcast, and thanks to our staff, some of whom have knowledge in the TV field, we were able to create a workflow not too dissimilar to that of one. Certain staff members commented that although we are using Unreal Engine, what we are doing is no different from filming in reality, so it turned out to be a good example of combining technology from staff who originally worked in TV and Unreal Engine. Note 9: An Unreal Engine plugin for streaming data to Unreal Engine from external software and devices in real time. It can provide a basis for sharing information in real time such as animation data and camera movements. Note 10: A communication standard for directly transmitting camera tracking information (pan, tilt, zoom, etc.) to a control system in order to coordinate camera movements with computer graphics content.We feel that there is an extremely high capacity to accommodate livestream concepts and talents’ wishes since using Unreal Engine to continue to develop our content. Original concepts, such as weather changes and the elapsing of time, can be implemented with an exceptionally high level of quality, and it has contributed to improved realism and elevated our livestreams, through such lighting improvements and by being able to have interactive expressions such as water bouncing off of the bodies of talents, or rain streaming down faces. That’s great. It seems like there are various ways to create anime likenesses from a system optimized for photorealism. What measures did you have in place to optimize frame rate and lag, also vitally important for livestreams?Our biggest issue was using over 50 light sources once activating ray tracing . First of all, we thoroughly managed channels such as light that did or did not cast a shadow or those that cast light. Also, we used and optimized Variable Rate Shading (VRS) , as a high amount of translucent light puts a lot of stress on the system. Originally, we also wanted to use VRS as it’s adaptive, but we set a constant unit due to time restrictions. In spite of this, we still got 2 to 3 times more speed.We greatly customized DMX (Note 13) light shaft calculations and implemented measures such as reducing the number of steps for ray marching (Note 14), and also optimized packaging. By minimizing the dependency, packaging that has usually taken about an hour was done in roughly 5-10 mins – iteration speed improvements were hugely important from a development efficiency standpoint. Note 11: A kind of technology that generates real images by simulating the volume, angle, refraction, and reflection of the rays of light via a computer. This is used to accurately represent the reflection, refraction and shadowing of light.Note 12: Variable Rate Shading (VRS) is a type of rendering technology for improving performance and picture quality in game development that allows for pixel shading rates (frequency of processing one pixel) to be actively adjusted to reduce the load when processing images. Note 13: DMX (Digital Multiplex) is a digital transmission network that is used to control stage lighting and effects for concerts and events, from the more simple to complicated ones. Note 14: A kind of rendering technique in the ray tracing field.We were doing a lot of customization within Unreal Engine, such as compressing values to 4 bit to preserve the G-buffer, and packing multiple parameters into single channels. Also, to handle translucent areas, we increased deferred rendering (deferred shading) , and increased speed making use of stencil masking. We are also steadily optimizing how we deal with divergent branches in the Shader.CPU optimization was also important. In particular, we greatly improved the performance of the editor while in use by introducing C++ to DMX plugin blueprint processes. In the future, we would like to continue this optimization to make both real-time editing using the editor and use in livestreams possible together. In terms of motion capture, we are using COVER’s original system, and we also developed an original system for integrating data from Vicon () to Motion Builder , and then to Unreal Engine. We could also use Live Link for motion capture as well, but we needed a multi-engine approach because we were developing with both Unreal Engine and Unity (). As well as this, we are developing our own system that takes into account redundancy support and transmission load distribution, so that issues never occur during livestreams.Note 15: A type of 3D computer graphics rendering technique where complex light can be effectively expressed in real time. Note 16: The name of a motion capture systemNote 17: The name of a real-time 3D character animation softwareNote 18: The game engine developed by Unity TechnologiesVery interesting. Thank you very much. I’m extremely interested in this example of actual camera operators and lighting staff directly controlling Unreal Engine rather than engineers.Traditionally, we have needed to allow time to transfer what we designed using the lighting simulation software to the game engine, but this time, we had lighting experts set fixtures () and patch () these designs directly into Unreal Engine. This new trend of having professional lighting staff use the game engine felt really revolutionary. (Note 19) Lighting equipment that use and are controlled by DMX protocols(Note 20) Making partial revision and changesThe Importance of a Multitude of Skills and a Support Network: Strengths and Prospects of Development Using Unreal EngineWhat advantages and/or costs have you felt there have been by introducing Unreal Engine and how has this affected the organization?The speed from production to implementation has been so helpful! Unreal Engine is full of high quality features meaning that even non-engineers can help in the development process, so it took just weeks after we had the concept of the concert to finish the stage prototype.We were able to take a balanced approach over a 7-8 month period for this concert production, by recompiling the engine where necessary while taking full advantage of Unreal Engine’s existing functions, such as the DMX plugin. Unreal Engine is super flexible, being able to handle a variety of different situations, so high quality content can be made in quick time for short-term projects without recompiling the engine, and for large-scale projects, one of the advantages is that our own expressions can be tracked by modifying the source code.There was a mix of staff on this production from a wide range of industries, including gaming, TV, and mobile, and everyone’s skills seemed to fit the project well. However, what kinds of skillsets do Epic Games expect people to have and are required when using Unreal Engine? I deal with a lot of different customers in technical support, but regardless of the industry you are in, it is extremely important to be fully across the concept of real-time rendering. We are coming up with a number of ways to draw frames in such short 16-millisecond amounts of time for the gaming industry, so understanding what can be done under real-time restrictions is so crucial when using Unreal Engine. Sometimes people used to more conventional forms of offline rendering suddenly start using Unreal Engine and are surprised by how restricted they feel. Having gaming industry graphics professionals such as yourself (Okugawa) is such a huge asset to COVER.  Oh, and one more thing: when working on livestreams, it is necessary to have multiple instances of Unreal Engine and have them in sync. Within Unreal Engine, there is a range of tools from those on the network level to synchronizing monitors, but you also need the knowledge to understand what is causing any problems that arise.   It definitely seems that you need a strong mix of people in an engineering team with a diverse set of skills from fields ranging from gaming to film for the production side of livestreams. Could you please tell us about what kind of support you, at Epic Games, provide Unreal Engine users?We have our official Epic Pro Support subscription add-on, as well as our Epic Developer Community forums where users help each other and exchange information. With Epic Pro Support, we provide support for those with highly technical issues and supply the latest information, as well as sharing know-how about profiling and optimization from what we actually do on-site. Our team mainly provides community support: we have recently started sharing Q&As we have received through our pro support subscription with our Epic Developer Community, after removing any confidential information, giving a whole lot of developers access to quality information.Behind this initiative to share Q&A with the public are the strong intentions from our founder (of Epic Games), Tim Sweeney. Tim himself began his career in game development with just a single computer, and truly wishes to support all those, from indie games developers to students, aiming to be creators, at Epic Games are striving to create an environment where creators can grow and develop. Also, there are passionate fans of Unreal Engine everywhere organizing their own independent community events, to which we at Epic Games actively try to attend. There are Unreal Engine enthusiasts not only in Tokyo, Osaka and Fukuoka, but in a lot of different places with a real energy to excite the community around them. We really value these fans and want to support them as best we can. Evolving Technology for a New Future:COVER and Epic Games Redefining Expressions and Entertainment with Unreal EngineCould you tell us what plans Epic Games has for the future and the direction the development of Unreal Engine is heading?We are currently envisioning a dual-axis approach to the development of Unreal Engine at the moment: the vertical evolution of quality along with the horizontal expansion of the platform and its userbase. One of the big themes for Epic Games as a whole is the strengthening of our support for mobile platforms, and optimization so that we can provide high-quality content to a wider range of devices.  Also, our metaverse vision is also strategically important for us. Our global expansion through Fortnite is a great representation of this, with Unreal Engine at the heart of its technical infrastructure. We are focusing a lot on UGC (user-generated content) through our UEFN (Unreal Editor for Fortnite), and creating an environment where not only engineers but regular users can also produce their own content.From a technological perspective, as well as improvements in graphics, we believe that movement and motion expressions are becoming an important topic. We (at Epic Games) have a comprehensive service where people can create a realistic human called MetaHuman, and we have recently added a function called MetaHuman Animator where, just by filming your own expressions using an iPhone, you can transfer these movements to MetaHuman. At the moment, we are focusing on developing the realism of digital humans, but we also plan to expand this so that this technology can be applied to various talents and other expressions. By further improving the real-time nature of it, we expect that even more natural and interactive expressions will be possible.The use of the fully immersive display Sphere in Las Vegas has also received quite a lot of attention recently. In most cases, a video that has been previously rendered is projected onto a screen, but more and more cases of projections in real-time using Unreal Engine are emerging. For example, the spherical screen of Sphere was used at a live concert for the band Phish in the US, who are known for their improvisation, to project graphics in real-time using Unreal Engine to match their performance. A Fortnite event in New York also had multiple screens around Times Square that were being controlled simultaneously and linked to artists’ performances. We hope to use Unreal Engine for more of these kinds of immersive experiences within Japan as well. Unreal Fest 2025 Tokyo is planned for November 14 and 15 of this year in Takanawa, Tokyo, where all the latest use cases of Unreal Engine in various industries and information on the technology will be shared over the 2 days on an even bigger scale than last year, so we hope you can join us if you are interested.What challenges would COVER like to undertake using Unreal Engine in the future?We would like to further improve the quality of our livestreams, and for not only that, but for a range of other events as well. For instance, every summer, hololive holds a swimsuit event and with Unreal Engine, it may even be possible to have talents swimming underwater as an example. We also hope to increase our AR (augmented reality) content combining both real-life and animation together, and with how compatible it is with real-time lighting, we also have our sights on developing our on-location content and TV programs too.    We are also considering content that features more interactivity with fans, taking advantage of its unique features as a game engine. At COVER, we are also developing a metaverse, so we hope to use Unreal Engine to develop content in the 3D space, and not just video streams. We can see from this chat that a range of experts are now taking on the challenge of blending the seemingly contradictory elements of realism and animated expression. The similarities of both Epic Games and COVER, who are supporting creators through technological development as well as talents and their aspirations, opens up a whole new world of possibilities for VTuber entertainment.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>We Held Our Third All- Employee Meeting and Announced the COVER AWARD 2024 Winners</title><link>https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en/list/2275</link><author>平松梨沙</author><category>COVER</category><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en">COVEREdge Magazine</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[On May 27, 2025, we held our third COVER Corporation All-Employee Meeting with over 700 employees in attendance, and included opening remarks from the directors, the announcement of the COVER AWARD 2024, a group photo session, and a casual networking reception. President and CEO Motoaki Tanigo reflected on the company’s journey so far, with the message, “Let’s not be afraid of change and evolve.” The COVER AWARD 2024 honored individuals and projects from the previous year that exemplified the company’s values and delivered meaningful results.Individual awards were presented to a member from the Sales Development Division (for securing national clients and proposing innovative promotions), a member from the Creative Production Division (for promoting Houshou Marine’s Beauty Witch model project and managing quality control for a new 3D model), and a member from the Product Development Division (for delivering live event merchandise on a tight schedule while maintaining a high-quality product). During the awards ceremony, each division head shared their thoughts on why the recipients were selected, followed by presentations from the winners themselves, reflecting on the projects they had worked on over the past year. Two projects were selected for the Project Awards. The offline event “hololive GAMERS fes. Cho-Cho-Cho-Cho GAMERS” received their award for delivering an offline experience focused on gameplay. The “Virtual Concert Development with Unreal Engine” project was awarded for bringing ReGLOSS 3D LIVE “Sakura Mirage” to life by evolving our technology through the effective use of existing assets and expertise gained in a Unity-based environment.The event brought employees from different divisions together, deepening everyone’s mutual understanding and connections with each other, and providing inspiration for the year ahead.Note: All division affiliations are as of FY 2024.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【順次予約開始】hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME オフィシャルホロカケース・オフィシャルスリーブ 癒月ちょこ／兎田ぺこら／尾丸ポルカ／アイラニ・イオフィフティーン／ネリッサ・レイヴンクロフト：25年9月19日発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/hololive-official-card-game-supply05/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 01:35:48 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[︎発売日2025年9月19日︎価格デッキケース：880円／ スリーブ 990円【関連】hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Thursday, June 26 at 1:36 AM EDT</title><link>https://warosu.org/vt/thread/101604976</link><author></author><category>/vt/ /news/</category><category>VTubers</category><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 05:36:51 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vt.rita.moe/">/vt//news/</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Where Is Hololive Vtuber Usada Pekora in Death Stranding 2 - Siliconera</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijwFBVV95cUxOeERGVm1LTDdkd24wNHZQZ1FvaGJ1VXRENXprQjMzbFBpY1A5R1BxTWRIWGlUYmk4amdpc1FEb0NCdDJLWDBIcFNMY21MRlVieXVMS05iUU5uOUczckw2ekNNVHRHaU9mZVJqUTlOdWtRTEpPWkpVeU1XQmtDWFVQcl9ackF6S1dQbkxnMzVwaw?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 04:20:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Rift Of The Necrodancer X Hololive Music Pack Now Live - NintendoSoup</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijAFBVV95cUxQb28xQ001eDBoeEVzTC01YW8xalRtcHgzTWZyMW9IRGVlZlk2RnF0WG5FUWFuYVdxU2h0bzZ1cEJ2bGd3aVRsVTluWk5uVW1Dc01vbDJ3ZzI3WmhjdzMyLUFWQk1BdVlGVWxpVHZJWFI4WkQwTlgyMXNJZ1IyT1J2Z1oxLVpsMEdlbm1OR9IBjAFBVV95cUxQb28xQ001eDBoeEVzTC01YW8xalRtcHgzTWZyMW9IRGVlZlk2RnF0WG5FUWFuYVdxU2h0bzZ1cEJ2bGd3aVRsVTluWk5uVW1Dc01vbDJ3ZzI3WmhjdzMyLUFWQk1BdVlGVWxpVHZJWFI4WkQwTlgyMXNJZ1IyT1J2Z1oxLVpsMEdlbm1ORw?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 23:26:33 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Rift of the NecroDancer reveals Hololive Music Pack DLC - Nintendo Everything</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxQbC04MVNUbHJpNllRdWctNGljaDFub1dFVjhNSjh5eXlZaEVTUWZXZWdFRS1vd1p2Um9VN2JYMHdXeFMyUlVKbWhTNXZyMmJyd2pMeS1JYzhiRnZHcVdiOG5UcUMxU1BPZnR5MDZHZl9jV052clZTcmVaRjZ4ZVhiSjJUc2x3SFgzbHVicGVTZV8?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 16:45:34 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【6/27〜開催】DMMオンクレ「儒烏風亭らでん特別セレクトフェア」開催</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/raden-dmm-onkure-select/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 15:50:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[︎開催期間25年6月27日（金）18:00～2025年7月28日（月）23:59「DMMオンクレ」は、hololive DEV_IS所属VTuber「儒烏風亭らでん」がセレクトした景品を獲得できる「特別セレクトフェア」を開催今回のセレクトフェアでは、儒烏風亭らでんの好きな「きのこ」・「プリン」・「日本酒のアテ」がの中から獲得できます。景品1個獲得につき、限定イラストのステッカーをプレゼント特別セレクトフェア対象景品を獲得された方の中から抽選で、DMMオンクレ限定イラストを使用した「A3布ポスター」が当たるキャンペーンを実施抽選は儒烏風亭らでんYouTubeチャンネルで開催予定・詳細は後日発表DMMオンクレのプレイに必要なDC（3,500DC）に、DMMオンクレ限定デザインの「アクリルステッカー」がセットになったお得なDCパックを販売]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Brace Yourself Games x hololive Collaboration: hololive DLC Pack Comes to Rift of the NecroDancer! | COVER Corp. - カバー株式会社</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXkFVX3lxTE56ZGU3cTI5eGt1N1FRMENWZEMxX2Z1Z2N2N1BuNXVXcTFtb3FRNUpSTjExTXVWNGJudGZEOUZUcjQyRjQ4TXlwU3pLcDVoZjdWb0RaQ1ZDNUFkX2RnYWc?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:25:04 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive Gen 0 Octopus Card Pre-Sale! - カバー株式会社</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXkFVX3lxTE9pcEtRNldDSEQ3S3RYekludWh3S1I3VGVfQldOLUh0WGZURmtZNE5zVGx1c3Zxdl9iWWNtTm9lbWQ4V0Jpb3UzdWVCTU11MWdiSE0tUWc1LVRySUtKalE?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:25:04 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Wednesday, June 25 at 9:24 AM EDT</title><link>https://warosu.org/vt/thread/101309741#p101574842</link><author></author><category>/vt/ /news/</category><category>VTubers</category><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 13:24:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vt.rita.moe/">/vt//news/</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive Gen 0 Octopus Card Pre-Sale! | NEWS | hololive official website - hololive.hololivepro.com</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaEFVX3lxTE9jX3U5WWd1VklvanY2SlRPMWI1RFhxY2Z4LWpCYjQwTU94d0JyRmYwWlRSMllnMXp4ZGtaUzdrQjQwZ2JMVnRLb21yRzRKV3dTSDVESDkzLXh5dXFtU0ZGM2RWOUVvTjJQ?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 04:51:49 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive Gen 0 Octopus Card Pre-Sale!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250625-01-172/</link><author>os_pr</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 04:00:54 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[COVER Corporation has officially announced an extended collaboration between hololive production and Octopus Card, unveiling a series of exclusive physical Octopus card-sets featuring the beloved talents of hololive Gen 0.
Pre-orders for this special edition are now available at: https://pump-water.com/product-category/hololiveThe hololive Gen 0 Octopus Card set is available in two editions: a  and a , perfect for both practical users and passionate collectors.
Showcasing Gen 0 members in classic Hong Kong-style outfits, take them along as you wander the streets, savour local delicacies, and make them part of your everyday life!Special Edition Octopus Single Card SetSet Includes:
・ hololive Gen 0 Special Edition Octopus Card
・ Octopus Card Holder with Lanyard*Designs under supervisionSpecial Edition Octopus Collector SetSet Includes:
・ hololive Gen 0 Special Edition Octopus Card
・ Magnetic Octopus Card Holder
・ Card Display Stand
・ Acrylic Shikishi Artboard
・ Gift Box PackagingPre-order your exclusive Octopus Card to take Gen 0 talents with you wherever you go!
The products will be available for purchase on Pump-Water.com, the platform dedicated to licensed anime merchandise.
*Designs under supervisionOctopus is a contactless stored value card that provides customers with a simple, safe, and secure way to pay. First launched in 1997 across public transport systems, the applications of the Octopus card have since expanded to include retail stores and various facilities, making everyday life more convenient.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Brace Yourself Games x hololive Collaboration: hololive DLC Pack Comes to Rift of the NecroDancer! | NEWS - ホロライブ公式サイト</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaEFVX3lxTFBXR3RGbmUwMmI1VE5fT0tsUklWOE53dmRrS2g1Z3pKR2JVRTkzcWJPanBOMkc2X2JwODZLWlB4ZmdQdExJcjJ5UVdwNy1sTWdmS0NVbS1wYXpMZ1FQRU4yWEYtcy1EY0Jw?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 02:07:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Brace Yourself Games x hololive Collaboration: hololive DLC Pack Comes to Rift of the NecroDancer!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250625-01-171/</link><author>os_pr</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 23:00:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[June 25, 2025 – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) has announced a collaboration between Brace Yourself Games and hololive production. An all-new downloadable content (DLC) pack featuring hololive talents will be added to Rift of the NecroDancer, the game.
The collaboration will launch simultaneously on Steam and Nintendo Switch on June 25th.Players will be able to sync the beat to five brand-new tracks featuring from hololive talents – including the graduated Gawr Gura. As a special promotion for this exciting crossover, the track “REFLECT” by Gawr Gura will be available to all Rift of the NecroDancer players to download for free.The full lineup of songs in the hololive Music Pack includes:
・ “REFLECT” by Gawr Gura (Free to download!)
・ “BIBBIDIBA” by Hoshimachi Suisei
・ “Ahoy!! 我ら宝鐘海賊団☆” by Houshou Marine
・ “Play Dice!” by Hakos Baelz
・ “Carbonated Love” by IRySEach song will be available for individual purchase at $1.99 USD, or fans can grab the entire collection as a bundle for a 25% discount.
We hope you enjoy it! The hololive DLC drops on Steam and Nintendo Switch on June 25th.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Final Hololive Dodgers 2025 Merchandise Revealed - Siliconera</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiggFBVV95cUxNampJZWVJRUFhQ3FsTVhqWU9mbDRmaDhRU3AybVFESC16aHBqS09KeXVUa0VScmxoQ1Zka09VUUIyR3RObklNVWs2UlhiVXVueF95UG5lLXlub3czb1RRbkpJYkdOS3hiakg0OW9WaXNrVHFONlA4d3lJTlhjYlRERnVn?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>&quot;BIG NEWS&quot; Watchalong (spoiler: It was worth the wait)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ge1x-Eyc4Qk</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ge1x-Eyc4Qk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 07:44:33 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[☄️ Hoshimachi Suisei PC Case + Keycap & Desk Pad Bundle Pre-order NOW
👉 Get yours here (please) https://hyte.co/hwikky-hololive

hololive Original Stream Link: https://www.youtube.com/live/huplUO3zqb8
hololive EN 3rd Concert Ticketmaster Link: https://www.ticketmaster.com/hololive-english-tickets/artist/2994403

✨ Support & Follow hwikky
- X (Twitter): x.com/hwikkyofficial
- Patreon: patreon.com/hwikky
- Ko-fi: ko-fi.com/hwikky
- StreamLabs Tips: streamlabs.com/hwikky/tip

#holoAllforOne #hololiveEN
#hololive #ホロライブ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hololive Vtuber DLC heading to Rift of the NecroDancer - GoNintendo</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilwFBVV95cUxQWDJDNktSM2hINUtpNFRKRXJqclBxS1oyRDg4MmpLdUpQNFppelZmSThacTBkblFhSVp0QUFVank4QXFMeEdZNTZ1UzEydmVaTVpPNWo0OXhNRy10THpfSHh2VTJ0eVlhNER5ekpEQmFvSnJuazBNdE1ZVGRlVUpnT1FCR0ZxMU16NENfTGhJZENvZTFzaWtB?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 04:42:52 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hololive Production Official Shop Using Death Stranding 2 Tape - Siliconera</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMilAFBVV95cUxPcXJ0cDBpbDdzTTRyTmRjS25waXBJT1ZLa09QNXlXNnBWZjVINzRxdzRra3psTE1lanpWTkU3dlpYQm5lcWtlVHAyZ1ktRGVvdTBsZWd4Zjh6d3Z0Y3R4LWdRVHBkY3VJSllkZjhiU1ozWU9FMDh4R0tLVEVWS1FIM0pCcmRmYkdqbC1pYVZabWt5MHB0?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>I CAN DO THIS ALL DAY (2nd Try - holoEN 3rd Concert Ticket)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9tJdWlwg7Ms</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/9tJdWlwg7Ms?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 06:53:19 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[☄️ Hoshimachi Suisei PC Case + Keycap & Desk Pad Bundle Pre-order NOW
👉 Get yours here (please) https://hyte.co/hwikky-hololive

Ticketmaster Link: https://www.ticketmaster.com/all-for-one-hololive-english-3rd-new-york-new-york-08-23-2025/event/3C0062CED2540BD8

✨ Support & Follow hwikky
- X (Twitter): x.com/hwikkyofficial
- Patreon: patreon.com/hwikky
- Ko-fi: ko-fi.com/hwikky
- StreamLabs Tips: streamlabs.com/hwikky/tip

#holoAllforOne #hololiveEN
#hololive #ホロライブ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hololive English tickets on sale in New York at Radio City Music Hall - TicketNews</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiqAFBVV95cUxQT3RVWVhzODJHdmFjazZrVEd2WUtKS0ZSXzhobUVzYnBiTGt6YzNmbjBlT1B6ckJFM0lITTE1bzdfZ3czcW1BeTc3SkZ4czlYVzZuMTFxV2ZaZE5HNllLR25FMzRyTVgtQWNIMEpLRnlPV0dIUmZFTGpubGN0WXBCenY4d1JSa013THNqdkdFSG1vVmhHS05saGlzRTNGcW8wWE5pa2JfM3c?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【作ってみた】これ…買ったほうがいいぞ‼ #shorts #hololive #nanoblocks</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/F5UXkPwJ5J8</link><author>くーぽん</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/F5UXkPwJ5J8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 13:00:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC_TI5ueTHqo7AJwapquSZRQ">くーぽん</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hololive&apos;s new talent auditions begin June 20! Special interview articles with Houshou Marine and Fuwamoco also released. - Saiga NAK</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMib0FVX3lxTE9EM0lQUDVKT1NDRVRZS3Z3a2N3OGhSaFpSZkFFQk5memd6U01jWFo3SWVPaDVUWmlaMTRCYjhveEZjSHd5WnFMdWxZZTV5NE9BZFcyeEFXb2pDRjRBQWFjRVRUZ1AzcjNMZXhpRnNDVdIBdEFVX3lxTE1UNjBXMTVNd1F3ZEZSTkJSWFRWRDN3ZUJZRUVZQkRwWFRmbVZ6c3hzY2FvY0ZxclNaX1BMTHNRc2k0c2M5aFlVV1pDQ1E0QzkyZzFINENZSE9ZQ1dGRUV0cmpSN2pYRXBaWk5PVHRadFNmY0xX?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 10:23:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Make your aspirations a reality! New auditions for Hololive begin June 20. - Saiga NAK</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMic0FVX3lxTE1lRnZrRDBGX3FvV1pKWWxwS29kVDFBWlppcFhjUjFrbXNPaEFLWU03NHFGOFAxam5iTHpBd2JwQXcwcEN5eTJEcTNkOW82NFZtVXk1RV9qQ2U3TEZlXzdnbS0taGlVNWpGOHdrVmkzN3BUaUXSAXRBVV95cUxNVDYwVzE1TXdRd2RGUk5CUlhUVkQzd2VCWUVFWUJEcFhUZm1WenN4c2Nhb2NGcXJTWl9QTExzUXNpNHNjOWhZVVdaQ0NRNEM5MmcxSDRDWUhPWUNXRkVFdHJqUjdqWEVwWlpOT1R0WnRTZmNMVw?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 10:23:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>I am Joining the Battle (result: I lost)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gexynJgQqdI</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/gexynJgQqdI?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 10:19:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[☄️ Hoshimachi Suisei PC Case + Keycap & Desk Pad Bundle Pre-order NOW
👉 Get yours here (please) https://hyte.co/hwikky-hololive

Ticketmaster Link: https://www.ticketmaster.com/all-for-one-hololive-english-3rd-new-york-new-york-08-23-2025/event/3C0062CED2540BD8

✨ Support & Follow hwikky
- X (Twitter): x.com/hwikkyofficial
- Patreon: patreon.com/hwikky
- Ko-fi: ko-fi.com/hwikky
- StreamLabs Tips: streamlabs.com/hwikky/tip

#holoAllforOne #hololiveEN
#hololive #ホロライブ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】ホロライブ ラバマスARTグミ Vol.2：25年10月発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/rabamasu-art-gumi-vol-2/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 01:47:21 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブの「ラバマスART」第２弾！ メンバービジュアルデザインのラバマスは全19種！ 背景からメンバーが飛び出て見える２層構造仕様です。 グレープ味のグミは全部で３種類です。 ～ラバマスARTとは～ 「デザイン性にこだわった2層構造のラバーマスコット」です。 イラストが背景から飛び出したラバマスは約55mm角！ホロライブの「ラバマスART」が登場！「ラバーマスコット×等身イラスト」の新アイテム！ぶどう味のグミは全部で３種類！「デザイン性にこだわった2層構造のラバーマスコット」です。イラストが背景から飛び出したラバマスは約55mm角のビックサイズ！【単品内容】●ラバーマスコット1個（全19種）・風真いろは本体：PVCH約55mm×W約55mm]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【発売中】Vジャンプ 2025年08月号 / 博衣こより hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME 付録</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/vjump-2508/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 13:54:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[︎発売：6月20日︎連載：「ほろらいぶいっ！」ホロライブ連載企画掲載あり︎雑誌付録：hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME 博衣こより【関連グッズ】hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【再版・予約受付中】ねんどろいど 一伊那尓栖：25年10月発売予定</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/nendroid-inanis/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 03:15:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[【初版】24年1月24日まで（GOODSMILE）【再販】25年7月30日まで（GOODSMILE）【DX】9,900円（税込）【通常】6,900円（税込）]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Report from the hololive production Official Shop: A New Transmission Hub for VTuber Culture – From Tokyo to the World</title><link>https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en/list/2228</link><author>cover_hirata</author><category>COVER</category><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en">COVEREdge Magazine</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[An Atmosphere Built Upon a Station. A New Fan Experience Full of Original Illustrations and Unique Content.The store, which will be available until spring 2026, is expected to be a new transmission hub for VTuber culture right on Tokyo’s doorstep, a destination for domestic and international tourists.One of the unique features of this shop is the original merchandise that changes depending on the time of year. For example, in December 2024, a range of products featuring hololive production talents in hololive Station Costumes designed by illustrator Hiragi to look like station attendants were released, including acrylic stands and name tag-style acrylic badges, which received a lot of support from fans. Inside the shop, one can hear exclusive in-store announcements recorded by the talents, and find handwritten signatures and comments from talents scattered all over the shop, creating a station-like atmosphere and bringing together all sorts of people. *Announcements will change at different times of the year.Unique initiatives can also be taken on, as the store can be easily adapted to suit requests from talents. Special campaigns or projects are implemented to coincide with a talent’s live concert or an album release, which talents in turn have brought up during their livestreams. Fans can look forward to different projects and campaigns throughout the year, with new themed merchandise releases and announcements whenever they visit the store.Best-Sellers and Creating Unique, Valued Experiences Through Offline StoresWhen asked what products are the most prolific sellers, KIDDY LAND’s Kaneaki Kubushiro, the shop manager, said that the station attendant uniform series of original merchandise and confectionery has been particularly popular.“We consistently sell 5-10 units of confectionery featuring the talents in their hololive Station Costumes every hour, with certain customers buying the maximum amount they can for restricted merchandise” he said, talking about the high demand for souvenirs taking full advantage of the prime location that is Tokyo Station.hololive Station Costume acrylic stands are also strong sellers, with many fans coming to the store in search of their oshi’s design, a highly valued piece of memorabilia.He spoke about their popularity as these merchandise are easily portable for fans’ : “The plushies and mascots have also been well-received because their design is perfect for daily use: they are a good size for fans to store in or decorate their bags with, so they can have one or more with them all the time. We get many customers who buy plushies of their oshi in bulk, so sales rival those of the hololive Station series.”The shop offers different experience value for fans, who have mainly shopped online, in physically coming to the store and actually holding the products in their hands before choosing their purchases.“I was thrilled to be able to see and choose my oshi’s plushies in person to see how big they were in actuality and how they felt,” said a male Sakura Miko fan hailing from Chiba Prefecture, who visited the store for the first time: a visit that coincided with a cheer screening in Shinagawa, Tokyo.Another male customer, who had been to the shop about 3 or 4 times to support Kazama Iroha,  places importance on the value of collector’s items, elaborating on his specific reason for being at the shop: “Because my oshi, Kazama Iroha, ends her sentences with “ござる” (), there is the wordplay “ござるの5” (), and so I want to collect 5 (“” in Japanese) of her plushies. I already have one at home, so I bought four more.” Kubushiro also talked about how popular the handwritten signature displays were, as fans can only see them because there is a physical store: “These are also extremely popular. Photos [of these displays] actively get circulated around social media because almost everyone who comes to the shop wants to take a picture of them, and we even get a lot of people asking us where their oshi’s signature is. These signature displays are valuable because the talents actually came to sign them in person, so you can only see them here, which has pleased a lot of customers over the first month since opening.”The shop is a new point of contact between fans and talents, offering special experiences that one cannot get online. It contributes to further stimulating the fan community, where there is tremendous value in “real” elements at a physical shop like this in a landscape where the digital medium is the main battleground for VTubers.“What has particularly left an impression on me is seeing customers lining up patiently while holding a suitcase or a huge backpack. Despite having such heavy luggage with them, many customers come ‘only wanting to buy one item.’ The crowds get really lively when there’s an ongoing campaign or event,” said Kubushiro, also mentioning that there are often lines of up to 50 people outside the shop before and after live events. The Global Expansion of VTuber Culture and hololive production from the Perspective of a Diverse FanbaseWhen asked who makes up the main clientele at the shop, Kubushiro responded, “About 70-80% are male, with about 20-30% from overseas. In particular, we get more customers from Asia, but on holidays we get westerners coming in as well.” He also mentioned that tax-free purchases can be made as part of the shop’s efforts to appeal to incoming tourists.We asked a female customer, who was visiting the store to get a Fuwawa Abyssgard random card and had visited about three times so far, about her impressions of the shop: “There are a lot of overseas visitors here early in the morning on weekdays.”When looking at customer trends a little deeper, we can see that VTubers are supported by many age groups, with many families also visiting the shop. We spoke to a family who were at the shop with their 10-year-old son, a Sakura Miko fan, about how they became fans of hololive: “We originally started out watching game livestreams, which is how we first heard about VTubers. It was because there were some VTubers among these video game streamers that we started enjoying VTuber videos as a family.”We also asked an elementary schoolgirl, a fan of Hoshimachi Suisei, making the most of her winter vacation and visiting the shop with her family from Kawasaki about how she came to know about hololive: “I became a fan after hearing her sing on YouTube, and now I support her wholeheartedly.”A male fan in his 40s, visiting the shop to buy Tokoyami Towa merchandise for his colleague, talked about music content as the gateway for new fans: “I am stopping in on the way to a jazz concert. I am a big music lover, and first learned about VTubers through Hoshimachi Suisei’s appearance on THE FIRST TAKE, and from then on I was a fan. I am planning on getting Hoshimachi Suisei’s upcoming LP.”A Hub for Fans Across the Globe. An Offline Store Opening Doors to New Possibilities.Store manager Kubushiro, based on what he has witnessed in Tokyo, spoke about the shop’s prospects: “We will continue to manage this shop by prioritizing the special feelings people get when buying a particular product, or looking forward to seeing something at the shop. I hope to be able to continue developing this store, making full use of the space here at Tokyo Station for 1, 2, even 3 years to come, and based on the success we’ve had here at Tokyo Station, expand to have more locations all over Japan.”For instance, he envisions a future with an Osaka store that fans can visit whenever a concert is held there. COVER President Tanigo still has the vision he has had since the company’s inception of “wanting to create a company that breaks through onto the global stage with Japanese entertainment,” and continues to pour all of his effort into making people more aware of VTubers both within Japan and on a global scale. Establishing a hololive production Official Shop in such an international location like Tokyo Station, where an abundance of overseas tourists can also easily visit the store, is an excellent opportunity for, not only domestic fans, but fans and tourists from all over the world to experience VTuber culture, and a step towards being able to share VTuber culture with so many more people.  There will be a lot of interest in what sort of possibilities this new hub on Tokyo’s doorstep can bring to the future development of VTuber culture, as a space for experiencing the world of hololive production and a place where fans from all over the world can gather.*This article is based on interviews conducted on December 28, 2024, and may differ from current information.First Store in West Japan! hololive production official shop in Osaka Umeda Opening Soon!Shop Name: hololive production official shop in Osaka UmedaLocation: B1F North Building, Hankyu Sanban Gai, 1-1-3 Shibata, Kita-ku, OsakaDates: June 27, 2025 – Spring 2026Opening Hours:  10:00 AM – 9:00 PM (JST)*Opening hours will follow HANKYU SANBAN GAI hours of business.https://hololive.hololivepro.com/en/events/shopumeda/]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Tuesday, June 17 at 6:16 PM EDT</title><link>https://warosu.org/vt/thread/101309741</link><author></author><category>/vt/ /news/</category><category>VTubers</category><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 22:16:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vt.rita.moe/">/vt//news/</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>How to Identify and Avoid Black Companies in the VTuber Industry</title><link>https://vtubersensei.com/2025/06/17/how-to-identify-and-avoid-black-companies-in-the-vtuber-industry/</link><author>Thomas Toblu</author><category>VTubers</category><enclosure url="https://vtubersensei.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/former-hololive-talent-kiryu-coco.jpg?w=640" length="" type="text/html"/><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 11:43:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vtubersensei.com/">VTuber Sensei</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A “Black Company” (ブラック企業, burakku kigyō) is a Japanese term for an exploitative, sweatshop-style employer that forces excessive unpaid work and mistreats employees. In Japan this commonly means young workers required to work brutal overtime without extra pay, subjected to verbal abuse and “power harassment” from bosses. VTuber agencies worldwide have been likened to black companies when they impose similar conditions on talent. Agencies promise stardom but may demand long hours, strict obedience, and ambiguous contracts. This can be especially dangerous for female VTubers, who may face added pressures or harassment. In this context,  warning signs of an exploitative VTuber company and knowing how to protect yourself are crucial.Originally coined in Japan, a black company is one that exploits staff much like a sweatshop: hiring young or inexperienced workers and forcing them to work excessive overtime without pay, often under bullying or harassing supervisors. Employees who try to quit can be threatened with humiliation or litigation. By extension, VTuber agencies that treat their performers as disposable labor – imposing grueling schedules, unclear rules, or punishing talent for speaking up – are sometimes called black companies by fans and insiders. These agencies may exploit the  of entertainers, offering fame in exchange for unreasonable demands. For example, some VTuber contracts bind talent  to the agency: “the talent will exclusively perform entertainment activities for the … agency” in return for support. A healthy agency might also bind talent to themselves, but black agencies use exclusivity to prevent talent from leaving or working elsewhere even when conditions deteriorate.Globally, fans and VTubers have grown wary of agencies with these traits. Media reports have noted VTuber companies coming under fire for “abrupt graduations, terminations, and suggestions that the company has stymied its talent’s attempts at potential growth opportunities”. In other words, when agencies suddenly cut ties with popular performers or block them from succeeding independently, supporters cry “black company.” Paying attention to how an agency treats its current talent is key to spotting trouble.One stark example involves , a popular Nijisanji EN VTuber. In Feb 2024, Nijisanji  Selen’s contract without warning  All her social accounts were immediately locked and her videos removed – far from the mutual “graduation” that is normal in VTuber culture. Only later did details emerge: Selen had been hospitalized for “poor management and a toxic work environment” at the agency. This incident sparked an unprecedented public outcry and even saw corporate sponsors dropping ties in solidarity.Another case was  (Nijisanji EN), who was fired in March 2023 over alleged copyright and “offensive” remarks. Nijisanji claimed she violated rules, but Zaion’s supporters pointed out inconsistencies and possible misunderstandings. In both the Selen and Zaion incidents, critics noted that Nijisanji’s handling was abrupt and opaque, with no chance for talent to defend themselves. Such incidents became rallying cries: fans observed that talents were even “paying out of pocket for assets and materials” because the company refused to cover basic expenses. (In fact, Selen had to fund a fan-art contest prize herself when Nijisanji insisted the money come from the VTuber’s personal funds.) These stories are symptomatic of black company behavior in VTubing: shifting blame onto the talent, demanding free labor, and terminating contracts unilaterally.Other VTuber agencies have faced criticism. New international groups like VReverie were even labeled  by former affiliates on social media. While details vary, the pattern is similar: former talents describe “toxic work environments,” withheld payments, or harassment by management. Whenever an agency consistently mistreats talent with no accountability, veteran VTubers warn others to beware.Challenges Unique to Female VTubersFemale VTubers can face additional risks in exploitative settings. In many cultures, women entertainers are subject to stricter expectations and more intense scrutiny. VTubers (virtual YouTubers) are no exception. Female talents often attract “parasocial” fan attachments – fans who feel a personal, emotional connection to the streamer. While a lot of parasocial support is positive, some of it can become dangerous. In practice, this means female VTubers are more likely to be harassed online, doxxed, or have false rumors spread. Management may do little to protect them, or worse, pressure them to cater to overzealous haters (sometimes calling it ).Parasocial Relationships in VTubing Explained (a female VTuber) was suspended in 2020 after intense online backlash: she had simply mentioned Taiwan on-stream and was flooded by nationalist harassment, leading her agency to suspend her despite her innocence. This illustrates how quickly a female VTuber’s career can be derailed by fan attacks and agency panic.Legally, female VTubers in virtual workplaces have the same rights as in any job. Experts emphasize that harassment via an avatar or chat is still harassment. For instance, U.S. labor lawyers point out that “the absence of actual touching is immaterial… [Harassing] verbal comments based on sex in an employment context is unlawful”, even in virtual settings This means an agency is responsible if a talent faces gender-based harassment, cyberbullying, or worse (and can be liable if it doesn’t address it). Unfortunately, some VTuber companies have been slow to implement clear anti-harassment policies. Female VTubers may also encounter pressure to adopt certain “cute” or sexualized personas; if an agency uses coercion or unfair expectations in this regard, that is another red flag.In summary, female VTubers must navigate both the general risks of a black-agency environment  gendered pressures. They may need stronger support networks (fellow VTubers, unions, legal advisors) to ensure they aren’t exploited or silenced.Red Flags and Warning Signs of an Exploitative VTuber AgencyVague or Missing Contract: No clear, written contract (or one packed with unclear terms) is a major red flag. Legitimate agencies will provide a professional talent contract. Be especially cautious of agreements that never specify pay, scope of work, or duration, or that can be terminated on a whim. (For reference, a typical VTuber “talent exclusive contract” should at least state that the talent performs exclusively for the agency, and outline mutual obligations.) Being asked to work “for exposure” is a classic exploitative tactic. Agencies forcing long hours of streaming, content creation, or fan service without overtime pay are using black-company tactics. Watch out if you’re routinely working late nights or weekends beyond any agreed schedule, or if they require you to skip breaks or sleep in the office/studio.Verbal Abuse or Harassment: Any bullying by managers, producers, or staff is unacceptable. Black companies often use “power harassment” to control employees. If agency staff or supervisors frequently belittle talents, issue ultimatums, or pressure you relentlessly, take it very seriously. Agencies should clearly explain how and when you’ll be paid (salary vs. revenue share vs. commissions). Beware if payment terms are never discussed or if money disappears mysteriously. Delayed or withheld earnings, unexplained “commissions,” or being told “you’ll see it eventually” are strong warning signs. (For example, Nijisanji reportedly blamed Selen for “delays in payment,” but artists she worked with confirmed she  paid them out of pocket – suggesting the blame was misdirection.)Ownership of Your Persona and Content: Many agencies claim ownership of the VTuber character or exclusive rights to your name and likeness. A one-sided clause that gives the company total control over your character design, brand, or even videos can be problematic. Legitimate contracts may license your character for agency use, but red flags include clauses that forbid you ever using your own avatar or name outside the company, even after you leave.Strict Exclusivity or Long Lock-in: If the agency demands an unusually long exclusive term (several years) with onerous penalties for early exit, be wary. Standard talent contracts often last 1–2 years with renewal options; anything much longer may be designed to trap you.Exploitive Auditions or Fees: Sometimes black agencies charge “management fees” up front or require you to pay for training, costumes, or equipment that should be provided. Legitimate agencies may require standard fees or deposits, but watch out if costs keep mounting or aren’t clearly justified.Sudden Termination or Blacklisting: A hallmark of a bad agency is firing talent without notice or mutual agreement. Nijisanji’s treatment of Selen – removing her from the roster  and locking her accounts overnight – is an extreme example. If an agency has a history of “graduating” or dropping VTubers abruptly (especially with public accusations or deleted content), that indicates low job security.Punishing Whistleblowers: If current or former talents speaking up about poor conditions are ostracized, threatened with NDAs, or prevented from leaving, consider that a warning. Black companies often try to silence complaints through legal threats or social pressure.Poor Reputation or Insider Reports: When researching an agency, pay attention to community chatter. If multiple VTubers or staff privately say the environment is abusive, believe it. Likewise, if the company is secretive about contract terms or refuses to put promises in writing, exercise caution.Any one of these signs doesn’t guarantee a company is exploitative, but several together strongly suggest trouble. Always trust your instincts: if something  off (like management making impossible demands or colleagues disappearing suddenly), take it seriously.If You’re Under Contract: Rights and Safety MeasuresIf you find yourself already working for a problematic agency, there are steps you can take to protect yourself:Know Your Contract and Rights: Carefully read your contract. In most places, a written employment or talent contract is legally binding; if you signed nothing, the agreement may be unenforceable. Check for exit clauses: does the contract specify a notice period, buyout options, or conditions for termination? Consult local labor laws: in many countries, forcing unpaid overtime or withholding wages violates employment law. If possible, seek legal advice from an attorney experienced in entertainment or labor law (some firms specialize in VTuber issues). Keep meticulous records of all mistreatment or contract breaches. Note dates, times, and details whenever you are asked to work beyond agreed hours, or subjected to harassment or unfair terms. Save copies of emails, messages, and any social media posts related to your work. Take screenshots of chat logs and keep them secure. This evidence can be vital if you need to prove your case to authorities or negotiate an exit.Follow Internal Procedures (If Any): If the company has a harassment or grievance policy, use it. Some contracts or handbooks outline a process for complaints. File written reports with HR or designated contacts, keeping your own copies. Even if you suspect management won’t act, having formally complained shows you raised concerns in good faith.Seek External Advice and Support: Look for unions or associations that represent entertainers in your region. For example, actors’ unions (like SAG-AFTRA in the U.S., Equity in the U.K., or the Japanese ) may offer guidance to performers. If no specific union exists, legal aid societies or labor rights groups can sometimes help with contract disputes. Peers in the VTuber community can also advise or refer you to reputable lawyers. Don’t underestimate reaching out to a lawyer even for a consultation; specialized entertainment attorneys exist and may work on a sliding scale. If you experience sexual harassment, threats, or stalking, treat it like any other workplace violence: inform the agency (preferably in writing) and consider contacting local law enforcement or advocacy groups. The virtual nature of VTubing doesn’t remove real-world protections: for instance, U.S. law recognizes that unwanted sexual comments or virtual touching of an avatar can count as harassment. If you fear for your physical safety or mental health, seek help immediately (hotlines, police, or medical professionals as needed). If the situation is intolerable, plan a safe way out. Review your contract for termination clauses. If there’s a required notice period, see if you can negotiate a shorter end or a buyout. Do  simply vanish; abrupt disappearance could breach contract terms and give the company legal ammunition. Instead, consider a formal resignation letter (or request for contract termination) and try to negotiate the terms (perhaps with the aid of a lawyer). Be cautious about making public accusations before you have secured an exit, as this can provoke threats of litigation. If possible, line up next steps first: for example, negotiate with the agency to let you keep your avatar or content rights when you leave, or have a friend or family member ready to take over tasks during your transition.Prioritize Mental Health: Working for an abusive company can be stressful. Make sure to lean on friends, family, or professional counselors for emotional support. Talk with other VTubers who have left agencies or who faced similar struggles; peer support can be invaluable. Remember that no job is worth sacrificing your well-being.Throughout this process, keep in mind your basic labor rights: in many countries, withholding agreed pay, forcing illegal contracts, or subjecting someone to a hostile work environment is against the law. Government labor offices often handle wage complaints even for creative industries. Documenting all issues and seeking legal counsel will strengthen your position if you must fight a very bad contract.Choosing a Safe Agency or Going IndependentPros and Cons of joining a VTuber AgencyTo prevent these problems in the first place, female VTubers should be very careful in selecting representation. Consider these strategies:Research the Agency Thoroughly: Before auditioning or signing, dig into the agency’s reputation. Look for news articles, forum discussions, or social media about the company. Have any former talents spoken out? How did the agency handle past controversies? An agency with transparent policies and few scandals is safer.Interview Current Talent: If possible, talk privately with current or recent VTubers at the agency. Ask about working conditions, management style, and whether they feel supported. Even just observing these streamers and their content can give clues: do they seem happy and well-resourced, or burnt out and secretive?Review the Contract in Detail: Don’t sign sight-unseen. Ask for the full contract up front and read every clause. Check for things like: payment terms (when and how you get paid), required streaming hours, exclusivity, ownership of your VTuber persona, and termination conditions. If terms are unclear, demand clarification or legal review. Remember that “talent exclusive” typically means you perform only for that agency – make sure you understand what that means for side projects or collaborations.Check Policies and Support Systems: A legitimate company usually has written policies on harassment, content guidelines, and dispute resolution. When vetting an agency, ask about these policies. For example, is there a handbook or coordinator you can talk to about any problems? Are there transparent rules for how revenue is split? If the agency hesitates to answer these questions or has no formal policies, it is suspect. (By contrast, the Whitcomb Law guide suggests reviewing a company’s policies carefully to see how to report problems– use this approach for any talent agreement.) Legitimate VTuber agencies often advertise professional services (talent training, marketing support, tech help, merchandise production, etc.). They should present themselves with a proper business presence: a clear website, public contact info, and reasonable expectations. Avoid agencies that seem amateurish (e.g. only a social media page, no official domain, no way to contact easily) or that behave unprofessionally during your application process (e.g. they fail to respond to emails, or they pressure you to join immediately). Remember that being an agency talent is not your only option. Some VTubers succeed independently or through community networks. If you go solo, be prepared to handle everything yourself (streaming setup, brand design, self-promotion). Building an audience organically takes time, so you might start as independent and join an agency later once you have more leverage. Keep backup plans: save money for emergencies, and never rely on an agency as your only source of support. Whenever possible, treat your VTuber persona as your intellectual property. For instance, retain authorship of your character design or use independent servers for streaming. If you work as an independent contractor, consider forming a small company or having a legal agreement that grants you ownership of your content. This way, if a bad agency tries to claim your VTuber identity, you can contest it.Finally, trust your instincts. If an agency’s pitch sounds  good to be true, or if early interactions leave you uneasy (e.g. they pry into personal matters, insist on immediate commitment, or make unreasonable demands during audition), they’re likely unsafe. Female VTubers should be especially careful about agencies that overemphasize “image” or personal sacrifice. Agencies exist to  your career, not to exploit your work or well-being.The Rise of Indie Vtubers amidst Corporate TurmoilEmpowering Yourself and OthersBy educating yourself on what a black-company environment looks like, you can avoid the worst traps. Always read any contract fully and keep records of all interactions. Look for solid references and don’t hesitate to negotiate or say no to clauses you find unfair. Remember that as a performer, you have rights: you can consult a lawyer, report illegal labor practices to authorities, and in many places even form or join a union. Sharing information with other VTubers creates a community defense – if you hear friends discussing a bad agency, take it seriously and spread the word to warn others (within safe legal limits).The VTuber industry is still young and evolving, and female performers should not have to endure abuse to succeed. By spotting warning signs early, documenting any mistreatment, and speaking up for proper contracts and safe workplaces, you protect yourself and pave the way for a healthier community. Trustworthy agencies recognize that supporting their talent’s safety and creativity is the only way to thrive. If every VTuber – especially women, who often carry extra burdens – stands together and demands fair treatment, exploitative “black” practices will become harder to ignore. Your skills and creativity deserve respect, compensation, and a positive work environment. If an agency won’t give that, better to walk away than sacrifice yourself for someone else’s profit.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hololive Night returns to Dodgers Stadium in July - MSN</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMinwFBVV95cUxQVFJNS0F0QnkzOVRleDFRa1dWUVRoRktOQ2dUdUlldkFKWENkU1hVWHROS1JveHBTckxRcC1TT2EycTRJMm9QWVUwX0E0QkJ5bEVzQVRvMjdoaFlrOF9lUXZyZ2N4amI2YUVzOFVjaFJ2VUZpM2hyNnJpWS1XMW5lYkVCZTRKcjJEaElxd0I5cDFCOTFFQTNyLVdSQVVOLWc?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 01:07:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hololive Night returns to Dodgers Stadium in July - mp3sandnpcs.com</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxNVnNGRnVxdjhiNnJXUklZMEFJRWR5OW9rMklyWjB0aEpNbHdwbUJ2SjMxb3A0ZElfdkRFN1lWcTVQZ3FJMjBIWGtKVzdtcURXN2Jhd0UxUGt3RjRoQlluTEk1RE9QX2h3Q205LV9jWk9iT2dlWFVkbzF0ZXhRSUxCWnJIVHY?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 17:17:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hololive English 3rd Concert Will Be at Radio City Music Hall - Siliconera</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikwFBVV95cUxQTElnZ3NibDlMcWZ2dC1hRFNnMVlpb05ta1lPYjBtdHBPbG81aVZRODVGa0ItcmozNnB1UlJXMEtqYUV6dnViWDhST3ZCeUNMR1RLUFluZU00anNjN0dYMWJIdWotOEd4UWhPSGp5M0YzZUNwbGRQWWZab1Y4T05aNGdWMzJoa0NMRkhtSFpIOWZFQTg?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>VTuber Sakura Miko Joins PUBG MOBILE in New Limited-Time Collaboration - Anime Corner</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMimgFBVV95cUxOSUE1T052RkhTRkZITEJ5VkZ1ZEpXNlZ1NUt6dm9xRGdpRXRscTNCdVE4ZktObjRQSmVFZ1VFbXJVYlFDeWk2UVBqWGNpUWZtcVFXSmd0eHNMdTRTNlltQ1AySHFhNkhnYjdxRHpuUjZibVRrZDJIa0JtVG44RldobjFDYUVtZnNYc2R6Z01BUEF2OXlsdzdGYXlB?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 08:45:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>COVER Corporation Announces hololive English 3rd Concert -All for One-! | NEWS | hololive official website - ホロライブ公式サイト</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaEFVX3lxTE1YVER6anRITHBISzdKbXhDX0ZjcVNrMWpTZ2FzM2M0MGJkd3hkZ0FDM3NTRTZIRU83NEd0UlVFTjRiSV9tUGFVUUR0aWNTbUhTa3o2aFZIenJ4UFRnRU96Z2VkN2p6TzQ4?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 02:08:34 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive English -Justice- Announces 3D Showcase Schedule! - ホロライブ公式サイト</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZ0FVX3lxTE1SLUtWbmxiRzNEb0o2MlM1YWJFVl9SYnpEcTd4cFJfbVYtYnBRWlFYZ1pUVHFsVUYySDNpYnUwX2N3UFhuOEVZelBIZE1XSFVYRkJvNE5kRUxxTmhQMFlyb0lJYVo3dVU?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 02:08:33 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive English -Justice- Announces 3D Showcase Schedule! - カバー株式会社</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiX0FVX3lxTE9Ub0lNUnBxTTN5ZGJ0djZNb0JRY2s2VmhnOFBXWFhwbUFxM05TSUdXM09uSTRjV0lzbERHMzNIZ3lXWHNTTXNuY045WDZXb2pUUGpuVThWZ1dsWUhFRENz?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 02:03:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>COVER Corporation Announces hololive English 3rd Concert -All for One-! | COVER Corp. - カバー株式会社</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXkFVX3lxTFBnNDdhZGY1aDJJSm4xR1Z0MFRuSENCLVhJenRUVG9JWjBLb3NaelJWdGtzVFI0T0FRS05RUHkzRWdxcWIxV0poc3VvdmZYTTBSdnJGakhBWHdtN0RHeUE?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 02:03:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive English -Justice- Announces 3D Showcase Schedule!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250616-02-7/</link><author>os_pr</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 01:55:21 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[June 16, 2025, Tokyo, JAPAN – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo, Japan, CEO: Motoaki Tanigo) today announced the hololive English -Justice-’s 3D Showcase Schedule, kicking off with Elizabeth Rose Bloodflame on August 1st, Gigi Murin on August 2nd, Cecilia Immergreen on August 8th, Raora Panthera on August 9th, and a 3D Collaboration on August 16th. (PDT)hololive English -Justice- talents Elizabeth Rose Bloodflame, Gigi Murin, Cecilia Immergreen, and Raora Panthera will star in their individual 3D Showcases, followed by a 3D Collaboration livestream together.The 3D showcases for hololive English -Justice- members and their collaboration stream will feature various contents and performances from each of the talents. The four talents will also be joining their fellow hololive English members in the upcoming hololive English 3rd Concert -All for One- event, announced to be happening later in August. hololive English -Justice- 3D Showcase]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>COVER Corporation Announces hololive English 3rd Concert -All for One-!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250616-01-170/</link><author>os_pr</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 01:54:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[June 16, 2025, Tokyo, JAPAN – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) has announced that hololive English will be holding their third concert event, hololive English 3rd Concert -All for One-, on August 23rd and 24th at the Radio City Music Hall in New York, NY, over the span of two days.The concert will feature the members of hololive English, including members of hololive English -Justice-, who will be debuting in 3D before the performance during the month of August 2025. More details regarding their upcoming 3D debuts can be found here.“Our staff have been working hard to make this concert even more enjoyable than previous ones, so please look forward to it! If you can’t make it there, we hope you will tune in via livestreaming,” commented Motoaki Tanigo, CEO, COVER Corporation.Additional updates will be shared through hololive English’s official social media channels, so be sure to follow them!hololive English 3rd Concert -All for One- Overviewhololive English 3rd Concert -All for One-
Organized by: COVER Corporation / hololive production
#holoAllforOne #hololiveEN
Day 1
Saturday, August 23rd, 2025 (EDT)
Doors open at 4:00 PM / Streaming starts at 5:30 PM / Event starts at 6:00 PM
Sunday, August 24th, 2025 (EDT)
Doors open at 4:00 PM / Streaming starts at 5:30 PM / Event starts at 6:00 PM
Radio City Music Hall
New York, NY
United States
Mori Calliope / Takanashi Kiara / Ninomae Ina’nis / IRyS / Ouro Kronii / Hakos Baelz / Shiori Novella / Koseki Bijou / Nerissa Ravencroft / Fuwawa Abyssgard / Mococo Abyssgard / Elizabeth Rose Bloodflame / Gigi Murin / Cecilia Immergreen / Raora PantheraENUE TICKETS (RADIO CITY MUSIC HALL)FRONT ORCHESTRA/FRONT 1st MEZZANINE: $160 USD
MIDDLE ORCHESTRA/SIDE 1st MEZZANINE: $150 USD
REAR ORCHESTRA/REAR 1st MEZZANINE/FRONT 2nd MEZZANINE: $135 USD
REAR 2nd MEZZANINE/REAR 3rd MEZZANINE: $95 USD1-DAY Streaming Ticket (Aug 23rd EDT)
1-DAY Streaming Ticket (Aug 24th EDT)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>What Could This Be? (hololive EN 3rd Concert Reveal Reaction)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E95zT3Ur5mM</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/E95zT3Ur5mM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 14:29:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[hololive EN Members have something to announce.
What could this be?

Official hololive Stream link: https://www.youtube.com/live/12H8FNbR_OU

✨ Support & Follow hwikky
- X (Twitter): x.com/hwikkyofficial
- Patreon: patreon.com/hwikky
- Ko-fi: ko-fi.com/hwikky
- StreamLabs Tips: streamlabs.com/hwikky/tip

#hololive #ホロライブ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>WuWa Cafe in Japan is SO CUTE!!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/llsk_BJFTWE</link><author>Linsaloty</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/llsk_BJFTWE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 03:00:55 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9lFqIDTZbjTwoiPGoBG_zw">Linsaloty</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[▼Related Video▼
https://youtu.be/ROCVMU1qlc4

English / 中文 / 日本語 subtitles available!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>HYTE Sent Me the New Suisei PC Case — and I need your help to build it</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EjRe5vxpjxY</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/EjRe5vxpjxY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 05:52:48 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[☄️ Hoshimachi Suisei PC Case + Keycap & Desk Pad Bundle Pre-order NOW
👉 Get yours here (please): https://hyte.co/hwikky-hololive

 *This stream is sponsored by HYTE*

✨ Support & Follow hwikky
- X (Twitter): x.com/hwikkyofficial
- Patreon: patreon.com/hwikky
- Ko-fi: ko-fi.com/hwikky
- StreamLabs Tips: streamlabs.com/hwikky/tip

#PR #HYTE
#hoshimachisuisei #星街すいせい
#hololive #ホロライブ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hololive Vtubers Fuwamoco Sing Nekopara After Song - Siliconera</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxNQ2o2TDBmcmIyTi1ubGpWRFl3VjA0OGhQQTBXUXd2NTJXVTRPaFdPN3doeERNV2xtbk1Rd295b0Q1N3JjZXVGZ3NBTjVRbXlTdHZYeEZVUUYxWEFuTEVpMUR3NEhBMFY4eTFMN0NCekI4N3diMEp6YVR4ajhCVEEwbGdYclc?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive English -Advent- are teaming up with SUSHIRO TAIWAN Starting June 16! | COVER Corp. - カバー株式会社</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXkFVX3lxTE5GUl95UlZJNW9iLWpjWWJVamJUSG0zVUVza3YxdDhVSjJ4dUlYV1ZDZVRMbE9sRE1JRmdraFJvV0hMaU9wZ3ByMWpqY0FvVlRLZFE3bGE3N1pUS1V0cnc?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 13:41:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive English 3rd Concert -All for One-</title><link>https://hololive.hololivepro.com/en/events/all-for-one/</link><author>maki</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 09:55:59 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive.hololivepro.com/en">hololive Events</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[hololive English 3rd Concert -All for One- Overview
COVER Corporation / hololive production / hololive EnglishMori Calliope / Takanashi Kiara / Ninomae Ina’nis / IRyS / Ouro Kronii / Hakos Baelz / Shiori Novella / Koseki Bijou / Nerissa Ravencroft / Fuwawa Abyssgard / Mococo Abyssgard / Elizabeth Rose Bloodflame / Gigi Murin / Cecilia Immergreen / Raora Panthera#holoAllforOne #hololiveEN
Saturday, August 23rd, 2025 (EDT)
Doors open at 4:00 PM / Streaming starts at 5:30 PM / Event starts at 6:00 PM
Sunday, August 24th, 2025 (EDT)
Doors open at 4:00 PM / Streaming starts at 5:30 PM / Event starts at 6:00 PMRadio City Music Hall
1260 6th Ave
10020FRONT ORCHESTRA/FRONT 1st MEZZANINE: $160 USD
MIDDLE ORCHESTRA/SIDE 1st MEZZANINE: $150 USD
REAR ORCHESTRA/REAR 1st MEZZANINE/FRONT 2nd MEZZANINE: $135 USD
REAR 2nd MEZZANINE/REAR 3rd MEZZANINE: $95 USD
1-DAY Streaming Ticket (Aug 23rd EDT)
1-DAY Streaming Ticket (Aug 24th EDT)
2-DAY Stream Pass]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive English -Advent- are teaming up with SUSHIRO TAIWAN Starting June 16! | NEWS - ホロライブ公式サイト</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaEFVX3lxTE81YXR0S2pGb3BrSFlGYnJMdWN4TmFZVGNnMzlXY0xiRUJVTVJUTHdUcTU3OURTWTR5VWNMTm5fMmxXOTRIS21NZy1DbWdaUVFoRDFTODRzYWNkTjdVY0wxVlpuNUwzVmU4?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 04:17:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive English -Advent- are teaming up with SUSHIRO TAIWAN Starting June 16!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250613-01-169/</link><author>os_pr</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 04:00:50 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[June 16, 2025, Tokyo, JAPAN – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) has announced that hololive English -Advent- of hololive production, will be collaborating with SUSHIRO TAIWAN. Merchandise and theme store activities will start on June 16th and end on August 10th.hololive English -Advent- are coming to Ximending!
On Friday, June 13th at 8:00 PM Local Time, hololive English -Advent- will appear on the big screen of the Watsons Wuchang store in Ximending, Taipei. Join us for this special event and be part of the excitement!SUSHIRO TAIWAN x hololive English -Advent- stores will launch on Monday, June 16th.
Exclusive merchandise, themed menu items, and specially decorated stores. Don’t miss out on this exciting opportunity to enjoy delicious sushi while collecting must-have collaboration goods!The event includes exclusive gift-with-purchases, add-on purchase promotions, as well as four limited-time collaborative sushi dishes. Every order comes with a special insert card and a surprise badge from a blind bag!SUSHIRO TAIWAN x hololive English -Advent- Collaboration Gift[SUSHIRO TAIWAN x hololive English -Advent- Collaboration Gift With Purchase Part 1]Event Period:
Starting from June 30th, 2025 while supplies last.Event Rules:
Customers spending over NT$700 at any Sushiro store across Taiwan and clicking the Like button on the official Sushiro Facebook will receive one SUSHIRO TAIWAN x hololive English -Advent- A4 file folder.・ SUSHIRO TAIWAN x hololive English -Advent- A4 file folder*6 designs in total, randomly distributed; limited to one per transaction.[SUSHIRO TAIWAN x hololive English -Advent- Collaboration Gift With Purchase Part 2]Event Period:
Starting from July 28th, 2025 while supplies last.Event Rules:
Customers spending over NT$700 at any Sushiro store across Taiwan and clicking the Like button on the official Sushiro Facebook will receive one SUSHIRO TAIWAN x hololive English -Advent- Blind Bag Clear Card.・ SUSHIRO TAIWAN x hololive English -Advent- Blind Bag Clear Card*6 designs in total, randomly distributed; limited to one per transaction.SUSHIRO TAIWAN x hololive English -Advent- Collaboration Add-On[SUSHIRO TAIWAN x hololive English -Advent- Add-On Merchandise Promotions – Part 1]Event Period:
Starting from June 16th, 2025 while supplies last.Event Rules:
Customers spending over NT$600 at any Sushiro store across Taiwan can add-on one SUSHIRO TAIWAN x hololive English -Advent- Blind Pack Chibi Acrylic Standee Blind Bag for just NT$200. Spend NT$1,200 to get two for NT$400, and NT$1,800 to get three for NT$600.・ SUSHIRO TAIWAN x hololive English -Advent- Blind Pack Chibi Acrylic Standee*6 designs in total, randomly distributed; limited to three per transaction.[SUSHIRO TAIWAN x hololive English -Advent- Add-On Merchandise Promotions – Part 2]Event Period:
Starting from July 14th, 2025 while supplies last.Event Rules:
Customers spending over NT$600 at any Sushiro store across Taiwan can add-on one SUSHIRO TAIWAN x hololive English -Advent- Large Desk Mouse Pad for just NT$500. Spend NT$1,200 to get two for NT$1,000, and NT$1,800 to get three for NT$1,500.・ SUSHIRO TAIWAN x hololive English -Advent- Large Desk Mouse Pad*1 design in total; limited to three per transaction.SUSHIRO TAIWAN x hololive English -Advent- Exclusive Menu ItemsCollect Insert Cards and Badges with Every Order!From June 16th, order any of the following collaboration dishes in-store at SUSHIRO TAIWAN and receive both a hololive English -Advent- insert card and a mystery badge:Salmon Tamago Roll – Shiori Novella Insert Card
Meat & Egg Inari Sushi – Nerissa Ravencroft Insert Card
Fried Chicken Gunkan – Koseki Bijou Insert Card
Seared Shrimp Duo – FUWAMOCO (Fuwawa Abyssgard・Mococo Abyssgard) Insert CardEach talent has 2 insert card designs (Character and Fan-themed), randomly given.
There are 12 badge designs, and with just NT$100, you get the dish, insert card, badge, and a chance at a special draw! Grab yours while supplies last!・ SUSHIRO TAIWAN x hololive English -Advent- 12 Mystery Badge BonusDive Into the World of hololive English -Advent- at Three Themed StoresExperience the magic where Virtual meets Reality at three specially-themed SUSHIRO TAIWAN locations:スシロー壽司郎 台北中華路店（TWSUSHIRO Taipei Zhonghua Road）：1F., No. 41, Sec. 1, Zhonghua Rd., Zhongzheng Dist., Taipei Cityスシロー壽司郎 台中黎明市政南店（TWSUSHIRO Taichung Liming）：No. 158, Shizheng S. 1st Rd., Nantun Dist., Taichung Cityスシロー壽司郎 高雄義享天地店（TWSUSHIRO Kaohsiung ESKY LAND）：5F., No. 115, Gushan Dist., Kaohsiung CityGet up close and personal with your favorite talents and immerse yourself in a one-of-a-kind themed dining experience!SUSHIRO TAIWAN x hololive English -Advent- Lucky Draw EventStarting June 23, Bring Home Limited Goods!
Win Exclusive Merchandise in Our Giveaway Event!From June 23 to August 10th, SUSHIRO TAIWAN is hosting a Giveaway Event packed with exciting prizes, rolling out in three phases!
Event Period:
June 23th to July 6th, 2025.
Event Rules:
Like the Sushiro Taiwan Facebook page and share the hololive English -Advent- collaboration menu post to enter the draw. You could win an exclusive Chibi Plush Keychain!*There will be 5 winners in total from Facebook.
Event Period:
Event Rules:
Like the Sushiro Taiwan Facebook page, follow the official Instagram, and tag a friend you’d like to dine with at Sushiro. You could win a 3D Character EZ-Link Card Blind Box!*There will be 18 winners in total: 9 from Facebook and 6 from Instagram.
Event Period:
Event Rules:
Leave a supportive message for hololive English -Advent- in the comments of the designated Instagram event post to enter the draw. You could win a Message Card!*There will be 8 winners in total from Instagram.
These rare official merchandise items are only available through this promotion.
Dine at SUSHIRO TAIWAN and test your luck—don’t miss your chance to bring home these must-have collectibles!Special Collaboration Merchandise – Pre-order Now!The “hololive English -Advent- Chibi Plush Keychains” and “ADVENT 3D iPASS Blind Boxes” are both available for pre-order now on anikoko’s official website: http://anikoko.com If you’re a fan of hololive English -Advent- don’t miss out on the pre-order period from June 16th to August 18th, 2025!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】hololive 6th fes. Color Rise Harmony CANバッジ：25年9月発売予定</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/6th-fes-color-rise-harmony-can-badge/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 03:46:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[︎販売価格：495円（税込）︎サイズ：直径約56×D4mm︎発売時期：25年9月予定下記は過去販売グッズから取り扱いが想定されるECサイトです。確実に予約開始する保証はありませんのでご了承ください。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>I Went to the Wuthering Waves Collab Cafe in Japan [ENG/中文/日本語]</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ROCVMU1qlc4</link><author>Linsaloty</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ROCVMU1qlc4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 03:00:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9lFqIDTZbjTwoiPGoBG_zw">Linsaloty</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Subtitles: English / 中文 / 日本語 Available!

Find me on X: https://twitter.com/linsaloty
BGM: "Get-Ready" by https://www.youtube.com/@KyattoWorks

▼Related Links▼
Sweets Paradise official site: https://www.sweets-paradise.jp/collaboration/wutheringwaves
Check out Wuthering Waves: https://wutheringwaves.kurogames.com/en/

Timestamps

0:00 - Intro
0:27 - Around the cafe
1:44 - Menu
2:46 - Foods I got
4:19 - Goods & novelties
6:44 - Final thoughts

#WutheringWaves #鳴潮]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Bae Gets Slapped Over and Over Again 🖐️</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/_pV-M0pBQ2w</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/_pV-M0pBQ2w?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 19:55:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[✨ Watch what other things I did in Japan: https://youtu.be/HDpaNavLFO8

⭐ Please follow and support!
Twitter - https://twitter.com/hwikkyofficial
Patreon - https://www.patreon.com/hwikky
ko-fi - https://www.ko-fi.com/hwikky

#hololive #ホロライブ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hololive Vtubers Participate in Sleep Fighter II eSports Cup - Siliconera</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikgFBVV95cUxQa1Y0VFdXS0NaTE9HVVVuSk85LVQ4dnBDdXRFZEtoWUhmLUFOTzdtRzE2NFVWYWx0N3c4X1VsNW5JRTVRQ1B6c1ZRZ3RKMHp0MU0yOVQwczdYS0VremkwSEpaMW9UX04wU3lLZU1aRklyMDBySkZqakxTSUh4WmN6N0VWYmhJT0I3VENEZ2FCN0ZwQQ?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>10-Hour hwikky Working (Yapping) + DJMAX Translation Stream</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=92gRJI1oar8</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/92gRJI1oar8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 16:16:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[⭐ Please follow and support! 
⭐ フォローとサポートはこちらへ！
⭐ 팔로우와 후원은 여기로!
Twitter - https://twitter.com/hwikkyofficial
Patreon - https://www.patreon.com/hwikky
ko-fi - https://www.ko-fi.com/hwikky

#rhythmgame #steam
#djmax #djmax_respect_v]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ANYCOLOR FY2025: Revenue Surge and Declining NIJISANJI EN Prospects</title><link>https://vtubersensei.com/2025/06/11/anycolor-fy2025-revenue-surge-and-declining-nijisanji-en-prospects/</link><author>Thomas Toblu</author><category>VTubers</category><enclosure url="https://2.gravatar.com/avatar/21366946cf9a06f2d52c2c9bb01025b3782e7b9ad804152dd14c5b0b2c2c5291?s=96&amp;d=identicon&amp;r=G" length="" type="text/html"/><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 07:48:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vtubersensei.com/">VTuber Sensei</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In the fiscal year ending April 30, 2025 (FY2025.4), ANYCOLOR, Inc. delivered strong overall growth, setting new records in revenue, operating profit, and net profit, driven primarily by its Commerce and Event segments. Total revenue climbed 34.0% year-on-year to ¥42,877 million, operating profit rose 31.7% to ¥16,280 million, and net profit increased 31.9% to ¥11,511 million .However, beneath the headline figures lies a notable weakness: NIJISANJI EN (the English-language VTuber branch) saw a marked revenue decline of approximately 45% year-on-year, and its quarterly revenue has trended downward throughout FY2025.4. This article unpacks the company’s overall performance, dissects each business segment, and explores the factors behind NIJISANJI EN’s ongoing contraction and its implications for future strategy.Link to the financial report.Overall Financial Highlights Driven by explosive growth in Commerce (+65.8% YoY Q4) and robust Event and Promotion performance . Operating margin remained near 38%, testament to tight cost controls even amid rapid expansion. Operating cash flow of ¥11.2 billion, enabling ¥7.5 billion share buybacks and an aggregate dividend payout of ¥4 billion .Livestreaming (12% of FY2025.4 revenue): ¥6,997 million in FY2025.4 versus ¥5,892 million in FY2024.4, up 18.7%. YouTube membership fees, “Super Chat” contributions, and ad revenue. High 38%+ operating margin, reflecting low direct costs. Steady growth expected as viewership and engagement rise with new VTuber debuts and large-scale streaming events .: ¥26,292 million, up 64.8% YoY. Merchandise tied to NIJISANJI 7th Anniversary, unit-based collaborations, plush-toy pop-ups, and in-store initiatives (e.g., the first permanent “Nui Store” in Yokohama) . Manufacturing efficiencies improved direct-cost ratio despite higher volume. Seasonal product launches (e.g., anniversary, seasonal merchandise) lead to Q-to-Q swings in revenue.Events (7% of FY2025.4 revenue): ¥2,829 million, +61.9% YoY. NIJISANJI Fes 2025 at Makuhari Messe saw stronger-than-expected online post-ticket sales and sold-out side events . Growing scale and fan engagement, with sell-out tours planned for the 7th anniversary live tour in FY2026.4.: ¥6,651 million, +25.1% YoY. Corporate tie-ups (e.g., MUFG Bank, Acecook), IP collaborations, and a rising average project size . Continued expansion into diverse industries, leveraging VTuber IP for marketing.Cost Structure & ProfitabilityCost of Sales (53.1% of revenue) (fees to VTubers, platform fees, merchandise/event manufacturing): ¥19,909 million, ~46.4% of revenue . (allocations of SG&A): ¥2,858 million, 6.7% of revenue.Increased due to ¥400 million in bonuses for employees and ¥40 million in depreciation corrections tied to studio relocations .Q4 FY2025.4 operating margin: 38.0%, in line with the full-year margin. Margin stability despite aggressive investment in new studios and VTuber debuts.NIJISANJI EN: A Case of Continuous DeclineWhile J-market VTuber operations soared, the English-language arm (NIJISANJI EN) faced persistent revenue erosion across FY2025.4:Full-Year Revenue CollapseNIJISANJI EN revenue plunged from ¥4,866 million to ¥2,658 million .Quarterly revenue has trended downward after Q2 FY2025.4, with Q4 at just ¥597 million, despite stable or growing headcount .VTuber Count vs. Revenue/VTuber Grew from 127 in Q1 to 135 by Q4 . With rising headcount and falling total revenue, average revenue per VTuber has halved, pressuring profitability and ROI on English-market investments.Market Saturation & Competition: English VTuber space fragmented, with local creators and competing agencies diluting audience attention.Content Localization Gaps: Translated or Japan-centric IP may not fully resonate with global fans. Twitch, Kick, and emerging platforms fragment viewership beyond YouTube.Merchandising Challenges: Logistics, higher shipping costs, and limited physical store presence outside Japan hamper Commerce growth. Develop EN-native characters with storylines and cultural touchpoints tailored to Western audiences.Expand Local Partnerships: Collaborate with Western brands, streamers, and events to boost visibility beyond the Japanese fanbase. Leverage Twitch, Discord, and region-specific platforms to capture non-YouTube viewership. Reassess production and promotion spend to align with the scaled-down revenue base; consider regional hubs to reduce overhead.Growth Investments & Shareholder Returns Tripled distribution studio capacity, boosting average operating hours by 30–100% across 2D/3D/recording studios . 19 new debuts in FY2025.4; Virtual Talent Academy drew 41,000 audition applications . ¥2.1 billion invested in studio build-out; additional spend on platform tooling and 3D/Live2D improvements. ¥7.5 billion in buybacks, ¥4 billion in dividends, with a target payout ratio ≥30% from FY2026.4 onward . More large-scale streaming spectacles to drive membership and ad revenue. Continued merchandise diversification, expanded pop-ups (e.g., “Nui Store”), and global shipping enhancements. NIJISANJI World Tour 2025 – Sendai and 7th Anniversary live tour. Broader IP tie-ups with global brands, aiming to offset NIJISANJI EN headwinds.ANYCOLOR’s FY2025.4 results underscore its dominance in the VTuber ecosystem in Japan, with record Commerce and Event revenues fueling robust profitability. However, the steep decline in NIJISANJI EN highlights the challenge of translating domestic success to international markets. Addressing content localization, platform diversification, and cost optimization will be critical to reversing EN’s downturn. If managed effectively, the company’s strong cash flow and balanced investment/return strategy position it well for further growth in FY2026.4 and beyond.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Latest Hololive Nendoroid Is a Casual Usada Pekora Figure - Siliconera</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxORHkxZXR4Qy02U2lqNHN4VEJoVWVqV01UUmVYMEt4SldCTFNBUmRycF9BMHBZZnN5Z20xVWlDLUlRWjk0UlBianp5YjlsaW5udkljeHBHUnlEUXhfRDlSQ3BCM2J0dUs3ZHBmWXFZYnNJQjN5QVQ1MlpLX29YVVdVa2Y5TDhobklVWFhCaUNB?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>I am in Google Maps Now 🌎</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/Ykm7FNTCcYY</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Ykm7FNTCcYY?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 19:38:34 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[✨ Watch what other things I did in Japan: https://youtu.be/HDpaNavLFO8

⭐ Please follow and support!
Twitter - https://twitter.com/hwikkyofficial
Patreon - https://www.patreon.com/hwikky
ko-fi - https://www.ko-fi.com/hwikky

#googlemaps #geoguessr 
#hololive #ホロライブ

- Music Credit
Music author: Frédéric Chopin
Music title: Nocturnos, Op. 9
License: Public Domain
Download: https://lamusicagratis.com/descargar-musica/nocturnos-op-9]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hololive Night Returns to Dodger Stadium for 2025 Show - The Outerhaven</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxPVzFsam5Fbi0yVmdJaUllS1dUS2RZVmlCeDN1YmFMeHYtWWlmN3JuQnUwdEowUUpmY3BIb2ZZWHZMSHJfX3JzSGFlTHBJTWJkSXJ0NEhWd1VNeG52SC0tcVFlVjhfT0pTamt1OWp6UDRPcXhRWUdhT2g4Wm1nREU4LTZYMm1SVEcwYWhlWlln?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 10:58:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>これってまだ売ってるところある？ #shorts #ガチャガチャ #hololive</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/Bzh9krM938Y</link><author>くーぽん</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Bzh9krM938Y?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 09:30:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC_TI5ueTHqo7AJwapquSZRQ">くーぽん</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>skebご依頼ありがとうございました🐼🎋 #illustration #イラスト #skeb #aftereffects #animation #shorts #commission</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/Qt9Z_OFEEoM</link><author>Riko-m</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Qt9Z_OFEEoM?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 08:00:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCm4-UmTD1TbYd7V0PBpKVbA">Riko-m</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】ねんどろいど 兎田ぺこら 私服衣装 Ver.：25年10月発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/nendroid-pekora-shihuku/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 03:04:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[※期間中は必ずご予約できます。※上記期間をもって販売予定数が決定し、以降は予定数に達し次第受付終了※GOODSMILE以外の通販サイトでは数に限りあり]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>World&apos;s Biggest VTubers Return to Dodger Stadium for Hololive Night 2025 - Comic Book Resources</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiZkFVX3lxTE05VlRxYTVNLW1iVHdUWjdKLVNpa1NIMkltUFNCX2IzRVhBMzdCN09HbXl4UHZiM1lyYWxyWURPV2JadTE3TmZNUW1XUl9Va1ZFS1VZM1Bhb1p4U0Z2NzhPVGZkTU9EUQ?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 9 Jun 2025 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hololive Dodgers Vtubers and Merchandise Revealed - siliconera.com</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMigwFBVV95cUxNaFN2TnJOZUJRd0ZtZE9EdnhNdTAxNEhDaENxVFNBUUdGZmZzQU83ZVpublRoQnF4VUxSUHdadlFIaGg5RlJiTnpyMHNXZW1WU09NQ1FtdFpwSDdBSTdpeG9XVHRQQ0JlOXJuTzN3TWI5Y1NEQ1dsajBDaU1jcmFNcGlRQQ?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 9 Jun 2025 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Dodgers x Hololive VTuber Collab Continues. This Time, With a Charming New Idea - VICE</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMitAFBVV95cUxQM1oyVWoxdDRYcDVoSDdnVDhsR0Y4RmEycm5maUM2VUFGNVNYUDRYSDFfYlNTNzVWVERFbjZuWW94X2IyQ2RNXy02MFhYc2lDVHFNamVSV0h6YURJWE9ZbFZMS0w3eGxObHNWVDNmeTYtRHFUZU4zN21rRmh1TEViVVBuNFBYTHhtV3RfV1RJQWpvM1Y3bU8wRGNIUUN2UWt6Y0JnNlJGdkRfSXVtaTJyQVFyN2Y?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 9 Jun 2025 15:49:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive night Collaboration Event Returns to Dodger Stadium on July 5th, 2025! | COVER Corp. - カバー株式会社</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiXkFVX3lxTE1qU2d1ZXdTNTVwUmQ4RjFpY1lPMHJHZWxXcjNJRVdNa1VNNUNrbDRDbG84RDlfMTBQcWJmTTlCNEg3ME1JaFBzTktMaENmQ0ZZUHlCb29WSm5XU1BfZnc?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 9 Jun 2025 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive night Collaboration Event Returns to Dodger Stadium on July 5th, 2025! | NEWS | hololive official website - ホロライブ公式サイト</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiaEFVX3lxTE4ySUlFNkZFOTl2SHVXYjlNMHNUUjloMGhqMGNadHZpNEZFY2VKaTVGZzBpVWxOUG94b1hfTXZHODZON19JWXZ4ak5ERWNiaVpfalZDVm9kYlFmZkI4VlZBcXJBUFRRYlJx?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 9 Jun 2025 04:07:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive night Collaboration Event Returns to Dodger Stadium on July 5th, 2025!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250609-01-168/</link><author>Horii</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 9 Jun 2025 03:59:17 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[June 9, 2025, Tokyo, JAPAN — COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo, Japan, CEO: Motoaki Tanigo) announced the second collaboration between the Los Angeles Dodgers and hololive production, taking place on Saturday, July 5th, 2025, at 4:15 PM (PDT).After a successful first collaboration with the Los Angeles Dodgers last year, “hololive night” will return to Dodgers Stadium again a second time. This year’s collaboration will feature the first-ever VTuber livestream both to and from Dodger Stadium. To furthermore commemorate this unique evening, co-branded Dodgers x hololive production merchandise will be available to purchase in the gift shops across the stadium.Fans can expect exclusive in-stadium appearances from three hololive English talents, Ninomae Ina’nis, IRyS and Koseki Bijou in real time. The hololive talents will not only cheer for the Dodgers, but also provide their sing-along version of “Take Me Out to the Ball Game” during the seventh-inning stretch of the baseball game. At the end of the game, fans will be invited to join the talents on the field, where they will host special programming such as interactive activities, and a new “WHO’S got the MOVES?!?!” segment where fans can dance and jam together to popular hololive tunes. In addition, this special event will be broadcast live to hololive English’s official YouTube channel, marking the first time ever in history for a VTuber company to stream both to and from Dodger Stadium. Fans can also enjoy a vast series of onsite hololive-themed activities, such as taking pictures with the featured talent’s cutouts, helping themselves to delicious stadium food and drinks with event-only hololive themed packaging, and more to be announced via hololive English’s official social media channels later.The hololive night ticket package includes a ticket to baseball game as well as event-exclusive Dodger x hololive production trading cards (pack of three) that feature the three main cast of this year’s event in Dodgers uniforms. Lucky fans may even draw a special version of the cards that include the talent’s printed autograph!Get hyped with us for this exciting collaboration between the Los Angeles Dodgers and hololive production! We hope to see you at the game.Official Hashtag: #hololiveDodgers・ “Play Ball!” Announcement
・ “Take Me Out to The Ball Game” Sing-a-long
・ Photo Spot with Life-size Cutouts
・ Event-Only Food & Beverage Packaging
・ holodance Crowd Dance Project
・ First-ever VTuber Livestream from the Stadium … and MORE!Collaboration Merchandise(*Products under development)Available from July 5th, 2025 in all shops inside Dodger Stadium. *While supplies last!On July 5th at Dodger Stadium, special beer, soda, and popcorn cups will be offered in hololive collaboration packaging.
Please enjoy these special collaboration designs, which can only be enjoyed during hololive night.hololive night Ticket Informationhololive night Ticket Purchase Bonus: Special Trading Cards (pack of three)For the first time in history, a VTuber livestream will be held at and from Dodger Stadium.
The livestream will be available on YouTube, allowing people from all over the world to experience the thrill of the event in real time. ・ Dance Project “WHO’S got the MOVES?!?!”
The livestream will feature a dance project segment taking place at Dodger Stadium. Songs by hololive production talents will be played at the stadium, and those who want to try their hand at the choreography will dance together! The song selection will be announced later on hololive production’s official social media.The stream will also feature other surprises from hololive production, including past videos, so be sure to tune in!
Despite her looks, Ina’nis is actually a priestess of the Ancient Ones. One day, she picked up a strange book and then started to gain the power of controlling tentacles. To her, tentacles are just a part in her ordinary life; it has never been a big deal for her. However, her girly mind does want to get them dressed up and stay pretty.
After gaining power, she started hearing Ancient Whispers and Revelations. Hence, she began her VTuber activities to deliver random sanity checks on humanity, as an ordinary girl.
A Nephilim who was once the embodiment of hope back in “The Paradise”.
While she has left to set off on an adventure, she continues to deliver hope through her lyrics and songs, with determination in her voice.
She also bears the precarious and unstable dual nature of a half-demon and half-angel; this phenomenon can be observed on rare occasions, in the form of the most unpredictably
yaba—*ahem*, “surprising”, comments from IRyS herself. Bewildering those around her is but another unexpected charm of her duality.
Formed from the crystallization of all forms of human emotion, Koseki Bijou is “The Jewel of Emotions.”
Over years and years, emotions of beauty and filth alike have woven into her under immense pressure, resulting in an unmatched brilliance.
Her ancient, mystic brilliance caused strife between the masses of the greedy, who fought over ownership of her. This led to her being imprisoned in secrecy, far from the reach of humans.
It seems as though when she encounters people, and particularly their good emotions, her radiance shines even brighter.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Getting Hyped for NEW HOLOLIVE X DODGERS that I can&apos;t go to</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zrCFt5qmDf0</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/zrCFt5qmDf0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 8 Jun 2025 22:53:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[hololive Official Stream HERE 👉 https://www.youtube.com/live/UjhwpeT6788

⭐ Please follow and support! 
⭐ フォローとサポートはこちらへ！
⭐ 팔로우와 후원은 여기로!
Twitter - https://twitter.com/hwikkyofficial
Patreon - https://www.patreon.com/hwikky
ko-fi - https://www.ko-fi.com/hwikky
StreamLabs - https://streamlabs.com/hwikky/tip

#hololiveEN #hololiveDodgers
#hololive #ホロライブ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Chaotic VTuber Fans VS Muscular Japanese Girls</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HDpaNavLFO8</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/HDpaNavLFO8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 7 Jun 2025 23:53:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[✨Turn on CC for English subtitles
⭐ Please follow and support!
Twitter - https://twitter.com/hwikkyofficial
Patreon - https://www.patreon.com/hwikky
ko-fi - https://www.ko-fi.com/hwikky

#hololive #ホロライブ

- Music Credit
Music author: Antonio Vivaldi
Musical interpretation: John Harrison (http://www.johnharrisonviolin.com/)
Music title: Spring Mvt 1 Allegro
License: CC BY-SA (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/deed.es)
Download: https://lamusicagratis.com/descargar-musica/primavera-movimiento-alegre

Music author: Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart
Musical interpretation: Advent Chamber Orchestra
Music title: Pequeña serenata nocturna K. 525: I Allegro
License: CC BY-SA (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/deed.es CC BY-SA)
Download: https://lamusicagratis.com/descargar-musica/pequena-serenata-nocturna-allegro

Music author: Frédéric Chopin
Music title: Nocturnos, Op. 9
License: Public Domain
Download: https://lamusicagratis.com/descargar-musica/nocturnos-op-9]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【C106】ホロライブ関連・コミケ情報まとめ（随時更新中）</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/c106/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Sat, 7 Jun 2025 06:18:04 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[2025年8月16日(土)～17日(日)10:30～【企業ブース】ホロライブプロダクション／カバー株式会社「百年梅酒ぺこらver.」「酔うたい焼きさくらみこすぺしゃる」（コミケ期間外でも購入可能）︎その他の購入ルートキャラクターデザイナー（通称ママと呼ばれる方やデザインに携わった方）のスペース一覧です。※頒布物はの扱いです。公式グッズではありません。※空欄は参加の有無がわからない状態です。※ホロライブ関連の頒布がない場合もスペースNo.を記載します。頒布内容はご自身でご確認ください。※記入漏れ・間違いや変更事項がありましたらこちらにご連絡いただけると助かります。コミックマーケットに入場するには「」または「」が必要です。（事前販売・当日販売制）一般入場する人向け（抽選制）開場直後に入場したい人向けチケット（抽選制）開場直後から更衣室を使いたい人向けチケットチケットは名前が印字され、当日本人確認書類が必要です。転売品では入場できませんので販売・購入はしないようにしましょう。※「アーリー入場」・「更衣室先行入場」は会場で受付時にリストバンド型参加証へ交換する必要あり。※親子で入場する場合のみ、チケット・リストバンド1つにつき中学生以下1人同伴可能。ただし中学生以下が一人で参加する場合はリストバンド型参加証が必要。1日目午後／2日目午後︎入場開始：？？？︎価格：？？円※親子で入場する場合のみ、チケット・リストバンド1つにつき中学生以下1人同伴可能。ただし中学生以下が一人で参加する場合はリストバンド型参加証が必要。サークル内容はすべてカタログに集約されます。現在はWebカタログが主流ですが、紙カタログもありますのでお好きなものを選ぶと良いでしょう。（C104では入場はチケット・リストバンド制になり、カタログは必要ありません。）コミックマーケット準備会サイトには、初めて参加される人向けの「初心者ガイド」がございます。コミケはとても楽しい場所ですが、準備不足で臨むと体調不良のリスクやスリに遭う可能性があります。気持ちよく帰宅できるようにぜひ目を通し、安全に楽しみましょう！]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Visiting the SUISEI ARCHIVES Exhibition</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WzdUXXxTHIQ</link><author>Linsaloty</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/WzdUXXxTHIQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 7 Jun 2025 03:00:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9lFqIDTZbjTwoiPGoBG_zw">Linsaloty</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Find me on X: https://twitter.com/linsaloty
BGM: "Cradle" by https://www.youtube.com/@KyattoWorks
Hololive event/collab vlog playlist: https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLZA05Mx0fct5KQkT5pLgMt7m4rtRiKcLl

▼Related Links▼
Official site: https://art.parco.jp/parcomuseum/detail/?id=1689

Timestamps
0:00 - Outside area
1:51 - Train cart room
2:58 - Quote room
9:04 - TV room
10:52 - MV screening room (no pictures allowed)
11:42 - Message room (no pictures allowed)
13:19 - Goods area
14:52 - Goods 
17:54 - Final thoughts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【発売中】HYTE hololive English 2nd Concert -Breaking Dimensions- ステンレスボトル＆マウスパッドセット/フライトタグキーホルダー</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/hyte-en-pad-bottle-tag-keyholder/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 6 Jun 2025 23:02:50 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【25年10月】グッズ予定まとめ</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/goods-oct25/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 6 Jun 2025 21:06:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Another Hololive Dodgers Night Will Take the Field - Siliconera</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMihAFBVV95cUxOeTFTRmtRR3NEZVVaWWVfQ3FfdDhUenAyc3lPMVBHSDBLT2Vidm5kMEc1WmZyV0JSeTY5c0w2Q1NneVNYT1Fra1ZjOElEWnpsVUREWTdTaUZoYzlEVUtnWWlWekExb1hydkhGT282anlRRkt6RnBGcHgzSnRmcE1lSE9MSjU?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 6 Jun 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME オフィシャルホロカマーカーケース Vol.1：25年9月19日発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/hololive-official-card-game-marker-case-vol1/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 6 Jun 2025 09:36:40 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[【関連】hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Here’s a Super Cute Hololive Idle Game. It’s Out on Steam Today. Go Nuts - VICE</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxOR0p0YWpBMzBrZjZhaVBYSFdVWWlmb044OGdMVldaU0VHT1NkZ01mYVc0TE1malBkaFNZenlmWTNNOW9TS21pWGVSbkY2Wl92YjNiWUR5Um5DSHBRbmxNQk5jeVYxYWI0NHpuRktJdHFqTVlQUDZMazNxczkyQzZtVVRjYTVTUnhEUXU2MmFPNHYxWDE4ZDZmY2d5OHEtLWxLdUNn?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 5 Jun 2025 14:58:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Cultivating Your Hardcore VTuber Audience</title><link>https://vtubersensei.com/2025/06/05/cultivating-your-hardcore-vtuber-audience/</link><author>Thomas Toblu</author><category>VTubers</category><enclosure url="https://vtubersensei.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/viewer-spectrum.png" length="" type="text/html"/><pubDate>Thu, 5 Jun 2025 09:38:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vtubersensei.com/">VTuber Sensei</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Being a female VTuber – whether you’re an indie streamer or part of a corp like Hololive English – means tapping into a passionate fandom. Some fans are just casual viewers, but the  (“gachi-koi,” “unicorns,” etc.) make or break a VTuber’s career. These super-devoted fans invest time, money, and emotion in you . Understanding who they are (and who casual viewers are) is the first step.A  is made of viewers who treat your avatar and persona almost like a beloved idol. They form  – one-sided bonds where fans feel close to you even though you only interact through the screen.. Hardcore fans come in flavors:  (heavy “in-love” supporters) and  fans. Gachikoi are the ultimate super-fans: they buy every merch, subscribe, member, and tip just to support you – basically your virtual “boyfriend/girlfriend,” showering you with money and praise Unicorn fans, by contrast, are totally into your . They demand  (Cute Girls Doing Cute Things) – think solo or all-girl collabs – and don’t care about your off-screen life. They’ll quit your channel if you invite male collabs, but otherwise they just love every adorable thing you do. Both types are highly parasocial – they feel like your best friends (or lovers), even though you only know them through the stream .In short, a hardcore audience is . They will subscribe, join paid memberships, buy merch, draw fan art, organize Discord communities, and defend you online. Casual viewers might stop by for a stream or two, but hardcore fans stick around and actively fuel your channel. As VTuber Sensei puts it, “Casual fans might stop by… but hardcore fans are the ones who stick around and invest their time, money, and emotional energy”. Those hardcore fans keep you relevant in a crowded market, and VTubers who nurture them enjoy long-term success even when casual viewership dips.Idol Culture and VTuber FandomVTubers didn’t emerge in a vacuum – they grew from , and that cultural heritage shapes fandom expectations. In J-pop idol culture, fans often expect their idols to stay “pure,” forming one-sided romantic feelings and even demanding a “no-dating” image. VTubing inherited this model in some ways. Like traditional idols, VTubers present carefully crafted personas: colorful avatars and consistent characters that never break character in public. This  approach lets fans project feelings onto you. Parasocial relationships are at the heart of this: viewers feel a unique closeness because they can chat with you live, send donations, and even see your avatar react in real time . This direct interaction takes idol culture’s “Idol Journey” – where fans support an idol’s growth – and turbocharges it with technology.Because of this idol influence, many VTuber fans come with very specific expectations. They want you to be cute, supportive, and accessible, but also mysterious. They crave : they’ll remember your catchphrases, avatar details, inside jokes – and expect the same personality each time. This can lead to pressure: some hardcore fans (especially unicorns) even  that their fave VTuber not interact with male streamers, mirroring old idol rules . On the positive side, idol culture also means fans will go all-out supporting you – buying albums (read: music CDs), concert tickets (3D live events), and tons of merch. The Hololive 3D live concerts are a perfect example: fans passionately cheer and spend just like idol concert-goers.Idol culture’s key legacy is . Fans develop an “Idol Journey” bond: they follow you from debut onward, cheering as you improve (level up your streaming, celebrate milestones, drop music, etc.). The more you lean into that persona-driven, interactive style, the more you encourage that idol-like loyalty. As Vtuber Sensei notes, VTubers and idols share a powerful phenomenon: a “special and strong parasocial relationship” where fans feel personally connected to the avatar. This closeness fuels both the emotional satisfaction of fans and their willingness to  on you (time, money, clout).Why Hardcore Fans Matter: Economics and EmotionHardcore fans are literally the  of a VTuber’s career – financially and emotionally. Economically, the VTuber world thrives on fan spending. VTuber streams only bring in modest ad revenue unless you’re huge, so most income comes from fans: superchats/donations, memberships, sponsorships, merch, and live events Hardcore fans pay for all of it. They’ll subscribe or join multiple tiers of memberships (often 5$–30$/month) because it’s like joining your “fan club” – and 70–80% of that is your profit. They’ll also drop big Super Chats (with YouTube taking 30%), send tips, and buy merchandise even at high prices. In fact, VTubers make up seven of the top ten most Superchatted channels on YouTube, showing how aggressively fans tip their favorites. According to industry data, merchandising is exploding: Cover Corp (Hololive’s parent) saw nearly 80% growth in merch sales in one quarter, thanks to fans buying everything from official card games to limited-edition hoodies. (Those fans are hardcore!)Even beyond money, hardcore fans are an emotional pillar. They form communities – Discord servers, Reddit groups, fan art boards – that keep your brand alive between streams. They constantly share clips, hype up events, and defend you from trolls. Psychologically, VTubers offer fans . Many viewers are socially isolated young men; watching your stream gives them a sense of companionship and a “safe space” to interact. When you thank someone by name, laugh at their jokes, or remember their pet’s name, it fulfills a real human need. Hardcore fans often report feeling happier and less lonely after watching their favorite VTuber. This emotional bond makes them fiercely protective: they’ll rally behind you during tough times and celebrate your victories as their own.Crucially, VTubers who nurture hardcore fans tend to thrive long-term. These fans keep watching and supporting even if algorithms change or casual viewer counts dip. “The loyalty these hardcore fans provide is essential to the long-term success of any VTuber”. In lean times, these die-hards are the ones still clicking “live,” still dropping the odd Super Chat, still repping your merch. They basically pay your bills – or at least bankroll the majority of your income. Vtuber Sensei bluntly advises: cherish those hardcore fans, because “they will carry you through your VTubing journey”.Casual vs Hardcore Viewers: How They Impact Your ChannelNot all viewers are equal. Understanding  vs.  is key to growing and sustaining your community: They catch a stream when they can, maybe watch an interesting game, or tune in during a big event or collaboration. They rarely stick around for the full stream and will drop off early if something better comes up. They might follow your highlights on YouTube or social media, but they don’t tune in regularly. At best, some casual fans will subscribe or join the lowest membership tier only to get a few extra perks, but they  or buy merch. These viewers boost your raw view count, but they’re unlikely to leave comments, tip a lot, or build community. You can’t rely on casuals for steady revenue – in fact, Vtuber Sensei notes you “rarely [make] a living off” a purely casual audience unless you have the backing of a big agency. A special subset of casuals – they  appear for big events (like collabs or announcements) and vanish otherwise. They might contribute a like but never engage deeply or donate. These give spikes in viewership statistics, but don’t build your core fanbase.Hardcore (High-Value) Viewers: These are the Gachikoi and Unicorns we described. They watch every stream they can, often for hours on end. They engage in chat, donate superchats on occasion, and subscribe to memberships (sometimes multiple tiers). They also help set trends – streaming cons told by clips and fan works. In forums and social media, they praise you and defend you if someone trolls you. These fans directly boost important metrics: high concurrent viewer counts, longer average watch times, and active chat logs help with platform algorithms. In short, hardcore fans are far more  per person than casuals.The impact on your channel shows up in two ways: Casuals give you random spikes, but hardcore viewers give you consistency. A stream with mostly hardcore fans might have a smaller peak, but steady viewership and high engagement (like chat activity or superchats throughout). This consistent support makes your channel look healthier to platforms. Over time, hardcore fans also help you trend – they share clips and fan content, bringing in new eyes. Hardcore fans pay for memberships, merch, and donations, whereas casuals rarely do. For example, a VTuber membership (fan club) can cost the equivalent of $5–$30 a month, which adds up when dozens or hundreds of hardcore fans join. Merchandise sales (T-shirts, keychains, plushies with your avatar) only happen when fans are  in you. Casuals might buy a sticker, but hardcore fans will buy  you release. A strong core of super-fans thus keeps the bank account healthy even if occasional viewers trickle.In short: casual viewers grow numbers; hardcore fans grow longevity. A massive but shallow audience can flame out; a modest but dedicated fanbase can sustain a career Hololive English Case StudiesHololive English (HoloEN) provides real-world examples of how cultivating a hardcore audience pays off. The first generation (Gawr Gura, Mori Calliope, Takanashi Kiara, Ninomae Ina’nis, Watson Amelia) each built fiercely loyal followings with distinct brands. Gura leaned into her shark-theme and cheeky personality, focusing on gaming and singing streams. Fans (her self-named “Chumbuds” and “Shrimps”) adopted her catchphrases, fan art, and even fan-made songs. She hit millions of subs in record time, illustrating how a clear niche plus consistent persona attracts both casual viewers  hardcore fans. The  around Gura (shark loli, memes) spread virally on Twitter/Reddit, showing hardcore fan involvement.Mori Calliope (Dead Beats): As Hololive’s musical emcee, Mori focused on original music. Her fans eagerly bought her albums and merch whenever released, treating each song drop like an idol single. Calliope’s emphasis on songwriting and character lore gave fans deep content to engage with. Her dedicated music supporters famously streamed her songs en masse (some hits reached millions of views in hours), exemplifying how tailored content and community hype fuel success.Cover Corp’s financial reports reflect this engagement. For example, Cover reported a ~50% revenue jump in one quarter, attributing much of it to new VTuber debuts (bringing new fanbases) and merch sales up nearly 80% thanks to fan demand. These numbers wouldn’t exist without super-fans snapping up products and promoting the brand.(Note: Hololive is a prime example of corporate strategy. But many independent female VTubers apply the same principles. Nimi Nightmare, for instance with a majority of male fans, leans heavily on GFE interaction to nurture those fans. Independent VTubers often rely even more on core fans since they lack corporate marketing, so they mirror these idol tactics in how they engage and brand themselves.)Actionable Strategies: Attracting and Nurturing Your Core FansBuilding a hardcore audience takes deliberate effort. Here are concrete steps VTubers can use to attract, retain, and grow a loyal fanbase, rooted in community-proven tactics:Craft a Clear Persona & Niche: Know who you are and stick to it. Successful VTubers have a consistent character and theme. Maybe you’re the gentle ASMR storyteller, the over-the-top gamer, or the soothing 2D musician. Pick what makes you unique.  Gawr Gura focused on her shark motif and love of games/music, and that clear branding helped her fans “get” her instantly. Your hardcore fans will rally around whatever distinctive trait or niche you own.Be Authentic and Responsive (Parasocial Bonding): Hardcore fans thrive on feeling close to you. During streams, , react to comments, and remember repeated viewers . Even small gestures make a big difference: a quick shoutout to “Suzuki-san” or remembering a regular viewer’s birthday makes them feel . Fans often say this personal touch is what makes them tune in every time. In short, treat your chat as friends. Be warm, caring, or playful – whatever fits your persona – and keep it consistent. One useful tactic is membership- or subscriber-only streams: e.g. a Q&A for subs or a private Discord hangout. This keeps interactions  for your core fans, deepening the bond without requiring 1-on-1 chats with every fan (setting a healthy boundary). Ironically, maintaining  mystery can make fans appreciate you more. You want to be engaging , but you don’t have to be on-call 24/7. Politely manage messages/DMs: for instance, direct fans to fan servers or use bots to handle routine stuff. This way, you stay safe from harassment but also make your live appearances feel more special. VTuber Sensei reminds creators to “set boundaries—both in what you share and how you respond to over-familiar fans”. Clear rules (e.g. no private social media DMs, no sharing personal info) protect you and remind fans that interactions happen mostly  on stream. This actually preserves the idol aura many fans expect. Keep your visuals and voice . Use the same avatar style and catchphrases on YouTube, Twitter, TikTok, etc. Hardcore fans notice if your persona wavers. If you’re a gentle story-teller, keep that vibe even on Instagram. If you’re the goofy gamer, meme-hard on Twitter too. Consistency helps fans feel at home and spreads your identity: for example, Gura’s shark theme and Mori’s oni horns are instantly recognizable and used in memes and fan art. Also use platform features: update your Twitch panels with your logo colors, have a unique clap-emote on YouTube, etc. All this solidifies your brand and keeps fans engaged.Engage in Fan Communities: Join (or start) Discords, subreddits, Twitter hashtags, etc. Fan communities often flourish on their own, but your presence (even silently reading or occasionally dropping a message) shows you care. Fanart channels, meme channels, translation channels – encourage them. When fans create fan art or fan songs, shout them out or react on stream. For example, when Mori’s fanmade music videos popped up, she publicly thanked the creators, which only fueled more creativity. This user-generated content keeps your fandom active. Also, consider contests or streaming games with fan-donated ideas. This co-creation makes fans feel invested in  success. Offer memberships and merch that hardcore fans love. Create  with genuine perks: special emotes, access to a private Discord voice chat on stream nights, or an exclusive monthly hangout stream . Make the perks feel like “joining your inner circle.” For merch, start with simple things fans can wear or display: T-shirts, hoodies, phone cases, stickers with your avatar or catchphrase. Then consider big-ticket items: plushies, figures, or artwork prints. Limited drops and themed bundles (e.g. “First Anniversary Set” or “Game Tournament Hoodies”) create excitement. Hardcore fans buy merchandise to  and feel closer to you 6768. (Sales of merch are a  stream because once it’s made, fans buy repeatedly.)Exclusive & Behind-the-Scenes Content: Hardcore fans crave anything . This can be easy to implement. Do occasional  where you maybe try a new project or just hang out in low-key chats. Release behind-the-scenes clips on Patreon or YouTube membership only – things like your VTuber rig setup, avatar design process, or blooper reels. The feeling of an “inner circle” is priceless to fans. It says, “You’re more than a number; you’re a supporter who gets special access.” VTuber Sensei recommends, “offer your hardcore fans something special, like exclusive streams… or behind-the-scenes content. Make them feel like part of an inner circle”. In the VTuber world, collabs can boost exposure. But to keep hardcore fans happy, pick your collabs . Many unicorn fans don’t like collabs with male streamers – so if that’s your audience, you might want to prioritize all-female collabs or VTuber-only collabs. (Alternatively, handle it on stream: if you do a mixed-gender collab, reassure fans it’s just professional content and you’re not changing your persona. But expect a hit in revenue.) Likewise, collaborating with fans (fan artists, voice actors) can be a fun way to reward community members. But don’t spread collabs too thin – fans sometimes feel betrayed if you suddenly stream with a random creator unrelated to your theme. Balance broadening your network with keeping your core brand. Hardcore fans often keep calendars to watch  streams. Maintaining a consistent streaming schedule helps them plan around your content. If fans know you’re live every Tuesday/Friday at 7pm, they’ll regularly show up. Sudden cancellations or long hiatuses can lose momentum. Of course, life happens – but give as much notice as possible and perhaps do a shorter backup stream or a quick chat so they aren’t left hanging. Ultimately, none of the above matters if the content doesn’t . Play games or do activities you genuinely enjoy (this keeps energy up), but also pay attention to what hardcore fans love: maybe chatty “Just Chatting” nights for bonding, or themed streams (karaoke nights, ASMR, storytelling, etc.) that fit your character. Analyze which streams get the most engagement or donations and do more of those. Variety is good, but a core identity (idol, artist, gamer, etc.) is key. High production values (good audio, visuals) also signal you care – and in our avatars, even minor improvements (like a cool new wave effect when someone subs) can thrill fans.Handle Shoppers (Gachikoi) and Shippers Carefully: Some hardcore fans (gachikoi) might act overly possessive, shipping you with someone or demanding personal attention. Engage gently: thank them for support, but keep public comments professional. If a fan tries to force personal drama (“Why aren’t you dating so-and-so?”), it’s okay to politely ignore or set boundary. High-conflict drama can upset other fans, so manage it swiftly. However, don’t alienate them completely – they still spend a lot on you. Redirect their passion: for example, start a fan art contest instead of a “ship” rumor.Embrace the Parasocial (But Carefully): Remember, hardcore fans  feeling they have a personal connection. Use parasocial techniques: use warm language like a friend, share “personal” stories through your character (e.g. funny pet anecdotes, favorite foods), even role-play “field trips.” Just keep real personal details vague to maintain healthy boundaries. For example, talk about your day as if you’re with them “late night studying” or “cooking dinner.” This closeness makes fans feel they truly know you, boosting loyalty. But at the same time, don’t pretend too realistically – maintain character cues so fans remember it’s an avatar. It’s a balancing act between fantasy and authenticity.Marketing Savvy (VTuber Marketing): Even as a VTuber, some marketing thinking helps. Use SEO keywords in your video titles (“VTuber audience,” “parasocial relationship,” etc.) if that’s part of your strategy. But more importantly, engage fans on social media like a brand: post clips on TikTok or Twitter, run polls (“What song should I cover next?”), and use fan-friendly hashtags. Announce merch or events with tease images. Some VTubers create countdowns or small puzzles leading up to big streams – these gamify your content. All these strategies are part of VTuber marketing: building hype and staying top-of-mind for your core fans. As one VTuber guide notes, “If your target audience is fans who want more than just casual chats, you’ll use your persona and consistent messaging to attract them”. Show appreciation. Thank your member sub-hype trains on stream, post a “thank you” tweet after hitting a goal, or send a fan a surprise gift (like a hand-signed art print) as a raffle prize. When fans feel recognized, they dig in even deeper. Many VTubers hold loyalty badges (e.g. “You’ve been a member for 6 months!”) or special titles for long-time followers. These small rewards keep hardcore fans around.The Takeaway: Make Hardcore Fans Your FoundationIn the fast-moving VTuber world, chasing every trend or viewer gimmick leads nowhere. The  are your foundation. They pay the bills, build the hype, and emotionally support you. Idol culture taught us that a passionate dedicated fanbase can turn a new face into a superstar. VTubers just have to tap into that by providing consistent, authentic content and fostering real connections.As VTuber Sensei puts it: “Hardcore fans are the backbone of any successful VTuber brand. They buy your merch, show up to streams no matter what, and spread the word about you”. In other words, treat them like VIPs. Offer them exclusives, involve them in your journey, and always stay true to the persona they love. If you do that, you’ll find those casual lurkers may slowly transform into your next super-fans.Remember: a parasocial relationship might only be “one-sided,” but its rewards can be very real. Your hardcore audience isn’t just a number on a dashboard – they’re a community that gives  to your VTuber career. So engage honestly, brand smartly, and always appreciate the Chumbuds, Shrimps, and Nincompees by name. They’ll repay you with loyalty, revenue, and the joy of watching your character thrive.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Thursday, June 5 at 5:29 AM EDT</title><link>https://warosu.org/vt/thread/100898511</link><author></author><category>/vt/ /news/</category><category>VTubers</category><pubDate>Thu, 5 Jun 2025 09:29:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vt.rita.moe/">/vt//news/</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>COVER Corporation Collaborates with We’s Star Ltd. for Mori Calliope themed New Liqueur “MoriZakura もり桜・花鳥風月”</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250605-01-167/</link><author>Horii</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 5 Jun 2025 04:25:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) has announced an upcoming collaboration between VTuber agency hololive production and We’s Star Ltd. (Taichung City, Taiwan) for the new Mori Calliope themed liqueur “MoriZakura もり桜・花鳥風月”. Following the 2023 release of “もり桜・金箔” and the 2024 release of “もり桜・一輪花” the latest creation, “もり桜・花鳥風月” will be available starting June 10th, 2025.This collaboration is a fusion of “森カリオペ” unique charm and the refined aesthetic of “花道物語” “MoriZakura もり桜・花鳥風月” is inspired by the concept of “beautiful natural scenery,” capturing the visual and flavor profile of cherry blossoms. It delivers a unique experience characteristic of sakura liqueur.: For individual purchases, tapestry (one of the four illustration designs) will be shipped randomly.: Scheduled to start around June 2025About 重星戰略, We’s Star LTD.
Aligned with the strategic rhythm of the global market, We’s Star LTD. gathers experts in prototyping, art, and marketing to create outstanding IP works with high standards. The company invests in the international market, collaborating with world-class IPs, companies, brands, and partners to build global strategies.
We’s Star Official X (Twitter)： https://x.com/wesstar_corp 
重星戰略企劃有限公司 / 重星戦略大阪株式会社]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】カードダス holoive vol.6 ：25年9月26日発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/carddas-vol6/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Thu, 5 Jun 2025 03:17:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[︎発売日：25年9月26日︎参加タレント：後日発表]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Transcending Age and Language: hololive SUPER EXPO 2025 Attendee Interviews</title><link>https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en/list/1909</link><author>cover_yamaguchi</author><category>COVER</category><pubDate>Thu, 5 Jun 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en">COVEREdge Magazine</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Kids Influencing Parents: Enjoying hololive as a FamilyA mother of a son in the 2nd grade of junior high school visiting from Hokkaido prints stickers at the Magical Girl holoWitches! booth as she enjoys EXPO with her son and husband as a family. “I’m here with my son because he’s a fan. We try to watch streams together as a family when we have the time,” she told us. Her son also went on to say, “My oshis are Usada Pekora and Murasaki Shion. I became a fan of hololive because of a smartphone game collab they did.”They explained that they have experienced going to a movie theater in Hokkaido in the past for a live viewing, but this time they planned to go to the live concert the following day, which was going to be their first time watching a hololive performance live, so they were really looking forward to it. The son has a lot of merchandise in his room, and told us that hololive for him is one of the “joys in life.”We also spoke to an uncle-niece duo from Saitama who were enjoying some of the EXPO-exclusive food who told us that they “became fans of hololive from watching YouTube Shorts.” The man continued, “I realised that my niece was also a fan when she bought hololive wafers,” and that EXPO 2025 was the first event they had attended. He went on to say that, “hololive is so comforting for me,” and his niece also expressed her love for hololive music and the trading card game (TCG): “My favorite song is Captain Houshou Marine’s “Bishoujyo Muzai♡Pirates. I have also played in a hOCG tournament before.” She continued telling us her dreams: “I want to be a VTuber in the future. I’m designing characters with my school friend,” and when asked about why hololive is so appealing, she responded from the genuine perspective of a schoolchild, “Everyone is so fun and are like friends to me.”We Learned How to Sew! Hobbies and Community Through hololiveWhen asked about their thoughts on EXPO, three friends in their 20s from Chiba and Tokyo who had come in hololive Indonesia 1st Generation cosplay said, “We had been looking forward to our oshis’ food! Moona-chan’s (Moona Hoshinova) Nasi Goreng came with a postcard and it tasted really good!”The girls, who arrived at the event at 6:30 AM on the first train of the day, had started making their costumes a month prior. “We bought all the material separately to suit our costumes.” they told us. “When COVID-19 hit, we couldn’t go outside so we started watching streams, which was something we were still able to enjoy without leaving the house,” they replied when asked about how they got into hololive. They were also addicted to hololive Indonesia content as a part of that. They also talked about overcoming language barriers and communicating across borders: “We couldn’t understand Indonesian at all in the beginning, but gradually started picking it up. Even now, we are looking up things in Indonesian, and interacting with Indonesian fans as well.”“hololive is one of our joys in life; we live for it. We usually wake up watching hololive and fall asleep to it too. It’s always there by our side regardless of whether we’re sad or happy.”They even gained new hobbies: “We’ve even learned how to sew thanks to cosplaying.”Two self-professed otaku friends in their 20s came from Osaka and Tokyo to attend both days of EXPO. They told us that they planned to cosplay on the second day as Houshou Marine in costumes that they made by hand together. “We were originally VTuber fans, and then got into hololive through watching 3rd Generation video shorts. We’ll definitely be going to our oshi’s live concerts now!” said the hololive fans of four years.“The Magical Girl holoWitches! booth was really good. We were really moved by the costumes there,” they responded about EXPO 2025.Their passion for hololive was evident as they spoke: “We watch our oshis every day: streams on our commutes and when we’re getting ready. We put on archived content, and it always feels like they’re with us. hololive is our lifeline—we couldn’t survive without it.”Another fan of 3-4 years in their 40s hailing from Tokyo was with plushies of his oshi Tsunomaki Watame he had brought, enjoying an EXPO-exclusive drink. He told us that he had arrived at 7 in the morning and “was glad to see the mascot parade, something that [he doesn’t] normally get to see.”He spoke about the appeal of hololive: “It is what comforts me on a daily basis.”“When I recommend hololive to people, I tell them that there are so many different kinds of VTubers, so they can definitely find one that suits them.”He was at EXPO with two of his friends who gained another common interest thanks to hololive: “They are longtime friends of mine who became fans of hololive because of my recommendations.”hololive Transcending Borders: From Online Encounters to Real-Life FriendshipsA fan of 5 years in his 30s who had traveled to Japan all the way from the Netherlands spoke about his love of cosplaying: “I really wanted to cosplay today, but I couldn’t get a ticket.”“I have been cosplaying for over half of my life,” he asserted, stating that he had started cosplaying when he was 17. “I was really looking forward to the hololive English booth (ENigmatic Recollection). I’m so glad I was able to see the booth where all the members are together for the first time.”A HOLOSTARS fan in her 20s who had traveled from Kanagawa talked to us about her oshis Rikka, Hanasaki Miyabi and Minase Rio and how she came across hololive production: “I started getting into them through watching their live content on TikTok about 2-3 years ago.”“I was originally a fan of other streamers, but HOLOSTARS was the reason I became interested in VTubers,” she said, also mentioning that she has a channel membership on YouTube.Four Oozora Subaru fans who met on social media (one of whom was in Japan from South Korea) told us that “[they] occasionally meet offline!”The one from South Korea also went on to say, “I first came across hololive at the start of 2022. Even in South Korea, there are events and collab cafes, and there’s even a live viewing for today’s event (EXPO).”They also told us from each of their perspectives what hololive means to the four of them: “It’s a place that gives us energy.”“I get energized from Subaru-chan’s (Oozora Subaru) streams.”“It’s entertainment that makes you feel positive.”“I feel really close with them because we see not only how they are on regular streams, but who they are in daily life too.”“There’s so much content in the archive that you can never get sick of it.”EXPO: The Culmination of Diverse Connections Made Through hololiveWe heard from people from all walks of life through these interviews over the two days at hololive SUPER EXPO 2025 Supported By BANDAI/hololive 6th fes. Color Rise Harmony at Makuhari Messe, showcasing how hololive can be enjoyed by anyone regardless of age, gender or nationality, and connects people through fan interaction. Whether you are a school student, adult, family, friends with a common interest or by yourself, hololive is a place for everyone to enjoy in their own way.We also heard how much hololive production means to people, with answers like “It’s part of my daily life,” “I live for hololive,” and “hololive comforts me,” giving us a little insight into how hololive is more than just a mere hobby for some.  Stay tuned here on COVERedge for more on the constant evolution of hololive production, bringing fans together regardless of talent and fan relationships. (Please also check out interviews with staff and booth representatives about the booths that featured at EXPO 2025 in Parts 1 and 2.)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Late Night Streaming testing</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kfYOiB6IibQ</link><author>Gordon Yeung</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/kfYOiB6IibQ?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 3 Jun 2025 07:23:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCmZiZpLlYgXI8mrWC-grdPg">Gordon Yeung</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[▽There's more info underneath▽
▶IG:gordonYeung314
▶Gordon FB:https://www.facebook.com/gordonnnyeung]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Late Night Streaming testing</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8k5DXevnbT0</link><author>Gordon Yeung</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/8k5DXevnbT0?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 2 Jun 2025 19:16:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCmZiZpLlYgXI8mrWC-grdPg">Gordon Yeung</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[▽There's more info underneath▽
▶IG:gordonYeung314
▶Gordon FB:https://www.facebook.com/gordonnnyeung]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>深宵直播測試</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AcE5IFYNhuw</link><author>Gordon Yeung</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/AcE5IFYNhuw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 2 Jun 2025 17:37:21 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCmZiZpLlYgXI8mrWC-grdPg">Gordon Yeung</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Sunday, June 1 at 9:55 PM EDT</title><link>https://warosu.org/vt/thread/100474403#p100794527</link><author></author><category>/vt/ /news/</category><category>VTubers</category><pubDate>Mon, 2 Jun 2025 01:55:01 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vt.rita.moe/">/vt//news/</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>COME IN AND SAY HI. I am working (actually yapping)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9DI-JFEWtVA</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/9DI-JFEWtVA?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 15:46:54 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[⭐ Please follow and support! 
⭐ フォローとサポートはこちらへ！
⭐ 팔로우와 후원은 여기로!
Twitter - https://twitter.com/hwikkyofficial
Patreon - https://www.patreon.com/hwikky
ko-fi - https://www.ko-fi.com/hwikky
StreamLabs - https://streamlabs.com/hwikky/tip]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Rat Dance Hue Shift🐭 #shorts #ratdance #anime</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/qzEPecKrwZc</link><author>Riko-m</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/qzEPecKrwZc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 01:01:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCm4-UmTD1TbYd7V0PBpKVbA">Riko-m</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Inside the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME: COVER and Bushiroad Share Untold Stories and their Vision for the Future</title><link>https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en/list/1889</link><author>cover_yamaguchi</author><category>COVER</category><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en">COVEREdge Magazine</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[I started by buying various card games in Akihabara and studying them. At the time, I was also acting as manager of the commercialization team, so from launch to release, it felt like I was just constantly running full steam ahead. Honestly, those days were such a whirlwind that I barely even remember them…(lol)I started working with Kawatsu in March 2024 and I clearly remember being asked, “How many people are working with you?” and answering, “It’s just me.”  Every time I explained the situation, so many people told me, “That’s insane!” (lol). Nevertheless, it was thanks to the support of my colleagues in other departments and collaborators such as Kawatsu that we were able to reach the point where the game was ready for release. I also felt I could draw on my own personal childhood memories of playing card games, which helped me a lot through this process.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>First Store in West Japan! hololive production official shop in Osaka Umeda Opening Soon!</title><link>https://hololive.hololivepro.com/en/events/shopumeda/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 02:45:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive.hololivepro.com/en">hololive Events</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Scheduled to Open on June 27th, 2025!hololive production official shop in Osaka Umeda will be the first store to open in western Japan, and the second store nationwide, and will feature new items using exclusive visuals drawn by illustrators 三九呂 and むぎた.The first part of this series will feature five talents, with future releases scheduled.
Apart from a selection of official hololive production merchandise, exclusive content will also be available.The hololive production official shop in Osaka Umeda offers an abundance of attractive content, so don’t miss this chance to visit us.Shop Name： hololive production official shop in Osaka Umeda
Location：Osaka 1-1-3 Shibata, Kita-ku, Osaka 530-0012　HANKYU SANBAN GAI Kita-kan B1F
Dates： Friday, June 27th, 2025 to Spring 2026
Operating hours： 10AM – 9PM* Same as the operating hours for HANKYU SANBAN GAI.As we expect a surge of visitors , we will limit entries using LivePocket-Ticket-.
Please register from the application pages below.Dates of restricted entriesAdditionally, we will be restricting entry and handing out numbered tickets should there be a high number of customers aside from the aforementioned dates.Store-original merchandise will be available in advance.
* There may be purchase limitations due to limited stock.
* We will try to ensure there are sufficient stocks, but please understand that they may still sell out.
* We cannot answer inventory-related inquiries (available quantities, restock dates, etc.).
* We will be selling merchandise from this store post this event.
* Images are for illustrative purposes only. Actual products may differ.Featured Talents for Part One
Shirakami Fubuki / Nakiri Ayame / Houshou Marine / Shishiro Botan / Kikirara Vivi
・ New arrivals of store-original merchandise
・ A selection of merchandise from the hololive production OFFICIAL SHOP *
・ A selection of licensed merchandise from hololive production* The lineup will not include talent anniversary or made-to-order merchandise. Once sold out, some merchandise may no longer be available.Novelties will differ depending on the period and amount purchased.
We will gift novelties on a first-come, first-served basis when you purchase over a certain amount in-store.* Randomized novelties will not be able to be chosen and will only be available while stocks last.Novelty giveaway period： From Sunday, June 27th, 2025, while stocks last.
・ Every 3,300 yen (tax incl.) spent in a single purchase will entitle customers to one hololive production official shop in Osaka Umeda original Vol.1 Uchiwa (handheld fan) (5 Designs/Randomized)
・ Single purchases over 11,000 yen (tax incl.) will entitle customers to one hololive production official shop in Osaka Umeda original bag (1 type)In addition, any customers who show staff that they have registered for an account on the holoplus app will receive an additional novelty.
Download holoplus* All novelties are available while stocks last.We will continue to provide more exciting content for everyone who visits us at the HANKYU SANBAN GAI, so be sure to stay updated for the latest news.① Life-sized illustrated panels of the talents as shop staff displayed outside the store
For a limited time, life-sized panels of talents as shop staff will be displayed in HANKYU SANBAN GAI.
When： Friday, June 27th – Friday, July 25th, 2025
(Illustrated by 三九呂)② Mini-character illustration of talents as shop staff displayed by the escalator in front of the store
Mini-character illustration of talents as a shop staff will appear in the open area inside HANKYU SANBAN GAI.③ In-store special announcements
Apart from original in-store announcements by the five featured talents, you will also get to hear announcements from hololive production’s official anchorwoman, Harusaki Nodoka.④ A message from the talents
The store will feature autographs and messages written by the featured talents.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Special Talk from Former Weekly Shonen Jump Editor-in-Chief, Mr. Kazuhiko Torishima</title><link>https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en/list/1891</link><author>平松梨沙</author><category>COVER</category><pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en">COVEREdge Magazine</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[On May 17, 2025, we held a special in-house talk featuring Mr. Kazuhiko Torishima, former Editor-in-Chief of  at SHUEISHA Inc., who played a key role in bringing numerous hit titles such as  and  to life. Drawing from his experience working alongside some of the industry’s top creators, Mr. Kazuhiko Toshima shared his valuable perspective on creative collaboration and what it takes to shape true compelling entertainment.During the session, Mr. Kazuhiko Torishima shared the story behind the launch of Weekly Shonen Jump and spoke in detail about the three core principles that have shaped the magazine’s enduring success: giving opportunities to new talent, fostering a collaborative relationship between editors and creators, and making sure that reader feedback is valued most. The two-hour session – including a Q&A portion – covered a wide range of topics from behind-the-scenes insights into the manga creation process using actual panel and page layouts, to a thought-provoking look at how social media and smartphone culture has influenced modern manga. The session received enthusiastic feedback from employees, with many commenting that they were able to reflect on the talk through the lens of their own work and reaffirmed the importance of communication. It proved a valuable opportunity for all participants to broaden their perspective and deepen their understanding of what it means to create and collaborate within the entertainment industry.It was a meaningful and enriching opportunity for employees working toward our mission “Together, Let’s Create Culture Loved by All” and deeply connected to the values we strive to uphold in our day-to-day work.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【発売中】猫又おかゆ スポーツ報知 ぴあアリーナ特別版 2025年5月28日付</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/sport-houchi-okayu250528/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 22:01:41 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[︎発売：25年5月28日︎通販：販売開始時間不明(なくなり次第終了)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【発売中】猫又おかゆ スポーツ報知 東京最終版 2025年5月29日付</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/sport-houchi-okayu250529/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 21:59:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[︎発売：25年5月29日︎通販：販売開始時間不明(なくなり次第終了)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>HyperX x IRyS Collaboration Keycap and Headset Accessory are Now Available</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250528-01-166/</link><author>Horii</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 12:48:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[COVER Corporation has announced a collaboration between HyperX and hololive production, introducing an exclusive keycap and headset accessory featuring IRyS of hololive English -Promise-.The keycaps and headset accessory will be available on the HyperX official website starting May 27th at 12 PM PST.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ダイナー風みこち🌸#さくらみこ #sakuramiko #hololive #illustration #shorts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/OUUKuMQVpBw</link><author>Riko-m</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/OUUKuMQVpBw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 08:00:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCm4-UmTD1TbYd7V0PBpKVbA">Riko-m</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive production 2nd World Tour Concert “hololive STAGE World Tour’25 -Synchronize!-” Key Visual, New Cities, New Guests, and Merchandise Announcement</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250527-01-165/</link><author>Horii</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 04:00:49 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Motoaki Tanigo) is pleased to announce the key visual, new cities, special guests, and merchandise for the second world tour concert, “hololive STAGE World Tour’25 -Synchronize!”.The key visual for “hololive STAGE World Tour’25 -Synchronize!” has now been unveiled. It features Momosuzu Nene, Kureiji Ollie, Mori Calliope, IRyS, and Nerissa Ravencroft dressed in stylish costumes.
Additional information on special guests has also been released.
First, Fuwawa Abyssgard and Mococo Abyssgard of hololive English -Advent- will be special guests at the Vancouver show. Akai Haato and Natsuiro Matsuri of the hololive 1st generation will appear at the New York show. Stay tuned for more information about guests at upcoming shows.Two cities that have been newly added to the world tour have also been revealed. The first is Seoul. This will be the first time hololive production performs a 3D concert there. The second is Taipei. Taipei was on the world tour last year and will be again this year.
More information about the Seoul and Taipei concert dates and venues will be announced at a later date.An original theme song for the world tour is currently in the works. It will be sung by Momosuzu Nene, Kureiji Ollie, Mori Calliope, IRyS, and Nerissa Ravencroft. Please look forward to its release!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Makeship and hololive production Announce Adorable New Plushie Collection Featuring hololive English -Advent-!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20250526-01-164/</link><author>Horii</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 01:56:04 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) announced today the release of the MAKESHIP x hololive English -Advent- exclusive plush collection, featuring members of hololive English -Advent-.The collection of plushies featuring the five captivating members of hololive English -Advent-: Nerissa Ravencroft, Shiori Novella, Koseki Bijou, and the twin hounds Fuwawa Abyssgard and Mococo Abyssgard.Following the overwhelming support for previous hololive production and Makeship collaborations, this new project will allow fans worldwide to bring home their very own cuddly companions inspired by the unique personalities and iconic designs of hololive English -Advent- members. Each plushie has been crafted to capture the lovely relationships between each member and their mascots.The plushie campaign will run for a limited time. Visit the Makeship website during the campaign to pre-order your favorite hololive English -Advent- members plushies and help bring this exciting project to life.
Get ready, adventurers!MAKESHIP x hololive English -Promise- Plushie Collection
Makeship is a platform that empowers creators and communities to bring their unique ideas to life through limited-edition physical products, primarily plushies. By utilizing a crowdfunding model, Makeship ensures that only successfully funded projects are produced, fostering a direct connection between creators and their fans.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Rise of Indie VTubers Amid Corporate Agency Turmoil</title><link>https://vtubersensei.com/2025/05/25/the-rise-of-indie-vtubers-amid-corporate-agency-turmoil/</link><author>Thomas Toblu</author><category>VTubers</category><enclosure url="https://vtubersensei.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/vtuber-agencies-proportions-by-viewership.png?w=1000" length="" type="text/html"/><pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 18:53:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vtubersensei.com/">VTuber Sensei</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The VTubing phenomenon has exploded from a niche Asian curiosity into a global streaming powerhouse over the past decade. In 2016, the avatar Kizuna AI became a viral sensation, hitting 2 million YouTube subscribers in just ten months (konvoy.vc). Within a year (mid-2018), the active VTuber population doubled from about 2,000 to 4,000(konvoy.vc). By January 2020 there were over  VTubers worldwide (konvoy.vc), and VTuber viewership swelled rapidly during the 2020 pandemic boom. Indeed, at one point VTubers accounted for 38% of YouTube’s top 300 highest-earning channels (114 of 300) with roughly  total revenue (konvoy.vc).As demand surged, professional agencies sprang up. Japan’s Cover Corp launched  in 2017, quickly building a stable of pro talent. Virtually at the same time, ANYCOLOR (then Ichikara) debuted , and Western-oriented agencies like  appeared by 2020. By 2023 the two largest agencies alone boasted staggering followings –  subscribers for NIJISANJI and  for Hololive (investing.com). And indie creators have thrived too. The VTuber market as a whole was already worth billions: one estimate put the global VTuber industry at , projected to (zionmarketresearch.com). (Another analysis cites $3.3B in 2023 and predicts ~$45.8B by 2032 ().)The past few years saw record growth. StreamsCharts data for 2024 Q1–Q3 (below) shows VTuber watch-hours climbing from ~430 million in Q1 to ~440M in Q2 – roughly a (streamscharts.com). In Q3, however, hours dipped slightly to ~433M (a 1.5% quarterly drop (streamscharts.com), the first decline after six straight growth-quarters.The chart above illustrates the trend: after years of explosive growth, VTuber viewership is now stabilizing. Even so, totals remain far higher than pre-pandemic; and VTubers continue to occupy a growing share of overall streaming. According to Stream Hatchet, VTubers now command 3.7% of live-stream viewership (up 10× from five years earlier) (). This mainstreaming means big brand partnerships and mainstream media exposure for VTubers – but it also invites scrutiny of the corporate models behind them.Corporate vs. Independent VTubing: Pros and ConsIn the VTuber world today there are : corporate (or “agency”) talents vs. independent (or “indie”) creators. Each has distinct advantages and drawbacks:Agency (Corporate) VTuber: Signing with a talent agency like Hololive, NIJISANJI, or VShojo often grants an enormous head start. Agencies provide high-end resources “to elevate your content”: pro avatar design, technical support, and marketing  (vtubersensei.com). Talents get custom 2D/3D models crafted by experienced artists, polished overlays, editors, and even direction for content (vtubersensei.com). Importantly, agencies also bring instant exposure: a slot in a top agency means your debut is introduced to an existing fanbase, and you’ll frequently collab with star classmates. Agencies handle promotion, sponsorships, and cross-channel events that an independent could never engineer alone (vtubersensei.com). In short, joining a well-known agency can give a huge jump in audience and production quality with far less effort on the part of the VTuber (vtubersensei.com).: All that support comes at a price. VTubers in agencies typically sign long-term, exclusive contracts with many restrictions. They often lose creative control: certain games or topics might be off-limits, and even collaborations or sponsorships may need agency approval (vtubersensei.com). Agencies may enforce strict quotas (e.g. required streaming hours), and because the persona/avatar is usually , leaving the company often means abandoning that identity (vtubersensei.com). In practice, this means if a talent parts ways, they typically cannot take their character or channel with them – the IP stays with the company. Additionally, agencies take a share of revenue (sometimes 30–50% or more) (vtubersensei.com), meaning VTubers earn  than they would independently. Some also report that agencies’ bureaucratic structures and red tape can slow things down – for example, one journalist noted complaints of  and “limited creative freedom” among Hololive staff (virtualsweet.jp).: Going solo gives a VTuber full autonomy. An indie can stream any content they want, manage their own schedule, and keep essentially  (minus platform fees) (vtubersensei.com). There are no corporate bosses or contracts limiting what you say or do, and you own all the IP for your character. Indies can pivot quickly or try unconventional ideas without waiting for approval. In many cases, this means greater creative satisfaction and control. For example, ex-agency talents have turned loose outside the corporate structure and invented new personas or content approaches that wouldn’t have been allowed on a corporate stream (hololivetoday.com)(jaxon.gg). In theory, indies have “a higher degree of freedom” (as one analysis notes) and can connect more personally with fans as individual creators (news.viverse.com).: Of course, independents must handle . They must finance their own avatar and studio costs, learn editing and marketing, and build audiences from scratch (or rely on an existing fanbase). Without an agency team, technical glitches or business negotiations can fall entirely on the VTuber’s shoulders. Indies also often lack consistent production: many solo creators upload less frequently and may experience burnout when handling all roles. A common metaphor is that agency VTubers are like “office workers” with support staff, whereas indies are solo entrepreneurs or artists (news.viverse.com). Crucially, breaking through as a completely new indie creator is very difficult. The vast majority of indie VTubers remain small or part-time; only a very few achieve large-scale success. This “winner-take-all” effect means that while headline success stories (often ex-agency talents) grab the limelight,  indies build modest channels that never rival agency peers. As one analysis points out, the roughly one-third market share held by indies is “likely accounted [for] by a select group of successful indies,” implying that the average independent creator has a tiny slice (hololivetoday.com).In summary, agencies offer a  with expensive production and built-in fans (vtubersensei.com), but at the cost of autonomy and revenue share(vtubersensei.com). Independent VTubers sacrifice that safety net for creative freedom and profit potential, but they face a steep climb to grow an audience on their own. The choice depends on a talent’s priorities: many aspiring VTubers join agencies for support, while others prize the indie path to keep their character and vision fully theirs (vtubersensei.com).Major Graduations and ExitsIn recent years, several high-profile VTubers have “graduated” or left their agencies, dramatically illustrating the tension between corporate control and personal freedom. These exits have drawn enormous fan attention and reshaped the scene. Below are some key examples:: In late 2024, Hololive English’s star  announced she would graduate (leave Hololive) effective January 3, 2025. Fauna, one of the most-watched English talents, surprisingly cited “differences in opinions with management” as her reason (vchavcha.com). Hololive’s official statement even explicitly used the term “Graduation” (implying a permanent departure in contrast to “Affiliation”). Many saw this as hinting at creative disagreements or stress. Within hours of her final Hololive stream, eagle-eyed fans noticed Fauna’s original persona “LemonLeaf” returning to activity: her YouTube channel rebranded as  the day after her graduation (jaxon.gg) (virtualyoutuber.fandom.com). Nimi Nightmare debuted Jan 17, 2025 – and blew past 300K subs almost immediately. In fact, her growth was meteoric: by Jan 18 she had 400K subs and by Jan 23 reached (virtualyoutuber.fandom.com). By late April 2025 she hit  subscribers, with debut streams peaking over 90,000 viewers (virtualyoutuber.fandom.com). This spectacular surge shows Fauna’s fans loyally following her to indie status. (Notably, Fauna also announced she’d make all her past membership content free after graduation (vchavcha.com) – a sign she wanted a fresh start.)Selen Tatsuki (NIJISANJI EN): Selen’s exit from ANYCOLOR’s English branch in January 2024 caused an uproar. The sudden  of Selen’s contract (not a normal graduation) was officially attributed to “behavior unbecoming” (later rumors blamed social media incidents), but it happened just as she took a medical break, which sparked outrage. Fans and VTubers reacted with , accusing Nijisanji of mistreating talent (polygon.com). ANYCOLOR’s CEO later apologized for communication failures, but the damage to trust was palpable. Importantly, Selen immediately revived as indie persona: . In Feb 2024 she relaunched as Dokibird, and the fan response was staggering. On Feb 5, 2024, her YouTube subs jumped from ~9K to over , and one day later she hit  (virtualyoutuber.fandom.com). Her debut stream on Feb 7 peaked at ~127,000 concurrent viewers. By Feb 13 she reached  subs – adding nearly  followers in 8 days (virtualyoutuber.fandom.com). By mid-March she was over 600K subs and hosting huge charity streams. In short, Selen/Dokibird’s meteoric indie success – and the vitriol aimed at ANYCOLOR over her firing – became a turning point. Many in the community lamented that a beloved VTuber was driven out by rigid corporate rules, yet immediately flourished independently (polygon.com (virtualyoutuber.fandom.com).Pomu Rainpuff (NIJISANJI EN): Pomu was an original member of Nijisanji EN’s first generation . By August 2023 she had amassed over  on YouTube (jaxon.gg) and seemed destined for big stardom. Then, in January 2024, Pomu announced a sudden graduation from Nijisanji EN citing burnout and . The news shocked fans; Pomu herself lamented that she had to turn down exciting projects due to agency constraints (though she said little publicly). Nearly three months later, in April 2024, Pomu re-emerged – but this time as her original indie avatar “Mint Fantôme (Maid Mint)”. As an indie, she immediately drew her old fans: within weeks she reached around (jaxon.gg), and by April 2025 she had about  subscribers (her numbers are still growing) (businessinsider.com). While Maid Mint’s count is smaller than Pomu’s peak, it shows a devoted following. Pomu/Maid Mint’s story is unusual in that she went from indie → corporate → indie, and yet maintained a sizable audience. Many fans cheered her return as Maid Mint, seeing it as a “second chance” at streaming on her own terms.: Gawr Gura, one of Hololive’s celebrated  talents and the single-most-subscribed VTuber in the world ((over 4.5 million subs (essential-japan.com)), stunned the community in April 2025 by announcing her graduation effective May 1. The reason given was familiar: “differences with management and the direction of the company”(essential-japan.com). The news was met with heartbreak and speculation. In a twist echoing Fauna, just days after her last Hololive stream, fans discovered Gura’s new independent channel. Now rebranded as , her debut video quickly confirmed the speculation – and her audience reacted at warp speed. Within 24 hours, Sameko Saba’s YouTube and Twitter followed count exploded to jaxon.gg) (remember, that’s from near-zero overnight!). This makes Gura the latest example of a top VTuber successfully migrating to indie status without losing fan support. Cover Corp has emphasized that it still owns the “Gawr Gura” character, so the new persona has a different name and look, but the loyal fanbase nearly instantly crossed over (jaxon.gg).Each of these graduations – Fauna, Selen, Pomu, Gura – sent shockwaves through the VTuber fandom. Fan reaction was overwhelmingly supportive of the talent. Social media exploded with messages like “I’m loyal to my oshi (favorite), not the company (hololivetoday.com). Viewers overwhelmingly took the side of the VTuber, trusting her narrative over the agency’s. Crowdfunding efforts like charity streams by Dokibird (raising $250K+) showed fans rallying to help the talent succeed. The common sentiment was that the content and personality of the individual, not the corporate label, were the real draw.In many cases, ex-corporate VTubers have indeed thrived independently, backed by these fans. Both Dokibird and Nimi Nightmare hit half a million subscribers within days/weeks of debuting. Maid Mint found over 300K as an indie. Gura’s Sameko is at ~200K after just a day. These stars have already shown they can monetize directly: for example, Dokibird’s February 9 “Merch Launch” stream generated nearly  in YouTube superchats and tips (virtualyoutuber.fandom.com) – more than she ever got as an agency talent in the same time span. Fauna’s merchandise sold out instantly. In short, the indie paths of these former corpo talents have been validated by the market: their audiences followed them and even expanded.At the same time, it remains an open question whether completely new VTubers (with no corporate pedigree) can break out at a similar level. So far, the most successful independents are often veterans or have compelling niches. Even Filian, one of the biggest “Kojinzei” VTubers mentioned by Forbes, ironically joined a small agency in 2023, blurring the lines (news.viverse.com). Generally, analysts note that the indie viewership pie is dominated by the same “superstar” phenomenon: a few big names get the lion’s share of views (hololivetoday.com). Fresh faces will need something truly unique to garner mass appeal without an agency’s marketing engine. It’s still early, but the expectation in the community is that fan loyalty will follow personalities – so a crafty and charismatic new indie might still grow large, just as Dokibird did. But they will be entering a more competitive and saturated market.Industry Statistics: Viewership, Graduation Rates, and RevenueTo understand these trends, it helps to look at the data. Third-party trackers and market analysts have documented how VTuber viewership and business metrics are evolving: StreamsCharts reports that over the past few quarters, VTuber audience growth has plateaued. After reaching record watch-hours in late 2023 and early 2024, the numbers leveled off. VTubers still command hundreds of millions of hours watched per quarter; Q3 2024 had about  watched (streamscharts.com) (vs. 440M in Q2). By one analysis, live-stream viewership attributable to VTubers has grown 10× over 5 years (), indicating explosive long-term growth, but short-term quarterly figures are now flat or even slightly down. Unique active VTuber channels fell below 5,000 in Q3 2024 (streamscharts.com), reflecting some consolidation.Agency vs Indie Market Share: Analysts estimate indies consistently hold around 35–36% of total VTuber watch-time. StreamsCharts pie-charts for Q3 2024 show independents at about , compared to Hololive’s ~23.5% and Nijisanji’s 18.9% (streamscharts.com). (Other agencies like VShojo, accelerators, etc., fill out the rest.) Hololive Today’s analysis similarly notes that independents have been stable at ~36% of viewership across recent quarters (hololivetoday.com). In other words, while the top agencies are still large, indies now represent over one-third of the VTuber audience by watch-time. This split is unusual: most entertainment niches are far more concentrated. It underscores that the VTuber audience is fragmented and that no single agency fully dominates.Graduation and Turnover Rates: Exact industry-wide figures are hard to come by, but 2024 saw unusually high turnover. ANYCOLOR closed its Indonesian and Indian NIJISANJI branches in 2023 and terminated several international talents. Cover also had multiple graduations and some suspensions. These high-profile exits (Fauna, Ame, Mumei, Gura, plus others like Hololive JP member Chloe, Aqua and Shion) have alarmed fans. For a sense of scale: NIJISANJI EN’s watch-hours fell by  in December 2024 (reddit.com) (partly due to losing talents and halting debuts), while NIJISANJI JP’s hours grew. StreamsCharts even noted that in late 2024, Nijisanji EN was by far the worst-performing branch of ANYCOLOR, leading to speculation about merging it back into the main company. Despite short-term turbulence, the VTuber industry remains highly lucrative. In 2020, the top 300 YouTube channels that year made ~$26M from VTubers (konvoy.vc). Aggregate market research suggests  in global VTuber revenue. As noted, Zion Market Research estimated ~$6.3B market value in 2023 (zionmarketresearch.com). (Other sources cite smaller or larger numbers, but all agree on a large, fast-growing market.) Much of this revenue comes from fan support: in the VTuber model, donations/superchats and merchandise sales form the bulk of income. For example, Kiryu Coco once earned ~$800K via superchats in a year (konvoy.vc). The new breakout indies are already pulling huge donation totals: Dokibird raised $252K for charity in early 2024 (virtualyoutuber.fandom.com), and Nimi Nightmare set a VTuber record by raising $361K in one charity stream (virtualyoutuber.fandom.com). These figures illustrate that fans are willing to directly finance independent VTubers just as they did with agency stars. The fortunes of VTuber agencies themselves have reflected these controversies. Both ANYCOLOR and Cover Corp (Hololive’s parent) are public companies in Japan, so their stock prices respond to news. For instance, ANYCOLOR’s shares  in the weeks following Selen Tatsuki’s termination and other setbacks (investing.com). An analyst report noted that fans “accused [ANYCOLOR] of mistreating its rising talent” and pointed out the company’s repeated abrupt restructuring (closing whole country branches) (investing.com). Cover Corp has weathered more stable growth, but even it has faced scrutiny. In early 2024, Cover publicized that it had taken legal action in  against fans/critics (cover-corp.com), which some observers worried could hurt its image.Cover’s latest financial reportControversies Undermining Agency TrustThe shift toward indies is closely tied to a series of scandals and trust issues at the big agencies. Fans have grown increasingly aware of behind-the-scenes problems:Abrupt Terminations and Non-Transparent Graduations: Agencies sometimes cite vague reasons for cutting ties. Fans were outraged by how arbitrarily Hololive or NIJISANJI jettisoned talent in 2024 and 2025. For example, both Fauna and Gura “graduated” with explanations like “management differences” (vchavcha.com) (essential-japan.com), leaving fans to speculate what really happened. Anycolor’s sudden firing of Selen mid-leave was particularly poorly handled; Nijisanji’s official statement admitted they’d harassed her and her emergency contact while she was hospitalized after a suicidal attempt, further enraging the community. Many in VTubing now demand transparency: the lack of clear policy around terminations has seeded distrust. Leaked industry knowledge suggests VTuber contracts heavily favor agencies. Talents often give up rights to their avatars and have little recourse if they quit. This has drawn parallels to older idol industries, and fans worry over abuse of power. Demands for standardized talent protections and fairer contracts have grown louder in the wake of major graduations.Management and Culture Clashes: Some controversies seem to arise from friction between Japanese corporations and overseas talents. Both Hololive and Nijisanji have noted “cultural differences between Japanese and non-Japanese work environments” as an issue (hololivetoday.com). Non-Japanese VTubers (especially in EN divisions) have at times felt unsupported or misunderstood by management. The NiJi EN division in particular collapsed largely amidst mismanagement allegations. Many English-speaking talents have left NiJi EN in the past year for new careers or indies (Zaion Lanza, Pomu, in addition to Selen). Fans interpret this exodus as evidence that ANYCOLOR lost the trust of its foreign talent.Heavy-Handed Fandom Policing: Cover Corp’s recent legal crackdown on fan posts (filing disclosure requests to unmask anonymous posters, as reported by their PR) (cover-corp.com) upset many community members. While intended to protect VTubers from harassment, critics saw it as bullying the community. ANYCOLOR likewise has been harsh on social media, one-finding and suspending fans for criticism. These actions, combined with perceived secrecy, have made supporters feel unwelcome. In effect, agencies seem more focused on controlling criticism than addressing the root causes of discontent.In sum, there’s a growing narrative that agencies have mismanaged or exploited their talents. The repeated emergence of similar issues – sudden graduations, legal threats, and cultural clashes – has convinced many fans that agency systems are fragile and not always in the talent’s best interest (polygon.com) (investing.com).Permanent Shift or Passing Phase?Is the rise of indie VTubing just a temporary reaction or a lasting industry realignment? The evidence points to a possible , but also to caution: A fundamental change is that fans now visibly assert loyalty to individuals over companies (hololivetoday.com). This ideological shift is likely enduring: once viewers recognize a person behind the avatar, they tend to follow that person wherever they go. Agencies used to cultivate brand loyalty (hololive vs. nijisanji, etc.), but the exodus of stars is fracturing that pattern. Companies may need to adapt by treating talent as more than disposable IP.Indie Viability and Precedent: The success stories above show that indie careers can rival corporate ones. When enough data points (like Dokibird, Nimi, Maid Mint, Sameko) demonstrate profitability and reach for indies, more talents and fans will believe it. This could lead to a reinforcing loop: the more big names prove they can go solo, the more other talents will consider it, potentially shrinking the agency pool. Faced with talent flight, agencies might respond by reforming. There are signs Cover and ANYCOLOR are experimenting with more flexible arrangements. For instance, Cover has allowed some graduated talents to get an “Affiliate” status, as a way to keep them engaged. ANYCOLOR promised changes for NiJi EN after Selen’s exit (though details remain scarce). If agencies can offer slightly better terms – more freedom, better communication – they might stabilize. But if profits decline because top earners leave, they’ll have to make real changes. The VTuber boom may be entering a mature phase. Niche communities are fracturing, new platforms (like VR or Kick streams) are emerging, and competition is heating up. Markets often oscillate: after rapid expansion comes consolidation or correction. We may see smaller agencies fold (like “production kawaii” or “idol”) and the large ones refocus, or new models (like affiliation status) arise. However, unlike a flash-in-the-pan trend, VTubing has shown staying power across multiple years and geographies (see rise of Nijisanji China, India, etc.).Global and Technological Factors: Finally, VTubing is riding larger tech waves – from more accessible AR/VR setups to AI-generated avatars. These trends favor more indie creators (easy avatar creation, generative tools) and could fuel sustained growth. Corporate VTubers may then face competition not only from human indies but also from AI-driven avatars., while the recent surge in indie VTubing owes much to current controversies, it taps into deeper shifts: fan loyalty to personalities and wider tech democratization. It’s likely not just a short-lived rebellion. However, agencies still have powerful infrastructure, and new talents will continue to emerge through both models. The future VTuber industry may be more mixed than ever – a blend of polished corporate acts and scrappy independents, each learning from the other. If agencies can regain trust (perhaps by improving talent contracts and transparency), they may coexist with a vibrant indie scene. If not, we could see a  where the most famous VTubers are largely self-managed, with agencies playing a supporting or niche role.]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>