<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>aside&apos;s newsfeed</title><link>https://asideaside.github.io/feed/</link><description>Liveboat RSS Feed</description><item><title>常闇トワ＆獅白ぼたんのサイン入り色紙が当たる！『灰仭巫覡』新PV＆オリジナルソング公開記念キャンペーン開催</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/towabotan/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 4 Sep 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[大暮維人先生が描く人気漫画『灰仭巫覡（カイジンフゲキ）』のオリジナルソングと新PVの公開を記念し、2025年9月5日より豪華プレゼントキャンペーンがスタートしました。新PV公開！常闇トワ＆獅白ぼたんが歌うオリジナルソング2025年9月3日、講談社の「マガジンチャンネル」にて『灰仭巫覡』の新たなプロモーションビデオが公開されました。このPVのために書き下ろされたオリジナルソング『君と明かした夜』は、ホロライブ所属の人気VTuberである常闇トワさんと獅白ぼたんさんが歌唱を担当。今回の発表を記念して、抽選で1名様にが当たるキャンペーンが開催されます。『灰仭巫覡』公式X（旧Twitter）アカウント（@KAIJINFUGEKI_WM）をフォロー ※「#灰仭巫覡PV公開」「#カイジンフゲキ」のハッシュタグが付いたポストが目印です。 2025年9月5日（金）0:00 〜 2025年9月14日（日）23:59まで 利用規約に同意し、日本国内にお住まいで郵便物・宅配物の受け取りが可能な方。注意事項：色紙には当選者の宛名が記載されます。当選者にはXのダイレクトメッセージにて連絡があります。 『灰仭巫覡』コミックス第1巻から第5巻まで好評発売中です。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【速報】戌神ころね、ホンダのeスポーツ大会アンバサダーに2年連続で就任！→本人も「よろしくお願いします」と意気込み「世界の戌神」「今年もきた！」</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/korone-22/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[人気VTuberグループ「ホロライブ」所属の戌神ころねさんが、本田技研工業（Honda）が主催するeモータースポーツのグローバル大会「Honda Racing eMS 2025」の公式アンバサダーに、昨年に引き続き就任したことが発表されました。このニュースに、ファンからは「2年連続はすごすぎる！」「今年も応援します！」といった声が相次いでいます。「Honda Racing eMS」は、世界3地区（アジア・オセアニア、米州、欧州・中東・アフリカ）のトップドライバーたちが地域最速の座をかけて競い合う、本格的なeモータースポーツのグローバル大会です。戌神さんは「Honda Racing eMS 2024」でもアンバサダーを務めており、今回で2年連続という大役を担うことになります。ゲーム実況で人気を誇る戌神ころねと、世界のHondaとのコラボが再び実現しました。2025年8月26日、Honda Racing eMSの公式X（旧Twitter）アカウントが「━ Honda Racing eMS 2025 開催 ━ 昨年に続き『戌神ころね』が公式アンバサダーに！」とポストし、戌神さんのアンバサダー就任を正式に発表。あわせて、されるという大会スケジュールも公開しました。この公式発表に対し、戌神さん本人も自身のXアカウントで「今年もアンバサダーを務めさせていただきます！よろしくお願いします」と引用ポストし、就任への意気込みを表明しました。この就任のニュースに、ファンからは「世界のHondaに認められた女、戌神ころね」「ころさんの影響力すごい！」「これを機にレースゲームに挑戦してみようかな」など、驚きと喜びのコメントがありました。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ3期生、Kアリーナ横浜で2DAYSライブ開催決定！「#きゅるるん大作戦」チケット受付開始</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/arena/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:56:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[「ホロライブ」所属の3期生（兎田ぺこら、不知火フレア、白銀ノエル、宝鐘マリン）によるライブイベント「hololive 3rd Generation Live #きゅるるん大作戦 〜最強アイドル、推すしかないでしょ〜」を、に「Kアリーナ横浜」にて開催することを発表しました。本ライブは、「ホロライブ」所属の3期生4名が出演するライブイベントです。本日10月19日（日）21:00より、現地会場指定席チケットの1次先行（hololive FANCLUB先行 / 抽選）が開始されるとともに、「ABEMA」「SPWN」「ZAIKO」にて配信チケットの販売も開始されました。チケット情報などライブの最新情報は、下記特設サイト及び開催概要をご確認ください。hololive 3rd Generation Live #きゅるるん大作戦 〜最強アイドル、推すしかないでしょ〜 概要 hololive 3rd Generation Live #きゅるるん大作戦 〜最強アイドル、推すしかないでしょ〜 主催：カバー株式会社 兎田ぺこら 不知火フレア 白銀ノエル 宝鐘マリンDAY1 ： 2026年1月17日（土） 開場 16:30 / 配信開始 17:30 / 開演 18:00DAY2 ： 2026年1月18日（日） 開場 15:30 / 配信開始 16:30 / 開演 17:00 Kアリーナ横浜 （〒220-8507 神奈川県横浜市西区みなとみらい6丁目2−14） 最寄り駅 〇新高島駅 みなとみらい線4臨港パーク口より徒歩5分 〇みなとみらい駅 みなとみらい線2いちょう通り口より徒歩12分 ※お1人様2枚までお申し込み可能です。 ※チケット氏名印字あり。■1次先行（hololive FANCLUB先行 / 抽選）受付期間：2025年10月19日（日）21:00 ～ 2025年10月29日（水） 23:59当選確認期間・入金期間：2025年11月5日（水）15:00 ～ 2025年11月9日（日）23:00※お申し込みには、hololive FANCLUBへの入会が必要となります。※別途手数料（先行サービス料440円、システム利用料330円、電子チケット利用料110円）がかかります。受付期間：2025年11月13日（木）21:00 ～ 2025年11月23日（日）23:59当選確認期間・入金期間：2025年11月28日（金）15:00 ～ 2025年12月1日（月）23:00※別途手数料（先行サービス料440円、システム利用料330円、電子チケット利用料110円）がかかります。受付期間・発券開始：2025年12月14日（日）12:00 ～※別途手数料（システム利用料330円、電子チケット利用料110円）がかかります。 2025年10月19日（日）21:00 ～ 2026年2月18日（水）20:00 公演終了後、公開準備ができ次第アーカイブ視聴可能となり、2026年2月18日（水）23:59 まで何度でもご視聴いただけます。 ※2026年2月18日（水）23:59 を過ぎると、アーカイブ視聴中でも視聴できなくなります。 ※プラットフォームごとに別途手数料が発生する場合があります。本公演開催に合わせ、本日10月19日（日）よりhololive 3rd Generation Live #きゅるるん大作戦 〜最強アイドル、推すしかないでしょ〜のライブグッズが解禁されました。 2025年10月19日（日）21:00 ～ 2025年11月25日（火）18:00 まで販売期間や注意事項・詳細は、公式HPの販売ページなどをご確認ください。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>「一番くじ ホロライブ ～Villain Style～」が2026年1月10日より発売決定！</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/%e3%80%8c%e4%b8%80%e7%95%aa%e3%81%8f%e3%81%98-%e3%83%9b%e3%83%ad%e3%83%a9%e3%82%a4%e3%83%96-%ef%bd%9evillain-style%ef%bd%9e%e3%80%8d%e3%81%8c2026%e5%b9%b41%e6%9c%8810%e6%97%a5%e3%82%88%e3%82%8a/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 9 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[VTuberグループ「ホロライブ」の新たな一番くじ、「一番くじ ホロライブ ～Villain Style～」の発売が決定しました！今回のテーマは「Villain Style」。いつもとは一味違った、ダークで魅力的なホロライブメンバーの姿が描かれることが期待されます。ファンにとっては見逃せないラインナップとなりそうです。 一番くじ ホロライブ ～Villain Style～ 2026年01月10日(土)より順次発売予定]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ときのそら、史上最大規模のワンマンライブを東京国際フォーラムで開催決定！「夢が叶った！」「絶対行く！」とファン歓喜</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/sora-18/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 9 Jan 2026 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブプロダクション所属のVTuber「ときのそら」さんが、自身の活動史上最大規模となるワンマンライブの開催を発表。　ホロライブ0期生としてVTuberシーンの黎明期から業界を牽引してきた「ときのそら」さんが、にて、ワンマンライブ「New Year’s Party 2026『Dreams in Motion』」を開催することを発表しました。ときのそらさんにとって史上最大規模となる本公演でSNSではファンから「国際フォーラムはすごすぎる！」「そらちゃんの夢がまた一つ叶う瞬間に立ち会えるなんて…」といった歓喜の声が相次ぎました。“そらとも”と共に描く「Dreams in Motion」今回のライブは、ときのそらさんが毎年開催している恒例のニューイヤーパーティ、通称「そらぱ」の特別版。公演タイトルの「Dreams in Motion（ドリームズ・イン・モーション）」には、夢に向かって歩み続けるときのそらさん自身と、その姿を見守り、応援し続けるファン＝“そらとも”の想いが込められているとのこと。本公演は、昼公演＜Day＞と夜公演＜Night＞の2部構成で開催。それぞれ異なる演出が期待されています。チケットは、最前エリアが確約され、Tシャツや無線制御ペンライト、限定ボイスなどの豪華特典が付いたSS席（¥18,800）から、学生にも優しい学割チケット（¥5,150）まで、幅広い券種が用意されています。また、遠方のファンに向けた配信チケットも販売され、こちらも限定グッズ付きのプランが用意されるなど、すべての“そらとも”が楽しめる配慮がなされています。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>星街すいせい、新曲「月に向かって撃て」が新作アニメ『真夜中ハートチューン』OPテーマに決定！</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/suisei-49/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 6 Jan 2026 00:53:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ所属のVTuber、星街すいせいの新曲「月に向かって撃て」が、2026年1月より放送開始となるTVアニメ『真夜中ハートチューン』のオープニングテーマ（OP）に決定したことが発表されました。本日、TVアニメ『真夜中ハートチューン』の公式X（旧Twitter）アカウント（@anime_mayochu）にてPV第2弾が公開され、あわせて主題歌情報が解禁となりました。星街すいせいが歌う「月に向かって撃て」が、本作のオープニングを飾ります。なお、エンディングテーマ（ED）はSoalaさんの「声の軌跡」に決定しています。TVアニメ『真夜中ハートチューン』は、2026年1月6日(火)23時より、カンテレ・フジテレビ系全国ネット“火アニバル!!”枠、BS朝日ほかにて放送開始予定です。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ、年末恒例のカウントダウンライブ開催決定！ 発表に「これがないと年越せない！」</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/holo-5/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[VTuber事務所「ホロライブプロダクション」は9月5日、公式X（旧Twitter）にて、年末恒例の大型ライブ『hololive production COUNTDOWN LIVE 2025▷2026』を、2025年12月31日（水）に開催することを発表した。この待望のニュースに、ファンからは「やっぱりこれがないと年は越せない！」「全編無料はありがたすぎる」といった喜びの声が殺到している。年末の風物詩！所属タレントがほぼ総出演する豪華ライブホロライブプロダクションが毎年大晦日に開催するカウントダウンライブは、所属タレントが一堂に会する、まさしく”お祭り”と呼ぶにふさわしい一大イベントだ。ホロライブ、ホロスターズの所属タレントのほぼ全員が3Dで出演し、オリジナル曲やこの日限りの特別ユニットによるパフォーマンスを全編無料で配信。年々スケールアップする圧巻のクオリティと、幸福感に満ちた演出で世界中のファンを魅了してきた。昨年開催された『hololive production COUNTDOWN LIVE 2024▷2025』では、60名を超えるタレントが出演。バラエティ企画満載の『ゆくホロくるホロ』からライブ本編へと繋がる構成で、ファンを飽きさせない工夫が凝らされていた。今年も同様の形式が期待されており、どのタレントがどんな楽曲を披露するのか、期待が高まっている。この発表に、ファンからは「うおおおお！今年も来た！生きる理由をありがとう！」「毎年クオリティが上がり続けてるから今年も楽しみすぎる」「全編無料…？ホロライブの福利厚生、手厚すぎ！」「大晦日の予定、即決しました」といった歓喜のコメントが殺到。また、「推しと推しのユニットが見たい！」「今年はどんな絡みがあるかな？」など、具体的なパフォーマンス内容を予想し、胸を膨らませる声も多く見られた。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【ロボ子さん】チャンネル登録者100万人突破記念！ファンミーティング「ろぼ～このマリオネットパーティー！」12月開催決定！</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/roboko-3/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sat, 6 Dec 2025 14:57:41 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[VTuber「ロボ子さん」のチャンネル登録者100万人突破を記念したファンミーティング「ろぼ～このマリオネットパーティー！～Robocosan’s Marionette Party～」の開催が決定しました！ 主催のタブリエ・マーケティング株式会社によると、本イベントは2025年12月6日(土)および7日(日)の2日間にわたり、秋葉原エンタスにて開催されます。◆ 100万人突破記念！トークショー＆チェキ会で直接お祝い！今回のイベントは、ロボ子さんのチャンネル登録者100万人突破を記念し、「ろぼさーとの交流を目的とした」ファンミーティングとして開催されます。ロボ子さんとのやが実施されるとのこと！ さらに会場では、ロボ子さんの愛用品やこれまでのイベントグッズを間近で見られるも設置されます。また、「ロボ子さんのメカ・ストロベリーミルク」と「ろぼさーに捧げるロボティック・クランベリーカフェオレ」（各800円/税込）の2種が販売され、注文特典としてコラボ限定名刺サイズカード(全2種)がランダムで1枚プレゼントされます。チケット購入＆入場特典として「」も用意されます。◆ チケット一次先行は11月4日から！開催概要をチェック「ろぼ～このマリオネットパーティー！」は、2025年12月6日(土)と7日(日)の各日、昼公演（12:00 START）と夜公演（16:30 START）の全4公演が予定されています。チケット料金は7,500円（※別途入場時にドリンク代が必要）。 は、2025年11月4日(火) 18:00から11月16日(日)23：59までの期間で受け付けられます。申し込みは「LivePocket -Ticket-」にて行われます。応募が集中することが予想されるため、参加希望の方はお早めに特設サイトで詳細を確認し、申し込みをお忘れなく！: ろぼ～このマリオネットパーティー！～Robocosan’s Marionette Party～:昼公演: OPEN 11:00／START 12:00夜公演: OPEN 15:30／START 16:30: 7,500円 (※入場時、別途ドリンク代必要): 2025年11月4日(火) 18:00～2025年11月16日(日)23：59: 「ろぼ～このマリオネットパーティー！」特設ページ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>鷹嶺ルイ 2ndアルバム『Lapis Lazuli』発売記念ミニライブが12月7日(日)に開催決定！参加抽選の申し込みがスタート</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/rui-9/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 2 Dec 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ所属のVTuber、鷹嶺ルイさんの2ndアルバム『Lapis Lazuli』が2025年12月3日(水)に発売されることを記念し、ファン待望のミニライブイベントの開催が決定しました。イベントは2025年12月7日(日)にAKIHABARAゲーマーズ本店にて開催され、対象商品をご予約いただいた方の中から抽選でご招待されます。鷹嶺ルイ 2nd Album『Lapis Lazuli』発売記念イベント2025年12月7日(日) 18時以降 ※詳細時間は当選者にのみ通知AKIHABARAゲーマーズ本店 6F イベントスペース本イベントへの参加は抽選制となります。対象店舗にて対象商品を全額内金でご予約いただいた方に、シリアルコード付きの応募券が配布されます。 2025年9月25日(木) 開店時 ～ 10月25日(土) 閉店時 2025年10月19日(日) 23:59までの注文分応募券に記載の二次元コードから申込ページにアクセスし、必要事項を記入してご応募ください。ゲーマーズマイページ内の「フェア・イベント申込履歴」にて当落結果をご確認いただけます。鷹嶺ルイ 2nd Album 『Lapis Lazuli』 発売日：2025年12月3日(水) 価格：3,850円(税込)ゲーマーズ全店（オンラインショップ含む） ※金沢ゲーマーズは対象外となります。イベントの詳細や応募に関する最新情報は、ゲーマーズ公式サイトをご確認ください。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ・角巻わため、大型マイクラ企画「LAMB VEGAS」の開催を発表！</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/watame-26/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ所属のVTuber、角巻わためさんが、Minecraft企画「」の開催を正式に発表しました。グランドオープンイベントはより開催される予定です。本企画は、ラスベガスをモチーフとしたカジノ風のワールドを舞台にしたMinecraftイベントサーバーです。企画概要によれば、「」をさらに豪華に、そして専用サーバーでリニューアルしたものとなります。グランドオープンを記念したイベントでは、ホロライブのメンバーが招待され、「」をテーマに、サーバー内の様々なゲームでメダルの枚数を競い合います。今回の「LAMB VEGAS」サーバーの大きな特徴として、11月29日のイベント終了後もになることが明記されています。さらに、サーバー内の装飾をリスナー（ファン）から募集する「」企画も発表されました。参加希望者は、ハッシュタグ「」をつけて作品を投稿することで、このビッグプロジェクトに参加できます。角巻わためさんは自身の投稿で「」と意気込みを語っていました。 MINECRAFT EVENT SERVER「LAMB VEGAS Presents by Watame」 2025年11月29日(土) 19:00 ～ 22:00（予定） ホロライブメンバーを招待したグランドオープンイベント]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【ロボ子さんのサイバーメイドカフェ】開催決定！ホロライブ「ロボ子さん」こだわりの限定メニュー＆特典を見逃すな！</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/robokosan-3/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 12:26:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ所属のVTuber「ロボ子さん」と「キュアメイドカフェ」のコラボレーションカフェ、「ロボ子さんのサイバーメイドカフェ」が2025年11月28日（金）から12月14日（日）までの期間限定で開催されることが決定した。ロボ子さんのこだわり満載！限定メニュー＆特典をピックアップ！今回のコラボカフェでは、ロボ子さんが「ろぼさー（ファン）」の皆様のためにこだわった、サイバーメイドな世界観あふれるオリジナルメニューが多数登場する。フードメニューには、ロボ子さんからろぼさーへの愛が詰まった「」（1,780円・税込）や、得意料理をキュアメイドカフェ風にアレンジした「」（1,480円・税込）などがラインナップ。さらに、ろぼさーをイメージした「」（1,300円・税込）や、制服＆エプロン姿をイメージした「」（880円・税込）など、スイーツやドリンクも充実。SNS投稿で注文できるスペシャルドリンクも見逃せない。限定特典も用意。コラボメニュー1品ご注文につき「」がランダムで1枚プレゼントされるほか、税込3,000円以上の注文ごとにもらえる「」も！◆ 開催は11月28日から！ファンミやグッズ販売も要チェック！「ロボ子さんのサイバーメイドカフェ」は、2025年11月28日（金）から12月14日（日）まで、キュアメイドカフェ（オノデンビル4F）にて開催。さらに、カフェ期間中には同ビル5階「エンタス」にても決定しているほか、同ビル1階「グランエンタス」ではも予定されている。なお、カフェ店内利用については一部日程で『Livepocket』を使用した事前抽選制の整理券配布が予定されている。グッズ購入についても混雑が予想される日は整理券が配布される場合があるため、参加予定のろぼさーは、キュアメイドカフェ公式サイトの情報を必ずチェックしよう。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>細田守監督最新作『果てしなきスカーレット』公開記念、ホロライブプロダクション所属 VTuber「儒烏…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000224.000100939.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/100939/224/100939-224-7b07725955ac2a5f2eb7a867511090d4-1691x1899.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:15:44 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>年末年始もホロスタ尽くし！！コラボ配信盛りだくさん！</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000001201.000030268.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/30268/1201/30268-1201-294c7ff282f9701a5f55d64ee5fcdc11-1920x1080.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:15:44 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ピザハット×『ReGLOSS（リグロス）』キャンペーン！【12/1～1/4開催】</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000325.000031164.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/31164/325/31164-325-7403d96a5279167b5f091edc9cef1e5d-1200x630.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:15:44 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】HELLO! GOOD SMILE さくらみこ</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/hello-miko/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 03:09:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[※期間中は必ずご予約できます。※上記期間をもって販売予定数が決定し、以降は予定数に達し次第受付終了※GOODSMILE以外の通販サイトでは数に限りあり]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】HELLO! GOOD SMILE ときのそら</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/hello-sora/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 03:08:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[※期間中は必ずご予約できます。※上記期間をもって販売予定数が決定し、以降は予定数に達し次第受付終了※GOODSMILE以外の通販サイトでは数に限りあり]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【HMV35周年記念プロジェクト】VTuberガールズグループ「ReGLOSS」の2nd Album…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000624.000034304.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/34304/624/34304-624-4a1ea1a106ff200b5e9afb4abe112e97-1454x820.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 10:46:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ANIPLUS x hololive English -Advent- comes to AGF 2025 in South Korea, December 5-7</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20251127-aniplus-x-hololive-english-advent-comes-to-agf-2025-in-south-korea-december-5-7/</link><author>os_pr</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:50:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[November 27, 2025, Tokyo, JAPAN – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) has announced a collaboration between ANIPLUS and hololive English -Advent- for AGF 2025 in South Korea, taking place on December 5 to 7, 2025. This collaboration includes a themed cafe as well as exclusive merchandise showcasing a new winter-themed key visual of the five members of hololive English -Advent-. This new merchandise will be available exclusively at the ANIPLUS MD booth, and includes products such as acrylic standees, can badges, and happi.Attendees of the event can also enjoy a collaboration menu inspired by hololive English -Advent-, which can be found at the ANIPLUS x hololive English -Advent- café booth at AGF Korea.For more information, please check out the ANIPLUS and AGF Korea official social media accounts below.ANIPLUS x hololive English -Advent- Collaboration at AGF Korea
Event Name: AGF 2025
Venue: Ilsan KINTEX, South Korea■ Collaboration Café Menu Caffeine Supply for our Listeners! hololive English -Advent-’s Americano
Drink purchase comes with a photocard (1 of 10 designs) A Korean Dish recommended by hololive English -Advent-! Tender Beef Kimchi Fried Rice
(Contains Fried Rice, Beef Brisket, Fried Egg, Seaweed)
Food purchase comes with a mini-poster (1 of 2 designs)
All purchases of ANIPLUS x hololive English -Advent- merchandise will come with a double-sided A4 Hologram Poster!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Regarding “NePoLaBo Major Announcement” and “holoX Arrival Party”</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/7991/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:18:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A “NePoLaBo Major Announcement” that was scheduled for November 28, and “holoX Arrival Party,” which was scheduled for December 2, will be postponed following further discussions.
We apologize for the inconvenience and concern this may cause to everyone who had been looking forward to these announcements.We will provide updated schedules as soon as they are decided.
Thank you for your understanding.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Sharing the Same Joy Worldwide: What Does Localization Look Like at hololive production?</title><link>https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en/list/3520</link><author>平松梨沙</author><category>COVER</category><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en">COVEREdge Magazine</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[The Wide-Ranging Work of LocalizationContent localization refers to the process of adapting content created in one country or region so it resonates naturally with users in another language or cultural setting: it is more than simply translating words. The role of our Localization Team requires an understanding of local customs, cultural context, regulations, and values, and adjusting expressions so the overall message feels authentic and reaches the audience effectively.Our Localization Team is made up of around ten members, covering a wide range of languages – English, Indonesian, Spanish, Korean, and both Traditional and Simplified Chinese. Each language has its own in-house specialist, who also works with a network of freelance translators. The team is also supported by our subtitle production staff, who take care of technical tasks such as “spotting,” the process of working out when subtitles should appear on screen. Examples of Content We LocalizeVideos on the official channel (including the 3D animated series “holo no graffiti” (hologra), variety segments, short videos, etc.)The manga series “hololive Alternative” (including “Yamato Phantasia,” “Vesta de Cooking,” and “Underworld Academy Overload!!”）Subtitles for Blu-ray versions of real-life concertsTalent voice pack contentIndividual talent projects (e.g., “Legend of Polka” by Omaru Polka; members-only four-panel comics of Tsunomaki Watame, etc.) <Example> How We Localize hologra1.Subtitle staff does the spotting for the episode2.A script is prepared in a spreadsheet ready to be translated3.Translators for each language are assigned to input their translations(English, Spanish, Indonesian, Korean, Chinese, Thai subtitles)4.Localization staff for each region review and refine the translations5.Once everything is checked, the finalized version is used to create the subtitles<Example> How We Localize hololive Alternative Manga1.Japanese dialogue and sound effects are translated by localization staff or by external translators, who create the initial draft2.The translated text is inserted directly into the manga panels3.The Japanese and translated versions are reviewed side by side, and necessary adjustments are made4.Finally, our team carries out a Linguistic Quality Assurance check to ensure there are no typos or missing lines/sound effects. From NARUTO to GTO: How Entertainment Sparked Journeys to Learning JapaneseQuietly supporting COVER’s global expansion behind the scenes are two members of the Localization Team with whom we sat down for this interview: team leaders Sriram Gurunathan (also known as Ram) and Natalia Solichin, who oversee English and Indonesian respectively.――When did you both come to Japan, and when did you start working at COVER?I came to Japan from Indonesia seven years ago. After spending a few years studying Japanese, I worked at a gaming company where I handled translation and localization for social games before joining COVER in 2024.I arrived in Japan later than Natalia. I’m originally from India, and I began working with COVER around 2019 as a freelance translator from my home country. I was set to join the company in 2021, but the pandemic made it impossible to travel. Once I finally received permission to enter Japan, I moved here and officially joined the company in May of 2022.――Since you’re from India, is Hindi your first language?No, my first language is English. In India, English is one of the official languages, and many school curriculums are taught entirely in English, including mine.India has more than 450 regional languages – some similar to one another and others completely different. Even distances as close as Tokyo and Kanagawa can see people speaking entirely different languages, not just different dialects. As my father’s job required us to move frequently, I spent my childhood relocating to all kinds of places and each time we moved, I had to learn a new language. Looking back, I think that experience really strengthened my ability to pick up languages.――What inspired you both to start learning Japanese?Japanese pop culture is hugely popular in Indonesia. I grew up watching manga and anime like “Doraemon” and “NARUTO,” and that naturally made me curious about the country they came from. At one point, I even tried playing a NARUTO game without understanding any Japanese and as I kept playing, I slowly started to recognize katakana – mainly because the character names were written in katakana. ――That’s very true. The first names of Naruto, Sasuke, Sakura, and Hinata all appear in katakana, don’t they?!Exactly. That’s actually how I ended up learning Japanese: I started with katakana before moving on to hiragana, and then kanji. I’ve never met anyone who learned Japanese in that order! Most people start with hiragana, then katakana and after that kanji. It probably is a little unusual (lol). Even after that, I continued consuming other Japanese works that had been translated into Indonesian, but there were no translated versions of things such as (self-published works), and there were some that I really wanted to read, so that pushed me to start studying Japanese more seriously.That’s actually a pretty common pattern among overseas  learning Japanese (lol). About ten years ago, it was normal to wait six months to a year for the English versions of Japanese content to come out, so a lot of fans started learning Japanese simply because they wanted to read or watch things as soon as they could. In my case, the first Japanese show I ever watched was GTO, the one starring Takashi Sorimachi. I watched it with English subtitles and got completely hooked. After that, I spent the next seven years devouring all kinds of Japanese content and eventually, I could understand about 70 percent of it and that’s when I decided to start studying the language more seriously.Bringing Out Each Talents’s Charm Through Translation――What are some of the challenges you face when localizing Japanese content?One challenge is translating expressions that are commonly used in Japanese but don’t exist in Indonesian. For example, phrases like “” or “” don’t have direct equivalents. So I adjust them depending on the context – sometimes as a greeting, or sometimes as a message of appreciation. Right. Instead of translating the words literally, we focus on what the phrase means in that specific situation and choose the wording that fits best. That’s right. Another challenge is translating Japanese onomatopoeia. Manga often uses sound effects as if they were dialogue, like “rero-rero” for licking or “sara-sara” for the sound of writing. But in Indonesian, those kinds of onomatopoeia feel very unnatural. So in those cases, I usually rewrite them as descriptive sentences instead of trying to recreate the sound. When I first started translating, I remember wondering what “” means in expressions such as “” (staring intently). Japanese onomatopoeia can be tricky even when translating into English.――Content from hololive production seems especially challenging to localize, since each talent has their own unique way of speaking and distinct character. That’s true. hologra, in particular, is a comedy-style show with lots of wordplay in Japanese, so localizing it can be quite tough. Comedy… I’m not sure that’s the right word (lol). To me, it feels more like “(nonsense humor)” – the kind of charm that comes from things being slightly nonsensical. For example, the maid cafe episode was absolute chaos.――You’re talking about the “U Maid?” episode, right?It was the episode where Shirakami Fubuki, La+ Darkness, and Omaru Polka – classic old-school otaku types – dote on FUWAMOCO (Fuwawa Abyssgard and Mococo Abyssgard), who are dressed as maids. The whole thing was filled with otaku slang and internet memes like “, “,” and “.” There was no way to translate them literally, so I replaced them with English slang and memes that would convey a similar vibe.  For the Indonesian subtitles, I use Indonesian memes instead. ――So, even though the wording wasn’t exactly the same as the original Japanese, you chose English or Indonesian expressions that still have that slightly old-school, otaku-like feel. That sounds like quite a challenge. Surprisingly, that part was actually pretty easy for me. I’m an old-school otaku myself, so all the phrases just came naturally (lol). Translating otaku terms comes with its own set of challenges, though. Take “,” for example. In English-speaking otaku circles, the word “” is already widely used, so I understand why many people think we should simply keep it as is. But as an official localization team, we want the content to be enjoyable for fans who aren’t necessarily familiar with otaku culture, which is why I intentionally choose words that are easier for a broader audience to understand.――How would you translate it?There are expressions like “hot and cold,” but that isn’t really well-received among otaku. They’ll say, “Why does it start with the ‘dere (hot)’ part?” since the whole point of ‘’ is that someone goes from feeling ‘ (cold)’ to ‘ (hot)’. ” So when I translate it, I adjust the wording each time depending on the context.“” is also tricky to translate into Indonesian. Sometimes I adapt it depending on the context, and other times I add a brief note explaining what “” means.  Adding explanations is another option too. But we’ve been doing it less and less lately because, with entertainment content, it’s important that people understand things instantly, so we try not to make it feel too much like studying.Exactly. I think it’s all about finding the right balance so the subtitles remain easy to read as part of the content. Indonesian subtitles tend to be longer than those in Japanese or Chinese, so they can easily take up more space. But if viewers are too busy reading the subtitles to enjoy the content itself, that defeats the purpose. So while keeping translations accurate, I try to keep them as short as possible – ideally within two lines. As the official localization team, we also see it as our role to keep each talent’s image consistent across different regions. In the VTuber community, fans often add their own translations to clipped videos, which creates a culture of many different interpretations. That means a single phrase can end up with multiple translations depending on who’s doing it. For example, take the unique greeting “Tis’ I!” (“Yo dayo~”) used by Nakiri Ayame. Everyone has translated it differently, so by providing an official translation through hololive production’s content, we’re able to offer something that fans can consider a standard translation. ――That makes sense. The words you choose in translation can really shape how a character comes across – cute, serious, playful, and so on. That’s a big responsibility.Exactly. That’s why we research each talent carefully, including watching their streams, so we can produce translations that feel natural and stay true to their personality.Sharing the Same Joy Across Languages and Cultures Through Localization――Is there a project that left a strong impression on you?For me, it would be the hologra graduation episode for Nanashi Mumei, titled “Memories I Will Not Forget.” It’s the episode where Nanashi Mumei visits other talents before graduating, and there’s a scene where Anya Melfissa from hololive Indonesia prepares a whole stack of stone tablets covered in ancient writing just so Nanashi Mumei can get to know her better. In the scene, Nanashi Mumei reads the ancient inscriptions with ease, which really impresses everyone around her, but in the original script, those “ancient characters” were just random strings of text. I felt that instead of having her read out meaningless letters, having her read the inscriptions in Javanese would give more context to the tablets in relation to Anya’s lore and make the moment feel more authentic.When I pitched this idea, they decided to run with it. I also recorded the Javanese lines for reference and shared them with Nanashi Mumei, who used them during the actual recording. After the episode was released, seeing that fans had noticed and reacted with comments like, “Nanashi Mumei is speaking Javanese!” and “They even localize such small details like that?” made me really happy. One project that has really remained with me was when I localized the lyrics for Hoshimachi Suisei’s “Stellar Stellar” music video. I translated the English subtitles so they could actually be sung along with the melody, which was quite a challenge. Hoshimachi Suisei once mentioned that she wrote the lyrics after extensively reading The Little Prince, so I wanted the English version to subtly reflect that. Not by stating it outright, but in a way that would make attentive listeners think, “Is this inspired by The Little Prince?” Striking that balance was tricky, but taking a deep dive into the lyrics and searching for the best possible wording made the whole process both challenging and enjoyable. Translating Japanese song lyrics is pretty difficult, isn’t it?It is. Even when the lyrics are abstract or don’t specify a subject, they still make sense in Japanese. But that doesn’t work the same way in English or Indonesian – we have to decide who the lyrics are referring to or to whom something belongs. I struggle with that every single time, but music is something people can enjoy regardless of language – it’s universal. And that’s exactly what we aim for as a localization team. So I really want to keep putting energy into lyric localization for music videos moving forward. ーーHave you noticed any differences in how fans from different countries react to content?Our job in localization is to minimize those differences. Even if the language they receive is different, the goal is for fans everywhere to have the same experience and the same sense of enjoyment. If there’s still a gap in that sense, it means we haven’t done our jobs well. Localization is all about making content feel just as natural in different languages and cultures. That’s the challenging part, but it’s also what makes the work so enjoyable. ――Lastly, what do you find most rewarding about working in localization at COVER?I’ve spent countless hours enjoying Japanese entertainment, and I’m genuinely grateful for all the great moments it has given me. Now, being able to help share that same content with fans around the world feels deeply rewarding. At COVER, there’s a strong commitment to global expansion, and the Localization Team plays a key role in that. That certainly comes with some added pressure, but when a localization project turns out well, the sense of accomplishment is huge. It really does come with a lot of responsibility. Since each language has just one person in charge, you feel almost like the representative for that language within COVER. For anyone who wants to take on meaningful, high-impact work, I think this is an incredibly rewarding place to be.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>[hololive] A Fun and Cute Singing Collaboration! FLOW GLOW, Active as part of hololive DEV_IS, Is Offering Original Drinks &amp; Goo...</title><link>https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/entry_421.html</link><author></author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:16:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/top_page.html?q=hololive">VTuber Republic</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>AZKi SOLO LiVE 2025 &quot;Departure&quot; のオフィシャルレポート公開！@ぴあア…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000001199.000030268.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/30268/1199/30268-1199-856ed69323634f77ba8efbe98cfc7bc4-1920x1080.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 10:20:39 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>[Usada Pekora] Let’s Take Care of Our Voices Together! A Collaboration with a Herbal Medicine Maker Featuring Lots of Oriental-S...</title><link>https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/entry_420.html</link><author></author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:51:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/top_page.html?q=hololive">VTuber Republic</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME オフィシャルスリーブ / シオリ・ノヴェラ / 古石ビジュー / エリザベス・ローズ・ブラッドフレイム / ジジ・ムリン：26年2月20日発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/holoca-supply07/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:36:51 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[︎発売日26年2月20日︎価格：スリーブ 990円【関連】hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【発売中】WurtS NEW EP「デジタル・ラブ」星街すいせい歌唱参加</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/digital-love/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 11:59:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[・CD・CD＋Blu-rayUPDATE feat. Deu & Ito (PEOPLE 1), Moto (Chilli Beans.)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>日本のアニメ・Vtuberコンテンツの海外展開を支援するカプセルジャパン株式会社、シリーズBで資金調…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000041.000042555.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/42555/41/42555-41-bdfc78f37bba2fef1de86a73af35edec-1920x1280.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 09:47:04 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>大空スバルさんと一緒に走ろう！『ソニックレーシング クロスワールド』視聴者参加型配信を11月27日（…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000006957.000005397.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/5397/6957/5397-6957-a881a2ec55459986b5c62659e8c7697d-800x450.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 09:47:04 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ver. 1.1.11 Release Notes</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/ver1111_updatenotice/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 09:03:49 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This is the Holoearth Management Team.
Holoearth was updated on November 25.■ Removal of NPC characters
Certain NPCs in Focal Square and Alternative City were removed.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Takanashi Kiara / Ninomae Ina’nis 1st Concert &quot;Dra…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000001197.000030268.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/30268/1197/30268-1197-b03b9343c5a75ae5d20d39058eccff70-1920x1080.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 09:45:35 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ロボ子さんのサイバーメイドカフェ in 秋葉原 11月28日よりコラボ開催!</title><link>https://collabo-cafe.com/events/collabo/hololive-robocosan-cafe-curemaid-akihabara2025/</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 07:17:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://collabo-cafe.com/?s=Hololive">hololive collabs in Japan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[大人気バーチャルYouTuber事務所「ホロライブ」に所属する「ロボ子さん」× キュアメイドカフェにて2025年11月28日〜12月14日までコラボカフェが開催される。ロボ子さんがろぼさーの皆様のためにこだわったコラボメニューがお楽しみいただける他、イベントオリジナルグッズが登場！]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>EMERGENCY STREAM - KIARA INA DUO LIVE CONCERT INCOMING 🐔🔥🔥🔥 (i am cooked)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xqok2SLm6q8</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/xqok2SLm6q8?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 04:55:34 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[✨ Support & Follow hwikky
- X (Twitter): x.com/hwikkyofficial
- Patreon: patreon.com/hwikky
- Ko-fi: ko-fi.com/hwikky

#hololive #ホロライブ
#holoIDChromaticFuture #comifuro]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Takanashi Kiara / Ninomae Ina’nis 1st Concert “Drawn to Dawn”</title><link>https://hololive.hololivepro.com/en/events/drawn-to-dawn/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 03:50:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive.hololivepro.com/en">hololive Events</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Takanashi Kiara / Ninomae Ina’nis 1st Concert “Drawn to Dawn”
Organized by: COVER CorporationTakanashi Kiara / Ninomae Ina’nis Friday, March 27, 2026
Doors Open: 6:30PM / Streaming starts: 7:30PM / Starts: 8:00PM (PDT) Saturday, March 28, 2026
Doors Open: 6:30PM / Streaming starts: 7:30PM / Starts: 8:00PM (PDT)
・ Early Entry GA Ticket: $130
・ FRONT Loge / FRONT Mezzanine: $160
・ REAR Loge / MIDDLE Mezzanine: $130
・ MIDDLE Mezzanine: $110
・ 1-DAY Streaming Ticket: March 27, 2026 (PDT)
・ 1-DAY Streaming Ticket: March 28, 2026 (PDT)
・ 2-DAY Stream Pass: March 27 & 28, 2026 (PDT)* Streaming tickets will be sold until April 28, 2026 at 8:00 PM (PDT)
* Once the performance has ended and the archive is ready, you will be able to watch the archived stream as much as you like until 11:59 PM April 25, 2026 (PDT)
* After 11:59 PM April 28, 2026 (PDT) the performance archive will no longer be available for viewing.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Takanashi Kiara and Ninomae Ina’nis to Star in Their Shared Concert, “Takanashi Kiara / Ninomae Ina’nis 1st Concert ‘Drawn to Dawn’” at The Wiltern in Los Angeles, March 27th and 28th, 2026!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20251124-takanashi-kiara-and-ninomae-inanis-to-star-in-their-shared-concert-takanashi-kiara-ninomae-inanis-1st-concert-drawn-to-dawn-at-the-wiltern-in-l/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 03:50:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[November 24, 2025, Tokyo, JAPAN – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) is excited to announce the first-ever joint concert headlined by hololive English -Myth- talents Takanashi Kiara and Ninomae Ina’nis. Taking place on March 27th and 28th, 2026 at The Wiltern in Los Angeles, “Takanashi Kiara / Ninomae Ina’nis 1st Concert ‘Drawn to Dawn’” will feature various performances from both of the starring talents.Streaming tickets are now on sale from November 24, 2025 onwards on platforms SPWN and Streaming+.
Venue tickets for the event will go on sale December 4th at 4:00PM PST.Takanashi Kiara/Ninomae Ina’nis 1st Concert “Drawn to Dawn” OverviewTakanashi Kiara/Ninomae Ina’nis 1st Concert “Drawn to Dawn”
Organized by: COVER Corporation
Takanashi Kiara / Ninomae Ina’nis
Day 1: Friday, March 27, 2026
Doors Open: 6:30PM / Streaming starts: 7:30PM / Starts: 8:00PM (PDT)
Day 2: Saturday, March 28, 2026
Doors Open: 6:30PM / Streaming starts: 7:30PM / Starts: 8:00PM (PDT)・ Early Entry GA Ticket: $130
・ GA Ticket: $105
・ FRONT Loge / FRONT Mezzanine: $160
・ REAR Loge / MIDDLE Mezzanine: $130
・ REAR Mezzanine: $95* Venue tickets will be available from December 4, 2025 at 4:00PM (PST)・ 1-DAY Streaming Ticket: March 27, 2026 (PDT)
・ 1-DAY Streaming Ticket: March 28, 2026 (PDT)
・ 2-DAY Stream Pass: March 27 & 28, 2026 (PDT)■ Streaming Ticket Purchase Links
・ SPWN: https://spwn.jp/events/evt_26032802-engkiarainanis1st
・ Streaming+: https://eplus.jp/takanashikiara_1st-st* Streaming tickets will be sold until April 28, 2026 at 8:00 PM (PDT)
* Once the performance has ended and the archive is ready, you will be able to watch the archived stream as much as you like until 11:59 PM April 25, 2026 (PDT)
* After 11:59 PM April 28, 2026 (PDT) the performance archive will no longer be available for viewing.Details regarding this concert’s merchandise will be released at a later time, so please stay tuned for future updates via our official social media channels.Upcoming Album Release OverviewTakanashi Kiara and Ninomae Ina’nis are also releasing a new album and EP respectively.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【発売中】VTuberスタイル 2025年12月号/ 表紙・巻頭特集 FLOW GLOW</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/vtuberstyle-202512/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 11:15:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ID Trip AFTERTALK - Chromatic Future, Comifuro Thoughts</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5QAfw66mb-U</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/5QAfw66mb-U?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 13:13:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Chromatic Future Premiere: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ScI02LHlT-w

✨ Support & Follow hwikky
- X (Twitter): x.com/hwikkyofficial
- Patreon: patreon.com/hwikky
- Ko-fi: ko-fi.com/hwikky

#hololive #ホロライブ
#holoIDChromaticFuture #comifuro]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>11/28(金)～コラボカフェ《ロボ子さんのサイバーメイドカフェ》 開催！12/6(土)7(日)ファ…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000001337.000099047.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/99047/1337/99047-1337-88a37abb431cf54a4ee37a78b29376e6-1200x675.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 09:37:51 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>カバー株式会社、Unreal Engineを活用した「バーチャルライブ開発プロジェクト」初のオフライ…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000001198.000030268.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/30268/1198/30268-1198-969a4ac9624333fc32631dda5b5bdf2f-1920x1280.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 09:37:51 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>[hololive] Eat Sushi! Adore Mikochi! A Big Chain and Sakura Miko Launch a Delicious and Cute Collaboration! Sushiro × “Sakura Mi...</title><link>https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/entry_418.html</link><author></author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:22:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/top_page.html?q=hololive">VTuber Republic</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>“hololive Indonesia 5th Anniversary LIVE Chromatic Future” Watch Party in Holoearth &amp; Free Partial Release on YouTube</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20251121-03-01/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 11:45:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[November 21, 2025, Tokyo, JAPAN — COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo, Japan, CEO: Motoaki Tanigo) announces that beginning November 23, 2025 12:00 (JST), viewers will be able to enjoy “hololive Indonesia 5th Anniversary LIVE Chromatic Future” through two platforms:
・ A full-version viewing event and watch party via the metaverse platform , and
・ A  on the official hololive Indonesia  channel.This initiative is designed to let even more fans experience the excitement of the anniversary concert firsthand.Chromatic Future – Watch Party in HoloearthA  will be held on , where the  can be viewed in its entirety.
Additionally, a  with  and  is planned during the event period.For full details, please see the links below:
November 23, 2025 (Sun) 12:00 – December 4, 2025 (Thu) 17:59* Schedule subject to change.
1,500 JPY (tax included)■ Special Watch Party Appearances
・ November 24 (Mon) from 22:30 JST – Vestia Zeta
・ November 26 (Wed) from 22:30 JST – Moona Hoshinova
November 23, 2025 (Sun) 12:00 – December 4, 2025 (Thu) 17:59* Schedule subject to change.
Install Holoearth and purchase the in-app item ID Card Case “Chromatic Future” Ver.* Available only on Windows.Chromatic Future – Free Partial YouTube Release
Starting November 23, 2025 (Sun) 12:00 (JST), a partial version of the concert will be available for free on the official hololive Indonesia YouTube channel.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>“hololive Indonesia 5th Anniversary LIVE Chromatic Future” in Holoearth Announcement</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/chromatic_future/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:46:49 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Greetings from the Holoearth Management Team!From November 22nd (Sat), 2025 (PT) “hololive Indonesia 5th Anniversary LIVE Chromatic Future” will be streamed in Holoearth!
During the event period the  of “Chromatic Future” will be available for viewing in the specially prepared viewing area.Vestia Zeta and Moona Hoshinova of hololive Indonesia will also arrive in Holoearth on November 24th and November 26th, respectively!(Schedules are subject to change.)
Anyone can join in the festivities by downloading and installing Holoearth and purchasing the ID Card Case “Chromatic Future” Ver. item in-app.
(Note: Holoearth is available only on Windows.)“Chromatic Future” Watch Parties in HoloearthWe will hold watch parties where the full “hololive Indonesia 5th Anniversary LIVE Chromatic Future” concert can be watched in Holoearth in the specially prepared “hololive Indonesia LIVE Viewing Area”!
Pacific Time between November 22nd (Sat) and December 3rd (Wed) starting daily at:
02:00 PT
06:00 PT
Note: December 3rd at 19:00 is the final showing.
“hololive Indonesia LIVE Viewing Area” in Holoearth.Accessing the Watch Party Viewing Area・Playback timing may vary depending on your system environment.
・To adjust the volume of content playing in the hololive Indonesia LIVE Viewing Area, go to Options (Esc) and adjust the “Media” volume setting.
・Taking screenshots and posting them & impressions on social media is allowed.
・Posting videos without audio up to 30 sec. long on social media is allowed.
・The viewing area cannot be entered without purchasing the “ID Card Case “Chromatic Future” Ver.” item.
・Purchasing the “ID Card Case “Chromatic Future” Ver.” item requires HoloCoin (Premium).
・Purchasing the “ID Card Case “Chromatic Future” Ver.” item allows entry to the viewing area any number of times.
・For the Holoearth streams of Moona Hoshinova and Vestia Zeta, only the free portion of the event will be viewable on YouTube.A new item will be available at the hololive production official shop in HOLOEARTH.
Note: Purchase of this item is required to enter the viewing area.750 HoloCoin (Regular)
(1,500 JPY equivalent (tax inclusive).)
(Schedule is subject to change.)
・ID Card Case “Chromatic Future” Ver.Special hololive Indonesia-themed penlights will also be added, which can be used with gestures to show support in Holoearth!
November 21st (Fri) 05:00 (PT)
(Schedule is subject to change.)
・Penlight Ayunda Risu ver.
・Penlight Moona Hoshinova ver.
・Penlight Airani Iofifteen ver.
・Penlight Kureiji Ollie ver.
・Penlight Anya Melfissa ver.
・Penlight Pavolia Reine ver.
・Penlight Vestia Zeta ver.
・Penlight Kaela Kovalskia ver.
・Penlight Kobo Kanaeru ver.Note:
These penlights are held in both hands when used.
These items cannot be used in the Simulation Room, My Room, or My Shop.Text plate items will also be added that include phrases related to hololive Indonesia talents.
November 21st (Fri) 05:00 (PT)
(Schedule is subject to change.)
・Text Plate Ayunda Risu 1 x 3
(Risu / Risu-chan / Hewrroo / Brrrr / Ohawroo)
・Text Plate Moona Hoshinova 1 x 3
(Moona / Moona (JP) / Moon Moon / MONYAA / Otsumoona)
・Text Plate Airani Iofifteen 1 x 3
(Iofi / Iofi (JP) / Yopi / Otsulonpas / Obisa!)
・Text Plate Kureiji Ollie 1 x 3
(Ollie / Ollie-chan / OTSUCRAZY!! / OHAYOLLIE!! / ZOMBANWA!!!)
・Text Plate Anya Melfissa 1 x 3
(Anya / Anya (JP) / ANYAA / Otsukeris / Yahho—!)
・Text Plate Pavolia Reine 1 x 3
(Reine Ojou-sama / Reine / Reine-chan / Gokigenyou / Ganba-Reine!)
・Text Plate Vestia Zeta 1 x 3
(Zeta / Zeta-chan / Zecretary / o7 / Otsuzeta!)
・Text Plate Kaela Kovalskia 1 x 3
(Kaela / Kaela-chan / Kaela-shin / ELA / Kaello~)
・Text Plate Kobo Kanaeru 1 x 3
(Kobo / Kobo-chan / Kobo (JP) / Moshi moshi! / Lucu Banget!)Note:
Text plates are consumable items.
These items cannot be used in the Simulation Room, My Room, or My Shop.
“Text Plate Kureiji Ollie 1” is the same set that was available during Kureiji Ollie’s Arrival Fest.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>VTuberとしてチャンネル登録者数 世界一(※1)を誇る宝鐘マリン監修！「シーフード豚骨ラーメン」…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000534.000155396.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/155396/534/155396-534-fb983970003a2d076f53a64f17b3c5a1-2302x2441.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 09:18:40 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>デビュー4周年記念！「秘密結社holoX」が『ホロライブごろごろマウンテン』に参戦決定！コラボステー…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000063.000104705.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/104705/63/104705-63-f9d34bdec98e0833b1850c247803183d-1920x1080.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 09:18:40 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】Mori Calliope 3rd ALBUM 『DISASTERPIECE』/ 森カリオペ 3rd アルバム：26年2月6日発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/disasterpiece/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 08:06:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[＜LIMITED “MORIPHEUS” BOX＞・CD(10曲収録)・ブックレット＜LIMITED COLLECTOR’S BOX＞・CD(10曲収録)・アクリルキーホルダー・ブックレット・CD(14曲収録・うち10曲は他形態と同様)・ブックレット]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【再販・予約受付中】ねんどろいど 獅白ぼたん：26年5月発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/botan-nendoroid/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 07:30:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[※期間中は必ずご予約できます。※上記期間をもって販売予定数が決定し、以降は予定数に達し次第受付終了※GOODSMILE以外の通販サイトでは受付期限が異なります]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【再販・予約受付中】百鬼あやめ ねんどろいど：26年5月発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/ayame_nendroid/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 07:30:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[※期間中は必ずご予約できます。※上記期間をもって販売予定数が決定し、以降は予定数に達し次第受付終了※GOODSMILE以外の通販サイトでは受付期限が異なります]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>tsun scoops x hololive English Collaboration Starting on November 23!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20251121-02-11/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 01:50:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[November 21, 2025, Tokyo, JAPAN – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) is excited to announce a collaboration between Californian ice cream parlor tsun scoops and hololive English. This sweet event brings ice cream together with hololive English talents IRyS and FUWAMOCO, as well as a lineup of exclusive merchandise available both online and in-store from November 23 to December 31.During the event, tsun scoops will transform into a dreamy hololive English paradise, decorated with original key visuals of your favorite talent. Three custom flavors inspired by IRyS, Fuwawa Abyssgard, and Mococo Abyssgard will be available for attendees to try, including:: A strawberry sorbet with vanilla ice cream・ Fuwawaffule and Blueberries: Waffle-flavored ice cream with maple syrup and blueberries・ Mococustard Strawberry Parfait: Custard-flavored ice cream with strawberries and granola
tsun scoops, 13137 Brookhurst St., Garden Grove CA 92843
・ Monday-Friday: 2PM-9PM
・ Saturday-Sunday: 1PM-9PM
November 23, 2025 to December 31, 2025
Don’t miss out on exclusive collaboration merchandise featuring IRyS and FUWAMOCO, available on-site during the event as well as online on tsun scoops’s official website. Items include hoodies, t-shirts, acrylic keychains, acrylic standees, and bowls.tsun scoops is a California-based premium ice cream parlor that has built its reputation through several anime and game collaborations. Proud to be an Asian-owned business, tsun scoops combines anime culture and aesthetics with a range of delicious flavors, including dairy-free options.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【発売中】漫画「しらないこと研究会」3話集中連載実施・週刊少年チャンピオン 2025年52号・53号・54号</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/shiranaikoto-rensaisaikai/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 22:33:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[アニメイト特典：しらないこと研究会 ブロマイド(全6種)ゲーマーズ特典：ランダムオリジナルブロマイド（しらないこと研究会／全5種）]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>[hololive] The legendary Budokan live is REBOOTED! Singing out a new setlist with new songs in Yokohama! Hoshimachi Suisei Live ...</title><link>https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/entry_417.html</link><author></author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 15:43:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/top_page.html?q=hololive">VTuber Republic</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME スタートデッキ 「推し Advent」「推し Justice」：26年2月20日発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/holoca-advent-justice/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:39:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[カードゲームは高額商品、中古品、偽物、無断キャンセル、再シュリンク品などトラブルが増えています。Amazon、楽天、Yahooショッピングなど大型通販サイトでは複数の販売元が出品しているため、販売元の実績や評価・販売商品の状態などをしっかりご確認ください。【関連】hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【発売中】セブンイレブン &amp; セブンネット限定 ホロライブ 描き下ろし限定グッズ / 大空スバル / 白銀ノエル / 雪花ラミィ</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/seven-eleven-big3/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:55:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>「ホロライブ」所属 AZKiのライブ映像を、JOYSOUND「みるハコ」で全国のカラオケルームに配信…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000002767.000004747.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/4747/2767/4747-2767-33714ba7f1eb85c2e41fc816192de89b-900x506.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 08:49:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>「hololive DEV_IS」所属ユニットFLOW GLOWのコミカライズが本日11月20日発売…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000003445.000013640.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/13640/3445/13640-3445-250f0eb2fb771c39de7caac3895554da-2040x1375.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 08:49:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>女性VTuberグループ「ReGLOSS」×極楽湯・RAKU SPAコラボを12月11日(木)より開…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000181.000108434.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/108434/181/108434-181-5d020c3b60210ce479f4e98bc9619873-1920x1080.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 08:49:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>From Three-Dimensional Audio to On-Location Recording: Inside COVER’s Voice Pack Projects Showcasing a Different Side of Talents</title><link>https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en/list/3413</link><author>平松梨沙</author><category>COVER</category><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en">COVEREdge Magazine</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[In the Voice Pack Project Team, one staff member takes full responsibility for each project, all the way from the planning stage right through to it going on sale. The process starts with creating a proposal and presenting it internally, and once it gets approved, we send an offer to the talent and move on to developing the script.To go into a little more detail, the staff member in charge also handles things like commissioning jacket illustrations, creating banners for sales pages, and preparing promotional videos and X posts ready for a pack’s release. There are two main ways we offer voice packs roles to talents. The first is a survey-based approach. For large projects that involve many talents, such as Christmas or Valentine’s Day, we send out a survey in advance to see who’s interested in participating.The other way is then, of course, individual offers to specific talents. We regularly watch all of the talents’ streams and look for those who would be a good fit for a particular project we’re planning. Or sometimes it works the other way around – we see something on a stream and realize “Oh, this talent really likes that kind of theme,” and then create a project based on that. ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】ホロライブプロダクション チョコクランチ vol.2：26年3月発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/choco-crunch-vol2/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 23:56:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[全31種よりランダムに封入。食べ応えたっぷりのザクザクの食感がクセになるチョコクランチが新登場！ホロライブのメンバーのデフォルメイラストステッカー付！（種類数は、生産商品全体での総種類数となります。販売商品にはランダムで封入されますので、商品によって全種揃えるために必要な購入数は異なります）（食玩等はコンビニ流通と、当店を含むホビーショップ・量販店流通でメーカー出荷日が異なります。商品によっては、コンビニ店頭に早く並ぶ事もありますのでご了承ください）]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【発売中】AZKi スポーツ報知 2025年11月20日付</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/sports-houchi251120/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 23:07:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【発売中】AZKi スポーツ報知 2025年11月19日付 ぴあアリーナMM特別版</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/sports-houchi-251119/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 23:03:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【発売中】AZKi スポーツ報知 2025年11月18日付</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/sports-houchi-251118/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 23:01:35 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【発売中】Sho-Comi (ショウコミ)2025年 12月 5日号</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/sho-comi-202512/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 22:54:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[FLOW GLOWコミカライズ始動&ポストカードふろくあり！（電子版には付録はつきませんのでご注意ください）]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>[hololive] Congratulations on the 1st Anniversary! Anniversary campaigns celebrating their journey since debut are being held ev...</title><link>https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/entry_416.html</link><author></author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 15:19:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/top_page.html?q=hololive">VTuber Republic</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ver. 1.1.10 Release Notes</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/ver1110_updatenotice/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 07:57:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This is the Holoearth Management Team.Holoearth was updated on November 19th, 2025.■ Voice chat mirroring test release
During events, users will be able hear the voice chat of hololive production talents even if they are not in the same Room via the new test version of the “Voice Mirroring” feature.Applicable areas:
・Focal Square
・Celestial Arena
・Celestial Beach■ New support category for the Holoearth launcher options
In cases where Holoearth does not install correctly, users can now check the relevant error code.
Including this error code when contacting support will allow us to assist more smoothly.1. Avatar Customization Options■ Fixed an issue where “Graceful Eyes” would be displayed incorrectly in purchase history.■ Fixed an issue where the World Quests menu would not open with the U key.■ Other minor fixes to the World Quests system.■ Minor fixes for the launcher.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ × セブン 11月20日より秋のお出かけファッショングッズ登場!</title><link>https://collabo-cafe.com/events/collabo/hololive-seven-eleven-campaign2025/</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 06:26:16 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://collabo-cafe.com/?s=Hololive">hololive collabs in Japan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[大人気バーチャルYouTuber事務所「ホロライブ」× 全国のセブンイレブンにて2025年11月20日よりコラボキャンペーンが実施される。対象商品を購入の方に大空スバル・白銀ノエル・雪花ラミィがデザインされた「ホロライブ A4クリアファイル」からお好きな絵柄を1枚プレゼント!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Wednesday, November 19, 2025 at 1:13 AM EST</title><link>https://warosu.org/vt/thread/106825434#p106825434</link><author></author><category>/vt/ /news/</category><category>VTubers</category><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 06:13:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vt.rita.moe/">/vt//news/</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive production Announces Exclusive Fan Experiences and Live Booth Streams at Anime Frontier, December 12-14!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20251119-hololive-production-announces-exclusive-fan-experiences-and-live-booth-streams-at-anime-frontier-december-12-14-2/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 01:20:40 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[November 19, 2025, Tokyo, JAPAN – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) is excited to announce a series of exclusive activities for fans attending  at the Fort Worth Convention Center in Fort Worth, Texas. The hololive production booth is the first of its kind in the Texas area, and will be the ultimate destination for fans at the event, with a scheduled lineup of live streaming appearances, engaging activities, and special campaigns that can only be experienced at the event from December 12 to 14. The booth will be located at space , with any updates to be posted on official social media channels.hololive production booth at Anime Frontier 2025
December 12th – 14th, 2025
Fort Worth Convention Center
1201 Houston St, Fort Worth, TX 76102
At the hololive production booth, fans will be able to partake in a host of  that will not be broadcasted anywhere else. Participating talents include Airani Iofifteen and Kureiji Ollie from hololive Indonesia; Ouro Kronii, FUWAMOCO, Gigi Murin, and Raora Panthera from hololive English; and Banzoin Hakka, Machina X Flayon, Jurard T Rexford and Octavio from HOLOSTARS English.Attendees can catch their oshis live and in-person as they interact with the crowd and participate in fun activities right on the show floor. Look forward to the full streaming schedule coming soon on SNS!■ hololive Meet Memorial Stamps & Freebies
The booth will also serve as a stop for the hololive Meet campaign. Fans can collect a Free Memorial Stamp as well as a  featuring the latest official illustration for hololive Meet 2025. Additionally, Special Video Messages from this year’s hololive Meet Ambassadors will be played on-site for all attendees to enjoy!An event-exclusive hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME English Edition PR Card featuring the hololive STAGE World Tour ‘25 -Synchronize!- Key Visual will be distributed to booth visitors as a special thank you to hololive production and TCG enthusiasts alike.■ hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME (hOCG) English Edition Experience
Want to learn the ins and outs of the new hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME in English? hololive production has prepared a dedicated space for new players to try their hand at the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME at our booth, where experienced staff will guide newcomers through the gameplay.Participants of our teaching space will receive a “Monthly Tournament Pack vol.1” hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME PR Card Pack, as thanks for joining in.■ holoplus Special Campaign
Attendees are encouraged to elevate their Anime Frontier experience through our official fan app, . Over the weekend, fans will have access to the Anime Frontier Exclusive Corner, available only for the duration of the event.
More information can be found in-app– be sure to check it out and spread your excitement!■ Official Social Media Links
Be sure to keep an eye on Anime Frontier’s official social media accounts to stay up-to-date on any changes and upcoming events with hololive production!About Anime Frontier Presented by CrunchyrollCreated by LeftField Media (the creators of the award-winning largest anime show on the east coast: Anime NYC), Anime Frontier is set in Fort Worth, TX, a city that blends cosmopolitan energy and cowboy culture, Anime Frontier Presented By Crunchyroll brings together the best of the US and Japan for a showcase of what’s next in Japanese entertainment. Featuring some of the biggest guests in anime and manga and leading publishers internationally to Texas, Anime Frontier is three days of exciting exhibits, exclusive premieres, and show-stopping special events. Join us for a convention unlike any other in Texas! For more, visit AnimeFrontier.com.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive production Announces Exclusive Fan Experiences and Live Booth Streams at Anime Frontier, December 12-14!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20251119-01-205/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 01:20:35 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[November 19, 2025, Tokyo, JAPAN – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) is excited to announce a series of exclusive activities for fans attending  at the Fort Worth Convention Center in Fort Worth, Texas. The hololive production booth is the first of its kind in the Texas area, and will be the ultimate destination for fans at the event, with a scheduled lineup of live streaming appearances, engaging activities, and special campaigns that can only be experienced at the event from December 12 to 14. The booth will be located at space , with any updates to be posted on official social media channels.hololive production booth at Anime Frontier 2025
December 12th – 14th, 2025
Fort Worth Convention Center
1201 Houston St, Fort Worth, TX 76102
At the hololive production booth, fans will be able to partake in a host of  that will not be broadcasted anywhere else. Participating talents include Airani Iofifteen and Kureiji Ollie from hololive Indonesia; Ouro Kronii, FUWAMOCO, Gigi Murin, and Raora Panthera from hololive English; and Banzoin Hakka, Machina X Flayon, Jurard T Rexford and Octavio from HOLOSTARS English.Attendees can catch their oshis live and in-person as they interact with the crowd and participate in fun activities right on the show floor. Look forward to the full streaming schedule coming soon on SNS!■ hololive Meet Memorial Stamps & Freebies
The booth will also serve as a stop for the hololive Meet campaign. Fans can collect a Free Memorial Stamp as well as a  featuring the latest official illustration for hololive Meet 2025. Additionally, Special Video Messages from this year’s hololive Meet Ambassadors will be played on-site for all attendees to enjoy!An event-exclusive hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME English Edition PR Card featuring the hololive STAGE World Tour ‘25 -Synchronize!- Key Visual will be distributed to booth visitors as a special thank you to hololive production and TCG enthusiasts alike.■ hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME (hOCG) English Edition Experience
Want to learn the ins and outs of the new hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME in English? hololive production has prepared a dedicated space for new players to try their hand at the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME at our booth, where experienced staff will guide newcomers through the gameplay.Participants of our teaching space will receive a “Monthly Tournament Pack vol.1” hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME PR Card Pack, as thanks for joining in.■ holoplus Special Campaign
Attendees are encouraged to elevate their Anime Frontier experience through our official fan app, . Over the weekend, fans will have access to the Anime Frontier Exclusive Corner, available only for the duration of the event.
More information can be found in-app– be sure to check it out and spread your excitement!■ Official Social Media Links
Be sure to keep an eye on Anime Frontier’s official social media accounts to stay up-to-date on any changes and upcoming events with hololive production!About Anime Frontier Presented by CrunchyrollCreated by LeftField Media (the creators of the award-winning largest anime show on the east coast: Anime NYC), Anime Frontier is set in Fort Worth, TX, a city that blends cosmopolitan energy and cowboy culture, Anime Frontier Presented By Crunchyroll brings together the best of the US and Japan for a showcase of what’s next in Japanese entertainment. Featuring some of the biggest guests in anime and manga and leading publishers internationally to Texas, Anime Frontier is three days of exciting exhibits, exclusive premieres, and show-stopping special events. Join us for a convention unlike any other in Texas! For more, visit AnimeFrontier.com.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ】AZKi、ぴあアリーナMMでソロライブ決定！11月19日開催、チケット争奪戦は必至か！？</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/azki-16/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[女性VTuberグループ「ホロライブ」から、ファン待望のビッグニュースが飛び込んできました！ホロライブ0期生ののソロライブ「AZKi SOLO LiVE 2025 “Departure”」「ぴあアリーナMM」で開催されることが決定しました！「ぴあアリーナMM」は、最大で1万人以上を収容できる巨大な会場です。【AZKi SOLO LiVE 2025 “Departure” 概要】 AZKi SOLO LiVE 2025 “Departure” 2025年11月19日（水） 開場 17:00 / 開演 18:30AZKiの夢と”Departure”に込められた想いAZKiさんは、2018年から活動を続けるホロライブの先輩メンバー。元々は音楽特化のレーベル「イノナカミュージック」に所属していましたが、2022年にホロライブ本隊に移籍し、0期生として活動の幅を広げてきました。AZKiさんの魅力は、と、音楽に対するひたむきな姿勢です。これまで数々の楽曲をリリースし、ファン（開拓者と呼ばれています）と共に音楽の地図を広げてきました。今回のライブタイトルは“Departure”、つまり「出発」を意味します。これは、AZKiさんがこれまでの活動を経て、さらに大きな未来へと一歩を踏み出す、そんな決意表明なのかもしれませんね。「AZKiのソロライブがついに！しかもぴあアリ！？」 「絶対行くしかない！」 「嬉しすぎて涙が出てきた…！」といったコメントで溢れかえり、公式ハッシュタグ「#AZKiと未来へ」がトレンドを駆け上がりました。現地で熱気を体感したい人はこちら！チケットは抽選販売からスタートします。 8月29日（金）20:00 ～ 9月14日（日）23:59 9月25日（木）21:00 ～ 10月5日（日）23:59 10月19日（日）12:00 ～まずは1次先行に申し込むのがおすすめです！期間内に忘れずにローチケのサイトから申し込みましょう。「会場には行けないけど絶対見たい！」という人は、配信チケットがおすすめです。 2025年12月19日（金）20:00まで 2025年12月19日（金）23:59まで視聴可能！アーカイブ（録画）期間が長いので、ライブの後も繰り返し感動に浸れるのが嬉しいポイントですね。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Twitch x hololive production “holoday” New Details Revealed</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20251118-twitch-x-hololive-production-holoday-new-details-revealed/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:55:51 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[November 18, 2025, Tokyo, Japan – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Motoaki Tanigo) is pleased to share new details about the upcoming Twitch x hololive production “holoday” event, taking place on November 20, 2025 (PST).In addition to the main “holoday” celebration, Twitch will host a “VTuber Week” leading up to the event, featuring a multi-day showcase that celebrates the creativity and charm of VTubers around the world, including members of hololive production.
This exciting collaboration between Twitch and hololive productions aims to introduce a wider global audience to the world of hololive talents through exciting streams, custom emotes, and a series of engaging campaigns.VTuber Week (Pre-holoday)Leading up to holoday, Twitch will release a series of unique videos and social posts designed to highlight the diverse talents of VTubers. VTuber Week will launch with a dynamic video featuring VTubers as heroic characters embarking on new and exciting adventures on the platform.Platforms: Twitch front page, Apple App Store, and Google Play
Blog Post: A dedicated Twitch blog will introduce VTuber Week and holoday to users worldwideholoday (November 20, PST)On holoday featured talents of hololive production will take over Twitch’s front page and top shelf with a series of live streams and special appearances.
Fans can join the celebration and earn exclusive limited-time emotes, which includes the return of the popular YAGOO Global Emote.■ YAGOO Bronze/Silver/Gold Emotes (3 types)
Unlockable by watching hololive talents on Twitch (earnable for 24 hours on November 20)
・ Yagoo (Bronze YAGOO): Watch 15mins total
・ Sadgoo (Silver YAGOO): Watch 1 hour total
・ Kingoo (Gold YAGOO): Watch 3 hours totalUsable from November 20 to December 20, 2025 (PST)■ Talent Emotes (16 types)
Unlockable by watching each participating channel for 60 minutes
Earnable from November 20–30, usable until December 20, 2025 (PST)Twitch will also feature hololive production talents across the front page and carousel banners throughout the day, showcasing a large-scale collaboration between the two communities.Event Overview: Twitch x hololive production “holoday”
(Same lineup as announced in the October 29 release, including members of hololive Indonesia, hololive English, and HOLOSTARS English)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Twitch x hololive production “holoday” New Details Revealed</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20251118-01-204/</link><author>Horii</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 07:55:17 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[November 18, 2025, Tokyo, Japan – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Motoaki Tanigo) is pleased to share new details about the upcoming Twitch x hololive production “holoday” event, taking place on November 20, 2025 (PST).In addition to the main “holoday” celebration, Twitch will host a “VTuber Week” leading up to the event, featuring a multi-day showcase that celebrates the creativity and charm of VTubers around the world, including members of hololive production.
This exciting collaboration between Twitch and hololive productions aims to introduce a wider global audience to the world of hololive talents through exciting streams, custom emotes, and a series of engaging campaigns.VTuber Week (Pre-holoday)Leading up to holoday, Twitch will release a series of unique videos and social posts designed to highlight the diverse talents of VTubers. VTuber Week will launch with a dynamic video featuring VTubers as heroic characters embarking on new and exciting adventures on the platform.Platforms: Twitch front page, Apple App Store, and Google Play
Blog Post: A dedicated Twitch blog will introduce VTuber Week and holoday to users worldwideholoday (November 20, PST)On holoday featured talents of hololive production will take over Twitch’s front page and top shelf with a series of live streams and special appearances.
Fans can join the celebration and earn exclusive limited-time emotes, which includes the return of the popular YAGOO Global Emote.■ YAGOO Bronze/Silver/Gold Emotes (3 types)
Unlockable by watching hololive talents on Twitch (earnable for 24 hours on November 20)
・ Yagoo (Bronze YAGOO): Watch 15mins total
・ Sadgoo (Silver YAGOO): Watch 1 hour total
・ Kingoo (Gold YAGOO): Watch 3 hours totalUsable from November 20 to December 20, 2025 (PST)■ Talent Emotes (16 types)
Unlockable by watching each participating channel for 60 minutes
Earnable from November 20–30, usable until December 20, 2025 (PST)Twitch will also feature hololive production talents across the front page and carousel banners throughout the day, showcasing a large-scale collaboration between the two communities.Event Overview: Twitch x hololive production “holoday”
(Same lineup as announced in the October 29 release, including members of hololive Indonesia, hololive English, and HOLOSTARS English)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>VSPO 「Diamond in the Rough」 Release Day!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iEypLZIHGCg</link><author>Linsaloty</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/iEypLZIHGCg?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 03:00:56 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9lFqIDTZbjTwoiPGoBG_zw">Linsaloty</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Find me on X: https://twitter.com/linsaloty
BGM: "Shooting Star" by https://www.youtube.com/@KyattoWorks
"Goodnight" by https://www.youtube.com/@KyattoWorks
VSPO! Related playlist: https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLZA05Mx0fct6YHBVRlDpiVcthQEPMSKgp

▼Related Videos▼
Visiting the VSPO Star Wars Collab Cafe: https://youtu.be/GJBbwrBqlDw

Timestamps
0:00 - Campaigns/promotions in Shibuya and Ikebukuro
4:44 - Unboxing the album
11:58 - Final thoughts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Bye at ID Airport (super quick before boarding soon)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hDwtbLlE4B4</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/hDwtbLlE4B4?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 14:01:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[✨ Support & Follow hwikky
- X (Twitter): x.com/hwikkyofficial
- Patreon: patreon.com/hwikky
- Ko-fi: ko-fi.com/hwikky

#hololive #ホロライブ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【雪花ラミィ】生誕記念3Dライブ『ホロレンジャー』開催決定！今度のラミィはまさかの「ヒーロー」！？</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/ramy-9/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 10:12:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[人気VTuberグループ「ホロライブ」所属の5期生・雪花ラミィさんが、自身の誕生日を記念した生誕3Dライブ『ホロレンジャー』を、2025年11月15日（土）20時より開催することを発表しました。◆ まさかの『ヒーローショー』！？新たな試みに期待高まる！今回発表された生誕記念ライブのコンセプトは、なんと『』！雪花ラミィさん本人も自身の公式X（旧Twitter）にて「生誕3Dヒーローショーライブ（？！）を行います！！」「新たな試みで今から緊張」とポスト。このサプライズな発表に、ファン（雪民）からは「全然予想してなかった！」「ヒーローショー楽しみ！」「面白そう！」といった驚きと期待の声が。告知ポストに添えられたヒーロー風のキリッとしたイラストも「超かわいい！」と話題を呼んでいます。注目の雪花ラミィ生誕記念3Dライブ『ホロレンジャー』は、から配信予定です。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>「星街すいせい」武道館ライブ再演 情報解禁！</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000001192.000030268.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/30268/1192/30268-1192-92496f1df0022ae7ddc454813e5829b6-1920x1080.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 08:20:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>さくらみこ × スシロー全国 コラボキャンペーン 11月19日よりスタート!</title><link>https://collabo-cafe.com/events/collabo/sakuramiko-sushiro-campaign-2025/</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 05:16:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://collabo-cafe.com/?s=Hololive">hololive collabs in Japan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[大人気バーチャルYouTuber事務所「ホロライブプロダクション」に0期生として所属する「さくらみこ」× スシロー全国にて、2025年11月19日〜12月7日までイベント名が開催される。コラボ限定ピック付きおすしや、コラボ限定グッズ付き6貫盛りなど、楽しいコラボが盛りだくさん!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive 兎田ぺこら「声をいっしょに守るぺこ!」コラボグッズ 予約受付中</title><link>https://collabo-cafe.com/events/collabo/hololive-pekora-ninjiom-armabianca-anime-store-goods2025/</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 05:16:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://collabo-cafe.com/?s=Hololive">hololive collabs in Japan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ所属のVtuber「兎田ぺこら」×香港・台湾で親しまれる喉ケアブランド「京都念慈菴 (きょうと ねんじあん)」によるコラボグッズ「声をいっしょに守るぺこ!」が予約受付中。キャンディや枇杷シロップ入りセットやコラボイラストを使用したボイス付きアクスタやぬいぐるみなどが登場。発売は2026年6月上旬予定。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Unboxing VSPO FES Goods before VSPO FES!</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JyMN4nEyv6Q</link><author>Linsaloty</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/JyMN4nEyv6Q?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 03:00:24 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9lFqIDTZbjTwoiPGoBG_zw">Linsaloty</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Find me on X: https://twitter.com/linsaloty
BGM: "Goodnight" by https://www.youtube.com/@KyattoWorks
VSPO! Related playlist: https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLZA05Mx0fct6YHBVRlDpiVcthQEPMSKgp

▼Related Videos▼
Visiting the VSPO Star Wars Collab Cafe: https://youtu.be/GJBbwrBqlDw

▼Related Links▼
Official site: https://event.vspo.jp/vspo-festival-2025/

Timestamps:
0:00 - Intro
0:19 - Acrylic stands
2:17 - Tags
3:08 - Penlight
4:27 - Towel
5:26 - Happi
7:20 - Random cards
13:27 - Plush
14:00 - Final thoughts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>At Indonesia - Night Before holo ID Concert (Can&apos;t sleep)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ima1_xc8_hw</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/Ima1_xc8_hw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:37:18 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[✨ Support & Follow hwikky
- X (Twitter): x.com/hwikkyofficial
- Patreon: patreon.com/hwikky
- Ko-fi: ko-fi.com/hwikky

#hololive #ホロライブ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】星街すいせい New Single 『もうどうなってもいいや』：25年12月24日発売【店舗特典まとめ】</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/suisei-moudounattemoiiya/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:04:41 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[25年12月24日発売（完全生産限定盤：26年3月25日）【通常盤】1,400円【完全生産限定盤A,B】6,000円・CD・CD＋ガンプラセット（HG78＋HG量産型ザク プロパーセット＋星街特製デカールステッカー付き）・CD＋コンチ風アクリルパッケージ03． もうどうなってもいいや（Instrumental）]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】星街すいせい New Single 『月に向かって撃て』：26年1月28日発売【店舗特典まとめ】</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/suisei-tsukinimukatteute/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 13:45:41 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[【通常盤】（ホロプロオフィシャルショップ、全国CDショップなどで流通）・ワイドキャップ・ジャケット（五十嵐正邦書き下ろしイラスト）(初回生産分限定)【完全生産限定盤】（ホロライブオフィシャルショップのみ取扱）・オリジナル・ギターピック・オリジナル・ジャケット A【完全生産限定盤＋通常盤セット】（ホロライブオフィシャルショップのみ取扱）・上記通常特典＋完全生産限定盤特典・セット限定特典 オリジナル・フォトフォルダー(月に向かって撃て ver.)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>[hololive] From cool visual boards to cute mini figures! Experience every bit of their charm! Ichiban Kuji × hololive DEV_IS ReG...</title><link>https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/entry_413.html</link><author></author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 13:28:15 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/top_page.html?q=hololive">VTuber Republic</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【FLOW GLOW】×【カラオケの鉄人】コラボ開催決定！限定コンセプトルームやノベルティ付きメニューあり</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/flow/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 08:38:41 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[「カラオケの鉄人」は、人気コンテンツ「FLOW GLOW」とのコラボレーションキャンペーンを、2025年11月14日(金)より開催することを発表しました。コンセプトルームやオリジナルグッズが登場します。「カラオケの鉄人」の対象店舗にて、「FLOW GLOW」の世界観を存分に楽しめる企画が満載です。最大の注目は、作品のビジュアルパネルやポスターで装飾された「」の展開です。池袋東口店、渋谷道玄坂店、秋葉原昭和通り口店など計8店舗で実施されます。さらに、ノベルティ付きのや、も販売されます。コラボメニューはテイクアウトも可能となっており、カラオケを利用しなくても楽しむことができます。その他、特定の楽曲で高得点を目指す「」も実施されます。◆ 開催は11月14日から！コンセプトルーム予約は11月5日スタート！「FLOW GLOW」と「カラオケの鉄人」のコラボキャンペーンは、2025年11月14日(金)から2026年1月11日(日)までの期間限定開催です（※京都河原町店のみ12月9日(火)から）。注目のコンセプトルームは、より、特設サイトの専用フォームにて予約受付が開始されます。利用料金はとなっています。オリジナルグッズは、2026年1月9日(金)より通販サイトでの販売も予定されています。詳細は「カラオケの鉄人」コラボ特設サイトをぜひチェックしてください！]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ所属VTuber「角巻わため」の好きな景品をラインナップした「特別セレクトフェア」開催が決…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000151.000096364.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/96364/151/96364-151-a1ba2f22f30a6d38602284be79f553c0-1720x900.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 07:38:35 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ、CRSL『シャドウバース』部門に参戦！博衣こより、夏色まつり、響咲リオナらが出場。</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/shadow/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 01:39:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[2025年11月14日（金）に開催される「CR Streamer League Shadowverse」（CRSL）第3節トーナメントの組み合わせが発表され、人気VTuberグループ「ホロライブ」がチームとして参戦することが明らかになりました。今回参戦する「ホロライブチーム」のメンバーは以下の通りです。コーチには氏を迎え、万全の体制でトーナメントに臨みます。トーナメント初戦はCrazy Raccoonかk4sen軍団公開されたトーナメント表によると、全6チームが参戦。他の参加チームには「にじさんじチーム」「Neo-Porte」「ぶいすぽっ！チーム」「k4sen軍団」といった豪華な顔ぶれが揃っており、ホロライブチームが強豪ひしめく中でどのような戦いを見せるのか、大きな注目が集まっています。『Shadowverse: Worlds Beyond』での優勝予想キャンペーンも本大会は、新作『Shadowverse: Worlds Beyond（シャドウバース ワールズビヨンド）』の公式X（旧Twitter）でも告知されています。大会開催を記念し、ゲーム内の「パーク」にあるモニターからSNSに優勝予想を投稿すると、カードパックチケットがもらえるキャンペーンも実施される予定です。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS】が一番くじに降臨！ファン待望のラインナップが11月13日より発売決定！</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/kuji-2/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 14:52:29 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[「一番くじ」の最新作として、「一番くじ hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS」が2025年11月13日(木)より順次発売されることが決定しました！ デビュー以来、快進撃を続ける「hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS」のメンバーたちが、ついに一番くじに登場します。今回発売される「一番くじ hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS」は、VTuberグループ「hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS」のメンバーたちをフィーチャーした、ハズレなしのキャラクターくじです。さらに、購入者を対象とした「ダブルチャンスキャンペーン」も実施が決定。こちらは発売日から2026年2月末日までの期間限定。「一番くじ hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS」は、2025年11月13日(木)より、ミニストップ、一番くじ公式ショップなどで順次発売予定。価格は1回790円(税込)です。また、「一番くじONLINE」では、同日17:00より販売が開始されます。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>[hololive] The streets of Shibuya become a stage! Explore the city and listen to over 30 brand-new voice clips! Enjoy a walking ...</title><link>https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/entry_412.html</link><author></author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:37:43 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/top_page.html?q=hololive">VTuber Republic</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>I am at an Airport to Indonesia</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OsNUyF-875c</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/OsNUyF-875c?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:11:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[✨ Support & Follow hwikky
- X (Twitter): x.com/hwikkyofficial
- Patreon: patreon.com/hwikky
- Ko-fi: ko-fi.com/hwikky

#hololive #ホロライブ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ueda Shuhei, COVER Director, on the Journey Toward Becoming an Essential Presence in the Global Content Industry</title><link>https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en/list/3368</link><author>cover_hirata</author><category>COVER</category><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en">COVEREdge Magazine</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[I believe that our greatest strength lies in the incredible passion of our fans. At hololive production, streaming is at the core of what we do. Those streams ignite enthusiasm among our viewers, which then carries over to music concerts, creating a powerful cycle of energy and connection. At those live events, fans come together again and celebrate a common passion, and that passion continues to spread, building a strong sense of unity throughout the community. The thought of how we can carry that passion forward and make it resonate with fans around the world is incredibly exciting.The atmosphere at trading card game tournaments is a little more subdued than that of live concerts, yet it’s common to see players meeting for the first time start their conversations with a question like, “Who’s your ?”, leading to spontaneous interactions among fans. The more touchpoints fans have with each other in different settings, the more the community grows, and that’s where we see exciting chemistry start to build. It’s precisely because of such incredible passion from our fans that we’re able to explore many different business opportunities to attempt to meet their expectations. We took on a new challenge in the trading card game space last year, and starting next fiscal year, we’ll be launching a full-scale game business as well. By responding to our fans’ desire for new kinds of experiences, and by offering opportunities that differ from what we’ve done before, we’re able to create entirely new ways for them to enjoy and engage with our content. I’ve been in the entertainment industry for a long time, but I’ve never seen this level of passion anywhere else. Meeting fans in person and feeling their energy firsthand is incredibly inspiring for me. That’s why I make a point to attend every live concert I can, and I also try to visit trading card game tournaments and shop events whenever possible.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>iPASS x hololive production “hololive 6th fes. Color Rise Harmony iPASS Card Blind Pack III” available from November 26!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20251113-01-203/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 02:20:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[November 13, 2025, Tokyo, JAPAN – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) has announced a follow-up collaboration with iPASS Corporation (Kaohsiung City, Taiwan; CEO: Keynes Cheng), releasing the third edition of their hololive 6th fes. Color Rise Harmony blind pack series.Following the overwhelming success and buzz generated by the first two blind pack releases, iPASS Corporation continues the excitement with the “hololive 6th fes. Color Rise Harmony Transparent Card Blind Pack III” which features 20 hololive production talents and a secret edition card limited to 1,500 pieces worldwide. The third wave of blind packs will be available exclusively at 7-ELEVEN stores in Taiwan from Wednesday, November 26, 2025, once again satisfying the passionate collecting desires of hololive production fans everywhere.As an official sponsor of “hololive SUPER EXPO 2025” and “hololive 6th fes. Color Rise Harmony”, iPASS Corporation actively brings the charm of virtual talents into everyday life by creating transportation cards that combine both practical use and collectible value.This Transparent Card Blind Pack series is officially licensed by “hololive 6th fes. Color Rise Harmony 2025,” and features exquisite transparent card craftsmanship and unique character-based designs. The collection allows fans to carry and treasure their favorite hololive production talents’ most dazzling stage moments wherever they go.The third installment of the blind pack series features a total of 20 hololive production talents along with one limited secret edition, including: Tokino Sora, Robocosan, Aki Rosenthal, Shirakami Fubuki, Nakiri Ayame, Yuzuki Choco, Oozora Subaru, Ookami Mio, Sakura Miko, Nekomata Okayu, Inugami Korone, Yukihana Lamy, Shishiro Botan, Airani Iofifteen, Anya Melfissa, Vestia Zeta, Ninomae Ina’nis, Gawr Gura, Ouro Kronii, and Nanashi Mumei. This lineup spans multiple generations and branches across hololive production, making it a must-have collection for fans.The highlight of this release is the extremely rare secret edition, limited to only 1,500 pieces worldwide, destined to become a highly sought-after treasure among fans.According to iPASS Corporation, the company continues to deepen its collaboration with hololive production by not only expanding the diversity and reach of transportation card applications and partnerships, but also actively bridging different audiences and market segments, bringing fans even more excitement and surprises through every new release.All hololive production enthusiasts are encouraged to set their alarms and head to their nearest 7-ELEVEN in Taiwan on , to try their luck and bring home their favorite idol card!The iPASS card is a convenient electronic wallet in Taiwan for cashless payments. You can use this small and easy card for many transactions such as for public transport, convenience stores, shops, malls. You can buy various goods and services with the iPASS card.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>AZKi SOLO LiVE 2025 Support Campaign in Holoearth Announcement</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/azkilive/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 08:54:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Greetings from the Holoearth Management Team!From November 12th (Wed), 2025 we are holding a support campaign for AZKi SOLO LiVE 2025 “Departure”!During the campaign period we will feature a street takeover with the “Departure” key visual and sell commemorative Holoearth merchandise, including a digital version of the concert T-shirt. The background music in the area will also change to “Mirai Campanella” and “from A to Z (Re: arrange ver.).”Show your support in Holoearth and post your images with #Holoearth!
(Schedule is subject to change.)
Anyone can join in the festivities for free by downloading and installing Holoearth.
(Note: Holoearth is available only for Windows.)A street takeover featuring the “Departure” key visual, as well as the Re:Start Re:Birth album cover illustration will take place in Alternative City. Users will also be able to take photos with a life-sized standee of AZKi.
The background music in the area will also be changed to “Mirai Campanella” until November 20th at 17:59 (JST) and then to “from A to Z (Re: arrange ver.)” until the end of the campaign period.Street Takeover BGM Period:“from A to Z (Re: arrange ver.)”
(Schedule is subject to change.)“Departure” Commemorative ItemsAZKi SOLO LiVE “Departure” T-ShirtA new T-shirt will be added to the hololive production official shop in HOLOEARTH.
Enjoy this new concert T-shirt in Holoearth!
(Schedule is subject to change.)
・AZKi SOLO LiVE “Departure” T-ShirtA new acrylic panel furniture item featuring the AZKi SOLO LiVE 2025 “Departure” key visual  will be added for decorating users’ spaces!Note:
The owner of a Simulation Room, My Room, or My Shop may place this item.
When purchased the item will be sent to the “Special Items” inventory in worlds where it can be placed.
(Schedule is subject to change.)
・AZKi “Departure” Key Visual Acrylic PanelSpecial AZKi-themed penlights will also be added, which can be used with gestures to show support in Holoearth!
(Schedule is subject to change.)
・Penlight AZKi Type ANote:
These penlights are held in both hands when used.
These items cannot be used in the Simulation Room, My Room, or My Shop.
These are the penlights that were available for purchase for the AZKi Arrival Festival.Text plate items will also be added that include phrases related to AZKi.
・AZKi Text Plate 1 x 3
(AZKichi / AZ-chan / Kon-AZKi~ / Otsu-AZKi~ / Let’s Go!)Note:
Text plates are consumable items.
These items cannot be used in the Simulation Room, My Room, or My Shop.
These are the text plates that were available for purchase for the AZKi Arrival Festival.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>人気バーチャルYouTuberグループ『ホロライブプロダクション』より、「白銀ノエル」が新しい人型プ…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000003043.000025615.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/25615/3043/25615-3043-a087e883d77f4f5c872df2946f2b06bb-571x800.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 06:52:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブプロダクション所属、ホロライブ2期生のVTuber『百鬼あやめ』が巫女衣装で立体化！あみあ…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000003046.000025615.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/25615/3046/25615-3046-df1e66aec0f590838d7438a95b24632f-534x800.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 06:52:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive’s Sakura Miko announces collab with popular sushi chain Sushiro</title><link>https://essential-japan.com/news/hololives-sakura-miko-announces-collab-with-popular-sushi-chain-sushiro/</link><author>James Richardson</author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://cdn.essential-japan.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/Sakura-Miko-Sushiro-collab.webp" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://essential-japan.com/?s=hololive">hololive articles from Essential Japan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A new collaboration has been announced between the popular conveyor belt sushi chain Sushiro and the Hololive VTuber, Sakura Miko.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>カバー株式会社（5253）2026/Q2決算分析 増収減益も営業利益は+10.2%会社予想を上振れ、好悪材料が混在［2025.11.11］</title><link>https://note.com/karuta54/n/na2d12b5b6755</link><author></author><category>karuta54&apos;s notes blog</category><category>COVER</category><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 16:45:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://note.com/karuta54">かるた</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>[Archive] Advent’s Arrival Fest Held in Holoearth on Nov. 6 PT</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/archive_advent/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 09:29:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Greetings from the Holoearth Management Team!On Thursday, November 6th, 2025 (PT), the members of hololive English -Advent- visited Holoearth as their own custom avatar models for a special “Holoearth Advent’s Arrival Fest” event.Streams of the event are archived for all those who are interested in viewing.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>「ホロライブプロダクション」傘下のVTuberグループ「hololive DEV_IS」所属の「FL…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000001195.000030268.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/30268/1195/30268-1195-fadb75762d9ceb955d7b6eb94f8de0a8-1920x1080.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 05:42:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>VTuber 兎田ぺこら＆宝鐘マリン × アバターアプリ『ポケコロツイン』、豪華アイテム＆リアルグッ…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000358.000002505.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/2505/358/2505-358-b161bbfb8e9d218cd6bc34e9ce9aa223-1920x1080.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 05:42:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>コンプティーク12月号は「宝鐘マリン」大特集！本人も驚きの”袋とじグラビア”も</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/marin-24/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sun, 9 Nov 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[2025年11月10日(月)に発売される「コンプティーク 2025年12月号」にて、大人気VTuberグループ「ホロライブ」3期生の宝鐘マリンさんが大特集されることが明らかになりました。本号の特別付録は、「宝鐘マリン 応援キャラスタンド」となっています。本人も反応！「袋とじグラビア」など特集内容も盛りだくさん誌面では、宝鐘マリンさんの魅力を隅々まで詰め込んだ大特集が組まれています。目玉企画の一つである「袋とじグラビア」について、宝鐘マリンさん本人も自身のX（旧Twitter）で「袋とじグラビア！？」と驚きのポストをしています。その他にも、貴重な「自筆プロフ」や「ご本人コメント付き動画紹介」など、盛りだくさんの内容で船長の魅力を余すところなくお届け。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Sunday, November 9, 2025 at 7:47 AM EST</title><link>https://warosu.org/vt/thread/106138000#p106497216</link><author></author><category>/vt/ /news/</category><category>VTubers</category><pubDate>Sun, 9 Nov 2025 12:47:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vt.rita.moe/">/vt//news/</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】FLOW GLOW 1st アルバム『FLOW GLOW』【店舗別特典まとめ】26年1月21日発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/flow-glow/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Sun, 9 Nov 2025 11:55:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[︎発売日：26年1月21日(水)︎日程26年2月8日︎一次抽選(Web)期間25年11月10日(月) 正午12:00 ～ 30日(日) 23:59︎二次抽選(タワレコ渋谷店限定)期間︎TYPE-A（公式オンラインショップ限定）オリジナルステッカーシートhololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME封入（初回プレス限定）︎TYPE-B（全国流通限定）FLOW GLOW オリジナルロゴステッカーアナザージャケット 数量限定ランダムで直筆サイン入り（初回プレス限定）なくなり次第終了①特典：ホログラムトレカ②タワレコ限定早期予約特典：「FLOW GLOW×TOWER RECORDS」キャンペーンポスター︎EC数量限定盤（公式オンラインショップ限定）直筆サイン入りアナザージャケット（1名ランダム）hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME封入]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>SHE IS WATCHING ME...(work)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ICtT_2XsxDc</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/ICtT_2XsxDc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 9 Nov 2025 03:47:46 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[✨ Support & Follow hwikky
- X (Twitter): x.com/hwikkyofficial
- Patreon: patreon.com/hwikky
- Ko-fi: ko-fi.com/hwikky

#hololive #ホロライブ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>渋谷ハル主催「V最協 VALORANT Act2」にホロライブから3名が出場決定！</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/haru/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sat, 8 Nov 2025 15:51:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[人気VTuber渋谷ハル氏が主催する大型eスポーツ大会「VTuber最協決定戦」が、2025年11月9日（日）に「Ver. VALORANT Act2」として開催されます。2025年10月24日に出場全8チームが発表され、ホロライブから、、の計3名が参戦することが明らかになりました。「VTuber最協決定戦 Ver. VALORANT」は、VTuberの間でVALORANTを盛り上げることを目的としたオンライン大会です。 VTuber最協決定戦 Ver. VALORANT Act2 2025年11月9日（日）13:00 開始予定 8チームによるダブルエリミネーショントーナメントホロライブから出場する3名のメンバーと、それぞれのチーム編成は以下の通りです。チーム5には、ホロライブ0期生のが選出。柊ツルギさん、八神ツクモさん、小森めとさん、光葉エニさんといった実力者たちと共に頂点を目指します。チーム6には、ホロライブX（秘密結社holoX）総帥のが参戦。紡木こかげさん、白雪レイドさん、本間ひまわりさんといった豪華メンバーとの化学反応が注目されます。チーム7には、ホロライブ2期生のが出場。叢雲カゲツさん、一ノ瀬うるはさん、小雀ととさん、心白てとさんといった強豪プレイヤーたちとチームを組みます。「最協」の称号を手にするのはどのチームか。大会は11月9日（日）13:00より、大会公式配信ページにて放送予定です。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Visiting the VSPO Star Wars Collab Cafe</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GJBbwrBqlDw</link><author>Linsaloty</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/GJBbwrBqlDw?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 8 Nov 2025 03:00:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC9lFqIDTZbjTwoiPGoBG_zw">Linsaloty</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Find me on X: https://twitter.com/linsaloty
BGM: "Moonside Howl" by https://www.youtube.com/@KyattoWorks
"Party Time" by https://www.youtube.com/@KyattoWorks
"Goodnight" by https://www.youtube.com/@KyattoWorks
VSPO! Related playlist: https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLZA05Mx0fct6YHBVRlDpiVcthQEPMSKgp

▼Related Videos▼
Visiting Shion's Magical Cafe: https://youtu.be/nD6j_bNvF4k

▼Related Links▼
Official site: https://collabo.sld-inc.com/vspo

Timestamps
0:00 - Intro
1:06 - Inside the cafe
3:01 - Foods
6:17 - Final thoughts]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Octopus x hololive Gen 3 Virtual Cards are Available from November 7th!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20251107-01-201/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 7 Nov 2025 05:50:05 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[November 7, 2025, Tokyo, JAPAN – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) has announced a new collaboration between hololive production and Octopus Card Limited, introducing exclusive virtual card images featuring hololive Generation 3 talents: Usada Pekora, Shiranui Flare, Shirogane Noel, and Houshou Marine.This collaboration presents a unique “Next stop, Hong Kong” theme, showcasing four hololive talents in specially designed autumn-winter school uniforms while experiencing Hong Kong’s iconic transportation systems.The virtual card images are now available for purchase through the Octopus Card Image Store　starting from November 7th, 2025, at HK$38 each.In addition to the virtual card images, physical Octopus cards and limited edition merchandise will be released in the near future. Fans are encouraged to stay tuned to official social media channels for upcoming announcements regarding product details and release schedules.Octopus is a contactless stored value card that provides customers with a simple, safe, and secure way to pay. First launched in 1997 across public transport systems, the applications of the Octopus card have since expanded to include retail stores and various facilities, making everyday life more convenient.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ 百鬼あやめ 新作フィギュア 6月発売! 巫女衣装、ぽよ余も付属</title><link>https://collabo-cafe.com/events/collabo/hololive-nariki-ayame-figure-kotobukiya-anime-store-goods2025/</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 5 Nov 2025 23:16:17 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://collabo-cafe.com/?s=Hololive">hololive collabs in Japan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Vtuberグループ「ホロライブ」2期生・百鬼あやめさんの1/7スケール新作フィギュアが、2026年6月に発売される。巫女衣装に合わせた造形の台座に加えて、マスコットキャラクターのぽよ余、愛刀の阿修羅と羅刹、式神の業と不知火も立体化。台座を含む全高は約255mm、価格は27,500円(税込)。発売はコトブキヤ。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>[hololive] Personally Supervised!? Two Cup Noodles Overflowing with the Captain’s Obsession Go on Sale by Lottery! Houshou Marin...</title><link>https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/entry_406.html</link><author></author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Wed, 5 Nov 2025 09:19:51 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/top_page.html?q=hololive">VTuber Republic</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【衝撃告白】白銀ノエル、結婚願望ゼロを断言。「愛は一生続かない」発言の真意と、ファンへの「お嫁さん宣言」が胸アツすぎた。</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/noeru-18/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 4 Nov 2025 16:10:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ3期生の白銀ノエルさんが、先日行った配信での発言が話題となっています。自身の「やりたいこと」について語る中、ポロリとこぼれた結婚観、そしてファン（団員）への想いが「深すぎる」とコメントが見られました。ノエルさんは「」とキッパリ断言！あまりにハッキリとした物言いに、コメント欄も一瞬ざわつきました。さらに団長は「」と持論を展開。「子供とかもあんまりだな」と、結婚や家庭を持つことへの関心が低いことを赤裸々に語りました。（ちなみにウェディングドレスは、過去の企画などで着たので満足しているとのことです）人肌恋しい季節柄、「寂しい」といったコメントや、「結婚なんかしない方がいいよ」というコメントを拾った団長。すると、急に優しい声色で「」と、ファンに寄り添う言葉をかけたのです。「脇で握ったおにぎり食べさせたるから」と、照れ隠しなのか団長らしい脳筋ジョークも飛び出しましたが、この不意打ちの「お嫁さん宣言」に、団員からは「大好き」「団長のこういう所が応援できる」と歓喜の声が上がりました。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>「最新がいいに決まってるじゃん！」大空スバル、獅白ぼたんの助言を無視した結果、高額PCが1年で壊れる悲劇に</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/subaru-71/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 4 Nov 2025 16:01:19 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ2期生のさんが、なんと、購入からわずか1年しか経っていない「高級」最新パソコンが動かなくなってしまったというのです。配信活動の生命線とも言える機材トラブルに、スバルさんは「まだ1年しょ！」と悲痛な叫びを上げました。スバルさんによると、このPCは購入当時「最新のPCにするんだ」と周囲に話していたとのこと。その際、ホロライブ5期生でPCにも詳しいさんから「」と、的確なアドバイスを受けていたそうです。しかし、当時のスバルさんは「」と、その助言を聞き入れなかったと後悔をにじませました。最新PCが動かないため、スバルさんは急遽、昔使っていた「古のPC」を引っ張り出して配信を試みました。すると、そのPCから出てきたのは、なんと「」や、スバルさんが出演したドラマ『四月一日さん家の』のイベント告知など、懐かしすぎるデータばかり。スバルさんも「これ何年前の告知のデータだよ！」と、思わぬタイムスリップに苦笑いしていました。スバルさんは、このPCに最初から入っていた「ムービーメーカー」を使い、マウスで一生懸命オープニング動画を自作していたというデビュー秘話も。ファンからは「エモすぎる」「そのPC大事にして」といったコメントが溢れました。配信中には、ファンから「金はあるんだから新しいPC素直に買って」というコメントも届きました。これに対しスバルさんは、と、改めて悲痛な叫びを上げていました。わずか1年での高額PCの故障という悲劇に見舞われたスバルさん。スバルさんが無事に新しい配信環境を整えられるよう、ファンからは多くの同情と応援の声が寄せられています。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ・儒烏風亭らでん、美術品保護に「私財500万」寄付の噂も。</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/raden-5/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 4 Nov 2025 15:27:02 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[31日の儒烏風亭らでんさんの配信にて「」と切り出しました。これは、東博が実施していた「源氏物語図屏風」の修復プロジェクト。なんと古民家から発見されたもので、猫が引っかいたような生々しい跡も残っており、その修復に費用がかかるとのこと。らでんさんは自身もすでに寄付済みであることを明かしました。ただ寄付を呼びかけるだけではないのが、らでんさんの“ガチ勢”たる所以。らでんさんはと、文化財保護の意義や現状を「知ってもらうこと」の重要性を強く訴えました。この真摯な姿勢と圧倒的な行動力に、ファンからは称賛の声がみられ、一部ファンの間では「らでんちゃん、ポンと500万円寄付したらしい」という驚きの噂も飛び交う事態に。（数百万寄付したと語るらでんさんですが、サイトでは100万を超える寄付をした方は1名のみのため）この熱意ある呼びかけもあってか、このクラファンはその後、無事に目標金額を達成しました。自身の「好き」を原動力に、文化財保護という大きな社会貢献にまで繋げた儒烏風亭らでんさん、その行動力が多くのファンの心を打ちました。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>pixiv×ホロライブインドネシア「hololive Indonesia Art Battle!」開…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000446.000035885.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/35885/446/35885-446-00ef7edcd843d737ecb890af49384133-1200x630.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Tue, 4 Nov 2025 04:43:24 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>「ソースはござる」― ホロライブ風真いろは、自身と同じ”心因性失声症”と闘うリスナーに送ったエールとは</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/kazamairoha/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 4 Nov 2025 02:53:41 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ6期生の風真いろはさんが、自身も経験した「心因性失声症」と現在闘病中のリスナーに対し、自らの体験に基づいた力強いエールを送りました。話題となっているのは、スーパーチャットを読み上げていた場面。そのリスナーは、夏から風真さんと同じ心因性失声症を患っていましたが、「」と報告。この報告に対し、風真さんは「」と祝福の言葉を送りました。「薬がきついのは分かる」 自身の経験を元にした共感風真さん自身、2023年の初め頃に心因性失声症と診断され、一時は配信活動を休止し、筆談でのコミュニケーションを余儀なくされた辛い経験を持っています。リスナーの状況に深く共感し、と、治療の過酷さを隠すことなく語りました。さらに声が戻った後も治療が続くという現実的な厳しさにも言及しました。治療の辛さから「マジでやめたくなる。本当にそう」と本音を漏らしつつも、風真さんはリスナーに向けて最も力強いメッセージを送ります。風真さんは、自身が今こうして配信でスラスラと喋れていることを「ソース（証拠）」として提示。と、同じ病気と闘う「仲間」として、温かくも力強いエールを送りました。また、薬の副作用について「どういう感じできついかは言わんとくわ。風真がこれ言語化して伝えると多分みんな考えたら辛いと思う」と、他のリスナーを思いやる優しさも見せました。このやり取りに対し、動画のコメント欄には感動と称賛の声が溢れています。「『ソースはこざる』って言葉に隊長の強さと優しさを感じました」「精神系の薬って副作用キツくて…それを体現してる風真殿という見本がいるのは同じような病気と闘ってる人にはきっと心強い」「同じ失声症を患ってるかざま隊の皆からしたら、こんなに心強い言葉はないと思う」「絶望的な状況を乗り越えてきたござるさんだからこそ、ものすごく心強さと優しさがある」自身が最も辛い時期を乗り越えた経験を持つ風真さんだからこそ言える「ソースはござる」という言葉は、リスナーにとって何よりのお守りとなったようです。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>VTuber博衣こより、誹謗中傷への切実な訴えに思わぬ声「斜め上すぎる」</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/koyori-13/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 4 Nov 2025 01:31:30 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[「ホロライブ」所属の博衣こよりさんが、2025年11月4日、タレントへの誹謗中傷についてXで切実な想いをポストしました。しかし、その投稿に寄せられた一部の思わぬ反論がありました。こよりさんはまず、「」と投稿。「タレントも1人の人間だからね！」と、心無い言葉を向けられることへの苦言を呈しました。（※自身については「こよはコヨーテだけどね！」と付け加える配慮も見せています。）この投稿に対し、一部から「」という趣旨の反論が寄せられたことを、こよりさん自身が続くポストで明かしました。こよりさんはこの反応に「びっくりしてます」と率直な驚きを示し、「侮辱発言は誰にでも言っちゃいけないに決まってるよ！」と、当然の前提を改めて強調しました。このように、タレントであるがゆえに心無い言葉の標的になりやすい現状を憂い、熟慮の末に発信した言葉であったと真意を説明。「すこしでも伝わるといいな」と結びました。こよりさんの一連の投稿には、多くのファンから共感と擁護のコメントが寄せられています。「どうしてそれほどまでひねくれられるのかわからない」「悲しいかな、こよちゃんの想いを正しく受け止められる人は、最初から侮辱発言なんてしない人たちばかりなんだよな」「そもそも面と向かって言えない言葉は書いちゃダメですよね…」など、寄せられた反論を「揚げ足取り」と指摘する声や、こよりさんの意図は「ちゃんと伝わってるよ」と励ます声が多数を占めました。また、「あんまり精神すり減らさないようにね」「言葉にして伝えてくれてありがとう」と、も多く見受けられました。タレントという立場から発せられた切実な訴えは、改めて「言葉の重み」と、SNSにおけるコミュニケーションのあり方を問いかける形となっています。こよりさんの1stアルバムは現在発売中であり、新曲のミュージックビデオも公開されています。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>星街すいせい＆百鬼あやめが豪華刺繍に！ホロライブ公式ブランド「hololive Connect」新作スカジャン登場</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/suisei-50/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 4 Nov 2025 01:06:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[2025年11月3日、「ホロライブ」は、公式アパレルブランド『hololive Connect』から待望の新作アイテムを発表しました。今回登場したのは、ホロライブタレントをモチーフにした豪華な刺繍が特徴の「スカジャン」です。第1弾として、星街すいせいと百鬼あやめをイメージした2種類のデザインが公開されました新作スカジャンは、それぞれのタレントを象徴するモチーフが背中や胸元に精巧な刺繍で施された、本格的なデザインが特徴です。価格は各22,000円（税込）と、アパレルアイテムとしては高価格帯ですが、情報を見たファンからは「公式アパレルのスカジャン、ええやん」「こういうのは安いものより、しっかりした作りのほうがいい」「自分の推しのモデルが出たら絶対に欲しい」本商品は、『hololive Connect』公式サイトからアクセスできるホロライブプロダクション公式ショップに加えて、全国のアニメイト各店舗でも取り扱いが予定されています。特にアニメイトでは、発売を記念した「ブロマイドプレゼントキャンペーン」の実施も発表されました。近くに店舗がある場合は、特典も併せてチェックするのが良さそうです。さらに、スカジャンと連動し、同じデザインの刺繍が施されたトートバッグや、描き下ろしイラストを使用したアクリルスタンド、ステッカーなどの関連グッズも同時に販売されます。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ「大神ミオ」が明日から活動休止―約2週間のリフレッシュへ「また歩き続けるための休憩」</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/mio-49/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 3 Nov 2025 06:42:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ所属のVTuber「大神ミオ」さんが期間は約2週間を予定して活動休止をするとのことです。リフレッシュと今後の活動について考えるための前向きな休止であると説明しています。大神ミオさんは配信の中で、ファンに向けて自身の口から休止を報告しました。「明日からゆっくりさしていただくという、形になります。」期間については「2週間ちょっとなので」と説明。休止の理由については、これまで精力的に活動を続けてきた中で、一度立ち止まって考える時間が必要だと感じたためとしています。「やっぱ今日までね、ずっと走り続けてきた感覚あるので、ちょっと立ち止まってみたいと思ってます」今回の休止は、今後の活動をより良くするための充電期間であると強調されました。休むと、初心を取り戻すというか、こういうことやりたいなとか、こういう風にした方がいいよなとか気づきもあったりする。これからの活動どんな感じで行こうかなとか色々としっかりと考えたいと思いますまた、休止を待つファン（みおファ）に対しては、」と気遣いました。大神ミオさんは、今回の休止が決してネガティブなものではなく、再び歩き出すためのものであるとファンに安心を呼びかけました。「でも安心してください。これはまた歩き続けるための休憩だと思っていただければ」休止期間中は、リフレッシュや今後の活動について考えるだけでなく、「他の周りのメンバーともね、ちょっと話したりとかしよっかなと」と、ホロライブの仲間とコミュニケーションを取る時間にも充てたい意向を示しました。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>猫又おかゆ、「男性は全員“立って”する」と信じていた！リスナーからの「座るよ」にカルチャーショック</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/okayu-31/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 3 Nov 2025 06:07:35 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[リスナーのお部屋（ゲーム内）を訪問する人気企画「おにぎりゃとリスナーさんのお部屋訪問配信」でのこと。おしゃれな内装のトイレを発見したおかゆさんは、その構造を見て想像を膨らませます。「あ、でも男の人だったら、立っておしっこするとちょうどいいのか。女の子だとね、グッズの方向いておしっこできないんで。」女性目線での感想を述べつつ、男性が使う場合について考察していたところ、コメント欄から「」といった趣旨の指摘が寄せられました。おかゆの純粋な疑問「え、男の人って立つんじゃないの？」このコメントに対し、おかゆさんは心底不思議そうな様子で、長年の“常識”を口にします。「え、男の人って立っておしっこすんじゃないの？座っておしっこすんの？」おかゆさんの中では「男性＝立って用を足す」というイメージが強く固まっていたようで、リスナーの反応に「へえ」と戸惑いを見せました。この純粋な疑問に対し、チャット欄は即座に反応。「座るよ」「人にによるけど、座る派の人多い」「（立つと）汚れるじゃん」といった、“座る派”からの証言が殺到しました。これにはおかゆさんも「へえ、そうなんだ。知らなかった！」と素直に驚き、「え、そうなの？汚れるの？」と、まさにカルチャーショックを受けた様子でした。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ「さくらみこ」、念願の“金コイ”ゲット直後に訪れた「努力値」という新たな地獄が始まる</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/miko-52/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 3 Nov 2025 05:49:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ所属のVTuber「さくらみこ」さんが、ゲーム配信（ポケットモンスター）にて、いわゆる“色違い”のコイキング（通称：金コイ）をゲットした直後、リスナーから育成のための「努力値」という新たな過酷な試練を告げられ話題となっています。長時間の苦行の末、ついに念願の「金コイ」を釣り上げたと見られるさくらみこさん。しかし、喜びも束の間、という、ポケモンシリーズ伝統の育成要素についてリスナーから説明を受け始めます。明かされる「ポチエナ152匹、ケムッソ252匹」という現実リスナーからは、育成に必要な努力値の詳細と、そのために倒すべき具体的なポケモンの数が読み上げられました。コメント「まずポチエナ152匹とケムソ252匹を倒すのお勧めします。」合計400匹を超える特定のポケモンを倒さなければならないという事実に、みこさんは思わず「」と漏らします。しかし、直前まで行っていた「金コイ」ゲットのための膨大な試行回数（”1.3万匹以上”とも言われる色違い厳選）を経験したみこさんは、すぐに独特の“悟り”を開きました。「ちょ待って。1万匹に比べたら誤差でしょ。」 「確かに」「それはそう。」「252匹」という数字を「誤差」と言い切る姿に、コメント欄も「面倒だけど、明確にゴールがわかるから釣りよりはメンタルに優しいよな」「ここでちゃんと努力値振らないと、金コイ縛りの攻略で地獄を見るからね。」「海から解放されて今度は草むらに縛られてるのかよw」一つの地獄を終え、またすぐに次の地獄へと足を踏み入れたみこさんでした。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>“hololive” Artist rurudo’s “FALLEN” Pop-Up Shop Arrives in Osaka and Nagoya</title><link>https://essential-japan.com/news/hololive-artist-rurudos-fallen-pop-up-shop-arrives-in-osaka-and-nagoya/</link><author>James Richardson</author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://cdn.essential-japan.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/rurudo-FALLEN-Pop-Up-Shop-1.webp" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 3 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://essential-japan.com/?s=hololive">hololive articles from Essential Japan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Following a massively popular run in Tokyo this past August that recorded over 20,000 visitors, the "FALLEN" pop-up shop for acclaimed illustrator rurudo is now touring Japan. ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>カバー株式会社 2026年/Q2決算展望 タレント卒業による業績影響は底打ちを想定［2025.11.3］</title><link>https://note.com/karuta54/n/n5e623143e55e</link><author></author><category>karuta54&apos;s notes blog</category><category>COVER</category><pubDate>Sun, 2 Nov 2025 15:30:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://note.com/karuta54">かるた</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[　2025年11月11日にVTuberグループ・ホロライブプロダクションを運営するカバー株式会社（証券コード：5253）2026/Q2決算発表が予定されております。　当記事ではプレスリリースやIR情報などの公開情報を基に、決算における注目ポイントの事前整理や今後の動向を考察していきたいと思います。続きをみる]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ「さくらみこ」、約8ヶ月の激闘ついに終結！ 13,329匹目で「金コイ」をゲットし旅立ちへ</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/miko-51/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sun, 2 Nov 2025 15:27:19 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ｓホロライブ所属のVTuber「さくらみこ」さんが、2025年11月2日、長期間にわたる挑戦の末、ついに「金コイ（色違いコイキング）」のゲットに成功しました。企画開始から28回目、13,000匹を超える試行の末に訪れた歓喜の瞬間に、多くのファン（35P）が沸き立ちました。さくらみこさんがこの企画を開始したのは、この挑戦は、長期間にわたり多くの配信で行われてきました。そして企画28日目となった11月2日、ついにその時は訪れます。出現したコイキングの数は、実に。気の遠くなるような試行回数の末に出会えた黄金色のコイキングに、さくらみこさん本人も、見守っていたファンも大きな喜びに包まれました。「ここからやっと旅が始まる」― 万全の育成で本編へ配信では、捕獲した「金コイ」を前に、さくらみこさんは「ここからやっと旅が始まることとなる」と、安堵と喜びの声を漏らしました。この旅立ちのために準備は万端のようです。このコイキングにはすでに育成アイテムである「タウリンを使い」、さらに「ふしぎのあめも189個持っている」とのこと。最強の「金コイ」（色違いギャラドス）と共に進む本編ストーリーは、「弱点以外、序盤はかなり有利に進むことができるだろう」と予想される旅のスタートとなりそうです。この歴史的瞬間に、X（旧Twitter）などのSNSではファンから爆発的な反応が寄せられました。「みこち本当におめでとう！」「お疲れ様！長かった！」 「ついに旅が始まるの楽しみ！」など、長期間の挑戦を共に見守ってきたファンからの祝福と労いのコメントが殺到し、トレンドを賑わせました。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ角巻わため、ついに「水曜どうでしょう」公式カメラ担当に捕捉される！ 深夜の“ガチ返信会議”の末に送ったメッセージとは？</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/watawme/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sun, 2 Nov 2025 11:03:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ所属のVTuber「角巻わため」さんが、人気番組「水曜どうでしょう」の公式カメラ担当のX（旧Twitter）アカウントに認知されたことが配信中に判明しました。事の発端は、角巻わためさんの配信中にリスナーから「水道（水曜どうでしょう）の公式さんに補足された」という報告が寄せられたことでした。これに対し、わためさんは「え、すごいいい！」「嬉しい！」と、喜びを隠せない様子。喜びも束の間、わためさんは「なんて送ったらいいんだろう？」と、公式アカウントへの返信（リプライ）内容に悩み始めます。ここから、わためさんとリスナーたちによる「返信会議」がスタートしました。など、ファンであることをアピールしつつ丁寧な文章を組み立てていきます。しかし、会議は難航。わためさんは、番組の名言である「」というフレーズを入れたい衝動に駆られます。「大丈夫？距離感大丈夫？これ」 「厳格な人だったら怒られるかもしれない。でもフランクな人だったら怒られないかも。」と、相手の反応を想像して葛藤。リスナーからも「どうでしょうスタッフに硬い人はいない」といった後押しもあり、最終的に「※ネタです。」と注釈を付けることで、このフレーズを採用することを決断しました。最終的に、以下の内容でリプライを送信したことを報告しました。さらに、わためさんは以前から「水曜どうでしょう」のエンディングテーマ曲である「1/6の夢旅人 2002」の「歌ってみた」動画を制作中であることも改めて報告しました。「やります。お楽しみに。」と宣言しつつ、現在の進捗を明かしました。改めて歌詞を読み返したわためさんは、と楽曲へのリスペクトと愛を語り、ファンからも大きな期待が寄せられています。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>戌神ころね、映画デートで「めちゃくちゃイケメン」なエスコートを披露！ みこち「惚れちゃった」</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/mikkorone-3/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sun, 2 Nov 2025 06:07:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[今回、二人が見に行ったのは、世界的に有名なホラー映画『死霊館』シリーズの最新作にして完結編。さくらみこさんが「見に行こうよ」と誘い、戌神さんも「シリーズ見たことある」と快諾したことで、このデートが実現したといいます。二人は「みっころね」というコンビ名で知られ、大型企画「みっころね24」を開催するなど、ファンからもその仲の良さが広く知られています。配信でさくらみこさんが語ったところによると、戌神さんのエスコートは完璧そのものだったようです。まず、映画館に到着すると、。さらに圧巻だったのは、映画鑑賞後の出来事です。なんと戌神さんは、映画後のご飯のお店まで完璧に予約していたのです。これにはさくらみこさんも「」と素で驚愕。「食べ放題ができる」「よりどりみどり」な飲食店を予約してくれていたそうで、そのスマートな振る舞いに「すごかった」「惚れちゃった」と大絶賛しました。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブさくらみこ、誹謗中傷への「覚悟」の声明配信を振り返る。「やってよかった」と心境吐露、HIKAKINの動画に勇気づけられた過去も</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/miko-50/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sun, 2 Nov 2025 06:00:51 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[今回の振り返りの発端となったのは、さくらみこさんが数日前に行った「応援してくれているみなさんと誹謗中傷をしている人へ」と題した配信です。この配信で彼女は、デビュー以来、特にここ数年悪化していたという誹謗中傷について、涙をこらえながら「もう我慢はできません」「やめてください」と強い言葉で訴えました。「悪質なものには個人でも対応していく」と、法的措置も辞さない構えを表明しました。「昨日の配信は、あえてやった行動でもあります。結構覚悟を持ってやった。後悔はないかな」さらに、この「覚悟」を持てた背景の一つとして、トップYouTuber・さんの存在があったことを明かしました。「HIKAKINさんがなんかそういう動画を出してたの。それにすごい勇気づけられたかなと思ってます」これは、HIKAKINさんが過去に自身に向けられた誹謗中傷について語った動画（2024年2月公開「誹謗中傷してる人へ」とみられる）に触発されたものと推測されます。さくらみこさんは、ファンを不安にさせたり、知りたくない情報を見せてしまったりした可能性に触れつつも、「」と、前を向く姿勢を改めて示しました。また、配信後すぐにホロライブのメンバーからも多くの連絡があったそうで、「嬉しかったね」と仲間たちのサポートに感謝を述べました。「昨日の配信は本当に辛かったけど、今日の笑顔が見れて安心した」 「『やってよかった』って言葉が聞けてよかった。ずっと応援してる」 「HIKAKINさんの動画、自分も見た。みこちが勇気をもらえて本当に良かった」 「ホロメンの絆に泣ける。みんなでみこちを支えてるんだな」ファンとホロライブの仲間たち。その温かい関係性があったからこそ、「やってよかった」という言葉に繋がったのではないでしょうか。つらい経験を語った翌日に、「今後は楽しい配信を」としっかり切り替えられるプロ意識。この強さこそが、さくらみこさんが多くの人に愛される理由なのだと思います！]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ鷹嶺ルイ、引っ越し業者に「何かされてる方？」と聞かれ大焦り！ “秘密結社バレ”の危機にファン「裏で消さないとw」</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/rui-20/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sun, 2 Nov 2025 03:39:24 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[「ホロライブ」の6期生「秘密結社holoX」の総帥、鷹嶺ルイさんが、自身の配信にて、新居への引っ越し作業中に起きたヒヤッとするエピソードを披露。引っ越し業者から職業について勘繰られたことを明かしました。事の発端は、鷹嶺さんが10/31に行った雑談配信での出来事でした。配信では「」と安堵の報告から始まりましたが、話はすぐに核心の「業者さんバレそうだった話」へ移ります。■「何かされてる方なんですか？」 業者からの“直球質問”鷹嶺さんによると、おそらく新居の豪華な様子や、運び込まれる荷物（配信用の機材や新調した昇降デスクなど）を見た業者から、「」と、その職業についてストレートに尋ねられてしまったとのこと。これに対し鷹嶺さんは、配信で「まずい、まずい」と当時の焦りを再現。表の顔はVTuberにとって、正体がバレることは一大事です。VTuberであるという正体がバレそうになった危機的状況を、「リモートワークです」と濁して回答したようです。コメント欄は、「今時そんな事聞いたらアカンぐらいわかんないかね引越し業者さんよ」 「証拠隠滅しないとｗ」 業者さんも「何かされてる」とは察するでしょうが、まさか「ホロライブ」とは夢にも思わないでしょうね（笑）]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ 白銀ノエル 組み立てて楽しむプラモデル PLAMATEA 6月発売</title><link>https://collabo-cafe.com/events/collabo/hololive-shirogane-noel-plamatea-anime-store-goods2025/</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sat, 1 Nov 2025 22:38:13 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://collabo-cafe.com/?s=Hololive">hololive collabs in Japan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[大人気VTuber(バーチャルYouTuber) グループ『ホロライブプロダクション』の第3期生「白銀ノエル」がフル可動プラモデルになって登場する。全高約160mmの組み立て式モデルで、価格は税込9,800円。マックスファクトリーの可動プラモデルシリーズ「PLAMATEA」より、2026年6月発売予定。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Come in and Ask Me Questions (+ BIBOO 3D REACTION)</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1ziLQU-W7qE</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/1ziLQU-W7qE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 1 Nov 2025 17:33:12 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[BIBOO 3D STREAM LINK: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WfGS8QW-b40

✨ Support & Follow hwikky
- X (Twitter): x.com/hwikkyofficial
- Patreon: patreon.com/hwikky
- Ko-fi: ko-fi.com/hwikky

#ROCKINbiboo
#hololive #ホロライブ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>猫又おかゆ、自身のゲームに「野球拳」実装をゴリ押し。CERO Cでの実装は十数年ぶり!?</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/okayu-30/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sat, 1 Nov 2025 14:41:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[所属の人気VTuber・さんが、お休み明けの雑談配信にて、2026年2月26日発売予定の自身のノベルゲーム『おかゆにゅ～むR』に、ミニゲームとして「」が実装されることを共有しました。事の発端は、おかゆさんがお休み明けに行った雑談配信でのこと。2026年2月26日に株式会社エンターグラムからリリース予定の自身のゲーム『おかゆにゅ～むR』の更新情報について触れた際、新たに追加されるミニゲームの詳細が明かされました。「にゃふにゃふタイム」といった可愛らしいミニゲームが並ぶ中、ひときわ異彩を放っていたのが「」でした。ホームページには「じゃんけんに勝つたびにおかゆが服を1枚ずつ脱いでいくドッキドキのミニゲーム」と説明されており、この時点で多くのリスナーがざわつきましたが、実はおかゆさん自らが強く要望したものだったと告白。僕からエンターグラムさんに、井の一番に言いました。「野球拳やらしてください！」って」なんと、おかゆさん側からの熱い提案だったことが判明。さらに驚くべきは、です。おかゆさん自身も調査したようで、「」と語り、「そういう意味ではかなりね挑戦的なミニゲームなのかなと思います」と胸を張りました。「令和のゲームで野球拳は聞いたことなさすぎるｗ」「CERO Cでどこまで脱ぐんだ…」まさか令和のコンシューマーゲーム（※CERO審査がある）で「野球拳」の文字を見ることになるとは…！おかゆさんの「やりたい」を本当に実現しちゃうエンターグラムさんとカバーさんの懐の深さに脱帽です（笑）。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>大空スバル、Tシャツが発光して恥ずかしい思いをする。暗闇レッスン＆タクシーで輝きすぎて、運転手も困惑</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/subaru-70/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sat, 1 Nov 2025 14:25:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ所属のVTuber、大空スバルさんが、2025年11月1日の配信にて、多忙なスケジュールの中で起きた「面白すぎるハプニング」を語りました。ストレス発散のために選んだ「夜に光るTシャツ」が、予想外の場面でその能力を発揮。レッスンスタジオやタクシーの車内で強烈な光を放ってしまったエピソードに、ファンからは「一発目からおもしろエピソード過ぎるw」「持ってるなぁw」などの声が相次ぎました。事の発端は、ホロライブ2期生の大空スバルさんが抱える「多忙によるストレス」でした。スバルさんには「忙しくなると変なTシャツを着ることでストレスを発散する」という独特の習慣があるとのこと。今回、ダンスレッスンに着ていく服として、「烈海王のTシャツ」か「夜に光るTシャツ」の二択で悩んだ末、「」という理由で後者を選択。しかし、レッスンは昼から始まるため、「」と、完全に油断していたと語ります。運命の瞬間は、レッスンの最後に訪れました。ストレッチのため、先生が「リラックスするために部屋の電気消すねー」と照明を落とした瞬間、スバルさんのTシャツが「パァーーー！！」と強烈に発光。真っ暗なスタジオで、スバルさんだけがスポットライトを浴びる形となってしまいました。さらにレッスンが終わり外に出ると、季節は秋、夕方でも外はすでに真っ暗。隣にいたスタッフさんから「光ってます」と冷静に指摘され、恥ずかしくなったスバルさんはすぐにタクシーに乗り込みました。しかし、「」というスバルさんの言葉通り、Tシャツは車内でさらに「めっちゃ光って」しまい、運転手さんから「」と、バックミラー越しに怪訝な視線を浴び続ける事態に。この一連の「輝かしい」エピソードに対し、スバルさんはリスナーに向けてお前らあんまり蓄光Tシャツ着ない方が良いぞ今の季節「バックミラーチラチラは草」「太陽少女が蓄光少女へ」「もっと光れスバル」運転手さん、バックミラーに光る乗客が映ったら、そりゃ二度見しますって！怖すぎます（笑）]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>I Fly the World-First VTuber Airplane 【 hololive &quot;ita-plane&quot; 】</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FIQRRagRZsc</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/FIQRRagRZsc?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 1 Nov 2025 13:48:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[🍹 hololive production Cheer UP Pop-up Cafe is now OPEN! 🍰
- From October 18th to December 06th
- At ARCANE CAFE in LA (171 Live Oak Ave Suite D, Arcadia, CA 91006)
- hololive-themed space inside the Cafe
- Exclusive merch, food, drinks, and giveaways
✨ More details here: https://arcanecafe.com/hololive/

+ hololive production Cheer UP FUN RUN: https://x.com/hwikkyofficial/status/1964161634101793214
Go and cheer the hololive fans joining as runners!

⭐ Please follow and support hwikky!
Twitter - https://twitter.com/hwikkyofficial
Patreon - https://www.patreon.com/hwikky
ko-fi - https://www.ko-fi.com/hwikky

#PR #hololiveproductionCheerUPCafe
#hololive #ホロライブ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ鷹嶺ルイ、「ホロリス界隈、心狭すぎ」との“ファン”の嘆きに「それはごく一部だから」と断言！ 「マジで正論」「スカッとした」</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/rui-19/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sat, 1 Nov 2025 09:25:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ6期生「秘密結社holoX」の幹部・鷹嶺ルイさんが、自身の配信中にリスナーから寄せられた「ホロリス（ホロライブリスナー）界隈の空気感」に関する相談に答弁。一部の過激な意見に萎縮するファンに向けた彼女の毅然とした、しかし愛のあるメッセージが、大きな反響を呼んでいます。事の発端は、鷹嶺さんの雑談配信中に読み上げられた、あるリスナーからのお便りでした。その内容は、「」という問題提起から始まります。相談者によると、「単推し（特定のタレント一人を集中的に応援するファン）でなければソロライブに応募してはいけない」「ゲスト目当てでライブに来るな、推しの人に席を譲るべき」といった趣旨の投稿をSNSなどで目にする機会があり、「」である自身は非常に片身が狭い思いをしている、と胸の内を明かしました。ホロライブのような大手事務所では、タレント個人を応援する「単推し」と、事務所全体を応援する「箱推し」が共存しています。しかし、人気のライブチケットともなると、こうした一部の過激な意見が目立ってしまうこともあるようです。この切実な相談に対し、鷹嶺さんは「」と前置きしつつも、そうした意見が存在することは認め、「中にはいるでしょう」と理解を示しました。そして、今回の核心とも言える見解を次のように述べます。「正直に言うとネガティブな言葉を言う人って声がでけんだよ。何も思ってない人は言わないわけだからこそ、文句を言ってる人だけがあの目立つようにできてる。多分そう思ってる人って、ごく一部だと思うし、気にしなくていいと思いますよ」さらに「」と具体的な数字まで挙げ、過激な意見は少数派に過ぎないと断言しました。鷹嶺さんは「」と、ファンの自由な楽しみ方を全面的に肯定。「」と、TPOや他者への配慮の重要性も付け加えました。「ルイ姉が『ホロリス界隈ではなく、ごく一部』って断言してくれて本当に安心した」 「『声がでけぇだけ』はネットの真理」「推し本人から『気にするな』って言われるのが一番効く」ネット上のネガティブな意見は、どうしても目立ちがち。当事者であるタレント本人、それもホロライブという巨大なコンテンツの中心にいる鷹嶺さんが「ごく一部」「5%もいない」と断言してくれたことは、ファンにとって何よりの“お墨付き”になります。これ、本当に大きい。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【HMV＆BOOKS SHIBUYA】オープン10周年を記念し、店舗リニューアル！「お客様がエンタメ…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000000595.000034304.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/34304/595/34304-595-93fde1c12c7aed25e60656c2d8bb2b7d-2243x1785.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 1 Nov 2025 04:18:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>大人気バーチャルYouTuberグループ『ホロライブ』より、ホロライブ0期生「星街すいせい」がセーラ…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000003023.000025615.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/25615/3023/25615-3023-4780196045d09e27e85bfc49a69942ac-600x800.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 1 Nov 2025 04:18:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Tokoyami Towa 2nd Live &quot;SHINier&quot; のオフィシャルレポート公開！@有明…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000001191.000030268.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/30268/1191/30268-1191-ad0dae96272932f4a175af115ab6339b-3900x2194.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sat, 1 Nov 2025 04:18:26 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ロボ子さん、食わず嫌いをまさかの克服！来訪中の”沖縄ガール”の手料理に「作り置きしておいて」と懇願。</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/roboko-4/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Sat, 1 Nov 2025 04:04:52 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ0期生所属のVTuberが、自身のX（旧Twitter）アカウント（@maybe_robochan）にて、自宅に滞在中の「沖縄ガール」に作ってもらったゴーヤチャンプルで、長年の食わず嫌いを克服したことを報告しました。事の発端は、ロボ子さんが「」とポストしたこと。「え、ゴーヤ美味しいかも」 食わず嫌いを克服した手料理今回、特に注目を集めたのは投稿の後半部分。沖縄ガールが振る舞ったであろう、沖縄の家庭料理「ゴーヤチャンプル」に関する記述です。初めてゴーヤチャンプルが美味しいと思いました(食わず嫌い)(え、ゴーヤ美味しいかも)(帰る前に作り置きしておいて)ロボ子さんはこれまでゴーヤチャンプルを食わず嫌いだったようですが、”沖縄ガール”特製の一皿をきっかけに「」と、その魅力に目覚めた様子。最後には「(帰る前に作り置きしておいて)」と、素直すぎるリクエストを添えており、よほど気に入ったことが伝わってきます。「泊まりに来てる」じゃなくて「住み着いている」と表現するところに、もはや家族レベルの信頼関係を感じてしまいますね！]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブさくらみこ、”事実無根のリーク”と赤井はあと休止関連の憶測に「我慢の限界」と語る</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/miko-49/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:09:37 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ所属のVTuber、さくらみこさんが自身の配信チャンネルにて、「応援してくれているみなさんと誹謗中傷をしている人へ」と題した緊急配信を実施。先日の赤井はあとさんの配信内容に便乗した一部の悪質な憶測や誹謗中傷に対し、「」と強く抗議しました。また、自身が長年、”“による攻撃を受けていたことも明かしました。ことの発端は、さくらみこさんは赤井はあと（はあちゃま）さんの活動休止が公式から発表されたことでした。さくらみこさんは配信内でこの件に触れ、この発表に伴い、事実無根の憶測を立てて赤井さんを利用し、さくらみこさん自身や他のタレントを攻撃する悪質な行為が横行していると説明しました。さらに、さくらみこさんは今回の件に限らず、自身がデビューからの約5年間、継続的にによって攻撃を受けてきたという事実を告白。ここ2年ぐらいはあまりにもひどい名誉毀損の日々だったと、これまで表に出さなかった苦悩を明らかにしました。さくらみこさんは「真剣な話をします」「（緊張で）手が震えている」と、時折声を詰まらせながらも、運営の許可を得た上で自身の言葉で強く訴えかけました。もう我慢をしているだけでは何も変わんないんじゃないかなと。今回の件についてはもう我慢はできません。と、毅然とした態度で表明。そして、「誹謗中傷はやめてください」と涙ながらに絶叫し、「」と、ファンへの感謝と共に、これまで耐え続けてきた胸の内を吐露しました。さくらみこさんは、赤井さんに対して「」と思いを語り、改めて「本当にやめてください」と強く釘を刺しました。配信の最後には、と、辛い告白の後でも前を向く姿勢を見せました。この勇気ある配信に対し、コメント欄やSNSではファンから、 「みこちが泣いてるの辛すぎる」 「勇気を出して話してくれて本当にありがとう」 「悪質なデマを流す奴らは絶対に許さない」 「みこちは悪くない、ずっと応援してる」 といった、励ますコメントが溢れかえりました。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>戌神ころね、本垢で野球実況を誤爆する。慌てて「裏垢消しました」と報告</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/%e3%81%93%e3%82%8d%e3%81%ad/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:57:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[人気VTuber事務所「ホロライブ」所属のが、2025年10月30日夜、自身のX（旧Twitter）本アカウントにて、野球実況を誤って投稿するハプニングが発生。直後にアイドルらしい投稿へ軌道修正し、さらに後日の配信で「間違いすぎるので」当該の裏アカウントを削除したと報告しました。事の発端は、プロ野球の日本シリーズ（阪神戦）で盛り上がっていた10月30日の夜。以前から阪神タイガースファンを公言している戌神さん。しかし、試合が白熱したためか、戌神さんは裏アカウントと本アカウントを間違えてしまったようです。同日午後7時5分、戌神さんの本アカウント（@inugamikorone）から「」と、熱心な野球ファンそのものの緊迫感あふれるポストが投下されました。これにはファンも即座に反応。「ころさんまた本垢で野球実況してるやんw」「キャラ完全に忘れとるやんw」「ころさん流れおじさんになってて草」と、タイムラインが溢れかえりました。その喧騒から約18分後、午後7時23分。戌神さんは「」と投稿。ここでようやく、アカウント間違いに気づいたとみられます。誤爆に気づいた戌神さんの対応は迅速でした。わずか5分後の午後7時28分には、」と、いつものアイドルらしい、いわゆる「キラキラポスト」へ完璧に軌道修正。この見事なまでの切り替えに対し、ファンからは「急にキラキラポストになって草」「ころさん正気に戻った…」「今まで気づいてなかったんかいwww」と、さらなるツッコミが殺到しました。さらに後日、11月1日の配信ではこの件について自ら言及。「（本垢と裏垢を）間違いすぎるので裏垢消しました」「使い分けできないアカウントはね、持っちゃだめ。本当に」と、反省しつつ野球用の裏アカウントを削除したことをファンに報告しました。誤爆に気づいてから、わずか5分でアイドルモードの「キラキラポスト」に切り替えた手腕は、さすがプロ根性を感じますね（笑）]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【ホロライブ】赤井はあと、体調不良で活動休止。運営は「いじめは曲解」「法的措置も」</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/haato-3/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 15:14:40 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブプロダクション所属のVTuber、が体調不良により、当面の間、活動を休止することが発表されました。所属事務所のカバー株式会社は、本人のご家族と協議の上で決定したと報告。同時に、休止の背景にある赤井さんの発言をめぐる「不適切な風説の流布」や、他の所属タレントへの誹謗中傷に対し、法的措置を含む断固たる措置を講じると強く警告しました。今回、活動休止を発表した赤井はあとさんは、2018年6月にデビューした。「はあちゃま」の愛称で親しまれ、その独特な世界観と予測不能な配信スタイルで、国内外に多くのファンを持つタレントです。カバー株式会社の発表によると、今回の休養は「」したもの。しかし、この休養の背景として、赤井さん本人の配信内での発言を一部の第三者が切り取り、「」が行われている状況があったと指摘されています。運営は、この「風説の流布」について、極めて強い言葉で警告を発しました。「特に、いじめが行われているというような表現については配信での発言を曲解しミスリードを生むものが多く散見されております。」このように、「いじめ」という憶測を明確に「曲解」「ミスリード」であると否定。さらに、当該配信（現在は非公開）で名前が挙がった他のタレントに対しても、情報の恣意的な解釈や攻撃的な言動、誹謗中傷が行われていることを確認しているとし、以下のように断じています。「これらの行為は、タレントの名誉や心情を著しく傷つける行為であり、到底看過できるものではございません。」 「（中略）発信者情報開示請求や訴訟等の法的措置を含め、民事・刑事の両面での断固たる措置を講じてまいります。」当該配信の発言については、「本人の精神的状態が不安定であった中での発言であると認識しております」と説明。関連するコピー動画の削除対応も進めているとのことです。赤井はあとさん本人のX（旧Twitter）アカウントからも、担当マネージャー名義で休養が報告されました。これら一連の発表に対し、ファンからは多くの反応が寄せられています。「まずは、はあちゃまの体調が第一。気に病まず、ゆっくり休んでください」「運営が『法的措置』と強く言ってくれて安心した。タレントを守ってくれ」今回の声明は、タレントの休養報告であると同時に、憶測による誹謗中傷の連鎖を断ち切ろうとする運営の強い意志が示された形となりました。 ファンとしては、まず「はあちゃま、お大事に」の一言に尽きます。休養は寂しいですが、ご家族と相談した上での最善の判断だと思います。私たちができるのは、憶測に惑わされず、元気に戻ってくる日を静かに待つことだけですね。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>獅白ぼたん、初の逆凸で奇跡が発生！一条莉々華とAZKi、まさかの「ラーメン企画」が一致！</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/botan-6/</link><author>風歌</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:51:44 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ5期生の獅白ぼたんさんが、自身初となる逆凸配信を実施しました。今回のトークテーマは「」というシンプルなもの。しかし、トップバッターの一条莉々華さんと、2人目のAZKiさんから、まさかの奇跡的な回答が飛び出しました。まず最初に逆凸の相手となったのは、ホロライブのユニットReGLOSSのメンバー、一条莉々華さん。「獅白ぼたんと一緒にやりたいこと」を聞かれた莉々華さんは、元気よくこう答えました。ラーメン配信一緒にしたいなって思ってるんですよね！一見、普通の料理配信かと思いきや、その内容はかなり個性的。「インスタントラーメンから色んな具材を入れて作っても良いし、出汁を考えてイチから作る本格的なものでも」と幅広く考えている様子。もうあれでしょ?「じゃ、あごだしを取りに海に行きます」とか言って釣りに行くか「」と名付けられたこの企画は、もはや料理配信というより、過酷なロケ企画の様相を呈していました。また、一緒に限界ラーメン作って、【獅白ぼたん監修】って言葉をつけることでと、最終的に獅白さんが！とハラハラする様子が見受けられました。続いて2人目の逆凸相手となったのは、0期生のAZKiさん。獅白さんは、AZKiさんにも同じく「獅白ぼたんと一緒にやりたいこと」を質問。すると、AZKiさんから返ってきた答えは…GeoGuessrで！して、そこにししろんと行きたいです。なんと、AZKiさんもに関する企画を提案！AZKiさんの提案は、「有志の方が作った『人気ラーメン屋マップ』を使ってGeoGuessrで遊び、当てたお店に実際に一緒に行きたい」というものでした。AZKiさんはラーメンのロケのナレーションとかもねAZKiさせていただきましてと発言。獅白さんがラーメン紹介配信をした際に、ナレーションを担当したことがあることからAZKiさんの企画提案のキッカケになったようです。と配信の冒頭で宣言しました。しかし、トップバッターの一条さんから「限界ラーメン作り」という提案が来た直後に、AZKiさんからも「ラーメン屋GeoGuessr」という提案が来たことに、獅白さんも思わず爆笑。獅白さんは、どちらの企画にも「」とを見せており、今後のコラボ配信の実現に大きな期待が高まりました。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>「最下位はらでん」の予想を覆し3位！儒烏風亭らでんが明かした、体力王シャトルラン直後の「カットされた魂の叫び」</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/raden-4/</link><author>風歌</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:20:36 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ所属の儒烏風亭らでんさんが、雪花ラミィさん主催の「第3回ホロライブ体力王決定戦」に出演。多くのファンから「最下位だろう」と予想される中、なんとに輝きました。しかし、この結果の裏で、感動的なシーンが「カット」されていたことを明かしました。シャトルラン100回直後、倒れ込んだらでんに「無慈悲な要求」が…最も過酷な競技「シャトルラン」で100回という記録を達成した直後、儒烏風亭さんは。すると、すかさずスタッフがカンペを持って現れ、と要求したといいます。息も絶え絶えの中、「」と思いながらも儒烏風亭さんはこれが…普段の…レッスンの成果です！12月16日有明アリーナで待ってるからな！と振り絞りってと自身が所属するユニット「ReGLOSS」のライブ告知をカメラに向かって放ちました。しかし、命からがら叫んだ渾身の告知は、残念ながら配信では使われなかったそうです。事前の優勝予想では「どう考えても1番下にはらでんがいるはず」「ゴスロリ衣装だから活躍できないだろう」という声が圧倒的だったといいます。これには、儒烏風亭さんも「」と、笑いながらも怒りをあらわにしました。また、このイメージは、ことも一因のようです。普段はですね、ReGLOSSの他の面々が体力お化けなんです。「」と自称する儒烏風亭さんですが、今回の体力王ではそのイメージを覆します。競技4種目のうち、「ぶら下がり」「イストリゲーム」「尻尾取り」の3種目までは、事前の予想通り最下位に近い結果でした。 しかし、最後のシャトルランで驚異の粘りを見せ、。ここで一気にポイントを稼ぎ、のです。儒烏風亭さんは、体力王の事前インタビューでと、かなり強気な発言をしていたことも告白。前半戦の不調により、ことも笑いながら振り返りました。それでも、大人になってから全力で運動する機会は貴重だったようで、服装が変われば確実にを取れるんじゃないかなと思いますと語り、来年の体力王への意欲ものぞかせていました。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>「魔法少女ホロウィッチ！THE STAGE 〜TRICK or MAGIC！〜」10月31日(金) 公開決定！ ホロライブ公式YouTubeにて</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/witch-5/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 13:30:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブのメディアミックス企画「魔法少女ホロウィッチ！」の新たな展開として、「魔法少女ホロウィッチ！ THE STAGE 〜TRICK or MAGIC！〜」が、2025年10月31日(金)のハロウィン当日に公開されることが決定しました。本作は、ホロライブ公式YouTubeチャンネルにてプレミア公開される予定です。出演者には、ホロライブから天音かなたさん、さくらみこさん、姫森ルーナさん、宝鐘マリンさん、白上フブキさん、雪花ラミィさんの6名。さらに、オリジナルキャラクターのアエル役を高橋李依さん、ラグ役を悠木碧さんが務めます。また、スペシャルゲストとして、ホロキャス配信者・大神ミオ役として大神ミオさん、人気歌手・カノン役として東山奈央さんの出演も発表されており、豪華なキャスト陣による舞台に期待が高まります。「魔法少女ホロウィッチ！ THE STAGE 〜TRICK or MAGIC！〜」概要]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>一条莉々華、後輩を食事に誘えない悩みを告白！「優勝商品のお寿司」を前に「プンプン」されて決意</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/ririka-4/</link><author>風歌</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 11:28:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ所属の一条莉々華さんが自身の配信で、FLOW GLOWの綺々羅々ヴィヴィさんとの「ある約束」をめぐるエピソードを語りました。約束とは「お寿司をご馳走すること」。しかし、なかなか実行に移せない一条さんは、スタジオでばったり会った綺々羅々さんから、可愛く催促されてしまったようです。以前、スタジオで偶然、綺々羅々ヴィヴィさんと遭遇した一条さんは、以前から約束していたお寿司にまだ行けていないことを謝りました。すると、綺々羅々さんは可愛らしく怒った様子を見せたといいます。あ、先輩って言いながら来てくれて、その時に「まだお寿司行けてないよね。ごめんね」って言ったら『本当ですよ先輩。プンプン！』って怒っててめっちゃ可愛かった。一条さん曰く、実際に「プンプン」と言ったかは定かではありませんが、でした。今回はただの食事の誘いではなく、以前莉々華さんが主催した大会で、綺々羅々さんが見事優勝した際の「優勝商品」だったのです。一条さんは、「綺々羅々さんが長時間配信とかもしてたから忙しいかも」と忙しさを理由にしていましたが、本当の理由は別にあると白状します。そうだよね。莉々華が誘わなきゃだよね。やばい。ちょっと頑張ろう。結構誘われ待ちなとこあるからさ。自分から誘うのあんま得意じゃなくて。一条さんは「」で、「」してしまうタイプ。そのため、先輩として、しかも優勝商品としてようです。と、自身の。一条さんは配信中にリスナーからの応援も受け、ついに決意を固めました。先輩たちにたくさん美味しいものをご馳走してもらってるんだから、莉々華だってちょっと。 これは単なる食事ではなく、大会を頑張ってくれた後輩への「」だからこそ、「ケチっちゃいけない」と、回らないお寿司屋さんなども視野に入れ始めた一条さん。さらに、この一件をきっかけに、綺々羅々さんだけでなく、他の後輩とも自分から積極的にご飯に誘っていきたいと、前向きな一面を見せました。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ夏色まつり、「ホロを辞めるタイミング」を激白→「1期生が全員いなくなったら」「クビになるか」</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/matsuri-7/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 09:48:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ所属の1期生VTuber・さんが、自身の配信（【PowerWash Simulator 2】寝れないなら洗おう。より）にて、「ホロライブを辞めるタイミング」について赤裸々に語りました。「（1期生が）全員いなくなったら」「首になるか」など、ドキッとするような具体的な条件を挙げたかと思えば、自身の叶えたい「夢」についても熱弁。一連の発言に、ファンからは「逆に安心した」「ずっといてくれ」といった安堵の声が相次ぎました。今回の発言が飛び出したのは、深夜帯の雑談配信中とみられます。夏色さんは、「推し大体卒業してってる」「デビューが早いってのもあってみんな卒業しちゃう」と、ホロライブ初期から活動する1期生ならではの寂しさを吐露。多くの卒業を見送ってきた経験から、「」と語りつつ、話題は自身の「進退」へと移っていきました。配信で夏色さんは、自身がホロライブを辞めるタイミングとして、2つの具体的な条件を提示しました。「1期生が全員なくなったら」「あとは、クビになるかどうか。」この「クビになるか」という発言の背景には、自身の過去の評価があったようです。まつりさんはSNSで「」と自虐的に告白。しかし、「最近言われなくなったのは多分こいつはもう多分ずっといるんだろうなって思われたんだと思う」と、自身のパブリックイメージの変化を分析。ホロライブへの「めっちゃお世話になってるし感謝してる」という想いと共に、活動継続の意思を強く示しました。「夢を全て叶えてやり切ったなって思ったらわかんないけどね」「今のところ全然夢叶わなさそう」具体的な夢として「ソロライブ」、「ホロライブザムービー」、さらには元々目指していた「声優」として「自分じゃない役でアニメとかに出たい」と、熱い想いを次々と明かしました。「夢が盛沢さんすぎて叶いそうにない」と笑う彼女に、ファンからは 「『夢が叶わないから辞めない』は最強の安心材料」 「こいつはずっといるって思われてるの草」 「映画化もソロライブも全部叶えてほしい！応援する！」 「なんだかんだホロライブ大好きなんだよな」 といった温かいコメントが寄せられました。「1期生が全員なくなったら」という言葉には、同期への強い絆を感じさせます。多くの卒業を見送ってきたからこそ、今いる仲間との時間を大切にしているのが伝わってきます]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ducky x hololive English FUWAMOCO Releases Limited Edition Keyboard to Celebrate 2nd Anniversary on October 31!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20251031-02-10/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 09:45:52 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[October 31, 2025, Tokyo, JAPAN – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) are collaborating with mechanical keyboard brand Ducky in celebration of two years with FUWAMOCO. Ducky has produced a collectible edition of their popular One 2 keyboard featuring twins Fuwawa Abyssgard and Mococo Abyssgard from hololive English -Advent-.Only 1000 units of the Ducky x hololive English One 2 RGB FUWAMOCO Limited Edition Keyboard are available worldwide, engraved with a unique serial number on a metal plate. This exclusive collaboration includes a matching mousepad and novelty keycaps that bring a pastel touch to any setup. The keyboard launches on October 31, 2025 with allocations in the United States, Japan and other territories.For more information, please visit Ducky’s official social media accounts and distribution page.
PBT Dye-Sub Keycaps with English and Hiragana legends
Full Case Illustrations by Mitarashi NekoDucky is a prominent manufacturer of mechanical keyboards and peripherals. They are committed to creating top-notch professional keyboards and mice with exceptional quality. With partners in over 50 countries, Ducky strives to create products that are not just your average PC peripherals but also works of art by blending cultural traditions with state-of-the-art technology. It is their mission to meet the needs of users and collectors.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Usada Pekora x KING TO NIN JIOM Collaboration Goods Available for Pre-Order from October 31!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20251031-01-199/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 07:50:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[October 31, 2025, Tokyo, JAPAN – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Tanigo Motoaki) and KING TO NIN JIOM have released an exclusive merchandise line featuring hololive production talent Usada Pekora. Fans can pre-order goods and exclusive merchandise sets starting from today, October 31.The theme of this collaboration is “Voice Protection.” CAPSULE has tailor-made merchandise for hololive production talent Usada Pekora, based on the theme Pekora’s own favorite voice protection item: KING TO NIN JIOM. The collaboration showcases products inspired by Usada Pekora’s energetic smile and Chinese motifs, with character art featuring two limited-edition outfits. From cute acrylic standees to practical everyday items, limited-edition merchandise full of Pekora’s charm is about to debut—get ready for the arrival of “Voice Protection Charm! Peko!” Pre-orders begin on Friday, October 31.Whether it’s the badges shining with Pekora’s signature smile, the high-quality acrylic standees, or the talking sitting plushie, each item is designed to make you want to collect the whole set.■ Taiwan-Exclusive Merchandise■ Japan-Exclusive MerchandiseIn addition to the new visual merchandise, this collaboration has prepared a variety of set options:* Images are for reference only. Please refer to the actual products.
* Styles for random items cannot be specified.
・ Voice Protection Charm, Peko! Set A (NTD250) – Includes limited-edition storage tin box, random badge, and limited-edition stickers.
・ Voice Protection Charm, Peko! Set B (NTD399) – Includes random charm, PVC cleaning cloth charm, and acrylic card.
・ Voice Protection Charm, Peko! Guardian Gift Pack (NTD1499) – An integrated set with multiple merchandise items, including a character art standee, badges, stickers, a candy’s set, and other rich content.
・ Let’s protect our voices together, Peko! A Set (¥2500) – Includes a PVC clear pouch with zipper, trading acrylic clear card, and a full-print acrylic stand.
・ Let’s protect our voices together, Peko! B Set (¥3500) – Includes a candy tin, trading stickers, trading pin badge, 2-in-1 chibi acrylic stand, and a trading hot-stamped illustration card.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>[hololive] 3rd Generation Live to be Held in January 2026! Fired Up for 2026 With a New Song! hololive 3rd Generation Live #Kyur...</title><link>https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/entry_403.html</link><author></author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 07:37:48 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/top_page.html?q=hololive">VTuber Republic</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Friday, October 31, 2025 at 2:32 AM EDT</title><link>https://warosu.org/vt/thread/106138000#p106138000</link><author></author><category>/vt/ /news/</category><category>VTubers</category><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 06:32:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vt.rita.moe/">/vt//news/</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ合格の決め手は？ 大神ミオ「ライバルがトンズラ」、天音かなたは「入社催促」！？ 衝撃のオーディション秘話</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/miokanamarin/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 04:42:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[今や絶大な人気を誇るVTuberグループ「ホロライブ」。その非常に狭き門を突破したメンバーは、一体どのようなアピールをして合格を掴み取ったのでしょうか。ホロライブ所属の天音かなたさん、宝鐘マリンさん、大神ミオさんが、30日のハロウィン企画配信で視聴者からの「」という質問をきっかけに、それぞれのオーディション秘話を語りました。ミオさんは、応募書類での力強いアピールを行ったことを明かしました。「自己アピールのところに、『この箱をナンバーワンの箱にします。よろしくお願いします』って書いた。」この熱意ある宣言に、かなたさんは「すごいじゃないですか」「かっこいい。やっぱ自信なんですね」と感心しきり。しかし、話はこれだけでは終わりませんでした。ミオさんは、さらに衝撃的な「本当の合格理由」を続けます。なんか最終審査で2人残ってたんだけど、1人とんずらしたからね、うちが勝ったって聞きました。これには、かなたさん、マリンさん共に「そんなことあるんですか！？」と驚愕。マリンさんは「」と、今とは状況が違ったであろう当時を推測しました。続いて、天音かなたさん（かなたん）のアピールポイント。「オーディションの動画の1番最初で、『曲がりくねた道の先に』を、。それが良かったんじゃないかな。ハーモニーを奏でました」その高い技術力とインパクトのある動画が評価されたようです。しかし、かなたさんもミオさんに劣らず衝撃的な裏話を暴露します。同時にもう1つの会社に受けていたよ。そちらが先に受かって、（ホロライブに）『早くしてください』ってメール送ったねなんと、別の事務所からも合格が出ていたため、ホロライブ側に合否を「催促」していたというのです。マリンさんが「ええ！？それでよくホロライブの方選びましたね」と驚くと、かなたさんはと、当時が大きな賭けであったことを振り返りました。一方、宝鐘マリンさん（船長）は、「（合格理由は）」と自信満々に宣言しました。三者三様の合格秘話。確かな実力はもちろんのこと、強い熱意、大胆な駆け引き、そして「運」という様々な要因が重なって、ホロライブへの所属を掴み取ったようです。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ「雑すぎる仮装」がカオスと話題。天音かなた・宝鐘マリン・大神ミオのハロウィン配信に「初期ホロライブ」の声</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/witch-6/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 01:10:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[2025年10月30日の夜、ハロウィンを翌日に控えたVTuberグループ「ホロライブ」の企画配信の内容が話題となっています。ホロライブ4期生のさん、3期生のさん、ゲーマーズのさんの3名が、「ハロウィンお悩み解決隊」と題したリレー配信を実施。しかし、そこで披露された3人の「雑すぎる仮装」と、それに伴うシュールなやり取りが、ファンから「初期ホロライブを感じるw」「地獄企画で草」などの声が相次ぎました。今回の配信は、ホロライブ全体で行われているハロウィンリレー企画「ホロウィッチ」の一環として行われたもの。「お悩み解決隊」として、3人がリスナーの悩みに答えていくという趣旨でした。しかし、配信が始まるやいなや、画面に映し出されたのは魔女（ウィッチ）とは似ても似つかぬ3人の姿。リスナーの度肝を抜いたのは、以下のカオスな仮装でした。: 『名探偵コナン』の「」（円谷光彦のモノマネ）配信の核心となったのは、「戸愚呂（妹）」に扮した天音かなたさんの孤軍奮闘でした。かなたさんは『幽☆遊☆白書』に登場する戸愚呂（弟）の大ファンとして知られており、配信中も「過酷だねェ…」「お湯80%！！」「100%のおなら！！」など、元ネタの「○％」構文や名言を連発。一方、マリンさんは得意の「マリ彦」モノマネで喉を酷使し、ミオさんは「ちいミオ」としてマイペースに場を和ませようとしますが、3人のキャラ渋滞と元ネタの不一致により、お悩み相談はほぼそっちのけでした。このカオスな展開に、リスナーからは「初期ホロライブを感じる雑仮装w」「久しく見なかったホロライブに求めてるものがここにある」「地獄企画定期的に頼む」といったコメントも多く見られ、作り込まれた企画とは一味違う、手作り感満載の企画を楽しむファンが続出しました。最近は大型ライブや豪華な企画が多いですが、こういう「内輪ノリの学園祭」みたいな雑な配信が見られると、ファンとしては嬉しくなっちゃいますね。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>にじさんじ × カラオケまねきねこ 11月5日よりIdios 1st LIVE コラボ開催!</title><link>https://collabo-cafe.com/events/collabo/nijisanji-idios-karaokemanekineko2025/</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:37:57 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://collabo-cafe.com/?s=Hololive">hololive collabs in Japan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[バーチャルライバーとして大人気を誇るVtuberグループ「にじさんじ」Idios 1st LIVE “Seize the day” × カラオケまねきねこにて、2025年11月5日〜12月5日までの期間限定でコラボ開催！Idiosメンバーをイメージしたコラボメニューや、歌唱キャンペーンが登場!]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】京都念慈菴コラボ 兎田ぺこら 声をいっしょに守るぺこ！護声符！PEKO！ グッズ</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/goseihu-peko/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 21:01:43 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[︎販売期間：25年12月10日まで︎販売期間：25年12月7日まで︎販売期間：不明(なくなり次第終了？)︎販売期間：数量限定※日本国内でも購入可能ですが関税や送料など高額になる可能性があります※アムニバスと値段が異なります]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>She is a Menace to Public 🍜</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/wyUd9rrjvdk</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/wyUd9rrjvdk?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 19:55:54 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[found the artist: @Mr_TheCatMan on Twitter

⭐ Please follow and support!
Twitter - https://twitter.com/hwikkyofficial
Patreon - https://www.patreon.com/hwikky
ko-fi - https://www.ko-fi.com/hwikky

#hololive #ホロライブ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Unstoppable hololive Loop ♻️</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/TF3eVPhi8ow</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/TF3eVPhi8ow?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 19:03:44 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[credit: Free preview from ‪@hololiveEnglish 
DAY 1 Free Preview: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HzTiec89h90&t=3281s
DAY 2 Free Preview: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h4isKo0FDF8&t=3539s

⭐ Please follow and support!
Twitter - https://twitter.com/hwikkyofficial
Patreon - https://www.patreon.com/hwikky
ko-fi - https://www.ko-fi.com/hwikky

#hololive #ホロライブ
#holoAllforOne]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>One VTuber Weeb VS New York City 【 hololive Concert ALL FOR ONE 】</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hS3ROw0X8VE</link><author>hwikky</author><category>yt-holo</category><enclosure url="https://www.youtube.com/v/hS3ROw0X8VE?version=3" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 16:49:40 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCI-K3cqRc7whDl_DAC_trYw">hwikky</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[☄️ Hoshimachi Suisei PC Case + Keycap & Desk Pad Bundle
Also check out other hololive collab PC stuff.
👉 Get yours here: https://hyte.co/hwikky-hololive

⭐ Please follow and support!
Twitter - https://twitter.com/hwikkyofficial
Patreon - https://www.patreon.com/hwikky
ko-fi - https://www.ko-fi.com/hwikky

credit: Free preview from ‪@hololiveEnglish 
DAY 1 Free Preview: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HzTiec89h90&t=3281s
DAY 2 Free Preview: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h4isKo0FDF8&t=3539s

#PR #HYTE
#holoAllforOne #AnimeNYC #hololiveSTAGE25 
#hololive #ホロライブ

- Classic Music Credit
Music autor: Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart
Musical interpretation: Advent Chamber Orchestra
Music title: Pequeña Serenata Nocturna
License: https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/deed.es
Download: https://lamusicagratis.com/descargar-musica/pequena-serenata-nocturna-allegro]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>桃鈴ねね、ホロライブの”急成長”に本音「情報についていけない」。”シンデレラストーリー”を望む姿を語った</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/nene-20/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 16:12:28 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ5期生の「ねねち」こと桃鈴ねねさんが、自身の配信中、最近のホロライブメンバーによるソロライブの多さについて言及。大きな会場での開催が続く現状に対し、「」という自身の”理想のアイドル像”について本音を語りました。現在、大手VTuber事務所「ホロライブ」では、所属タレントによるソロライブイベントの開催が活発化しています。先輩たちが次々と大規模な会場でのライブを発表しており、事務所全体の勢いを感じさせる一方、その展開の早さに驚くファンも少なくありません。そんな中、桃鈴ねねさんは配信で「ライブをして成長していくアイドル」に憧れてホロライブに来たと語りました。ホロライブ自体「毎月誰かのライブがあるのはめっちゃ嬉しい」と、ライブ自体はポジティブに捉えている様子したが、同時に現在の「」と語り、自身の理想とのギャップも感じているようでした。配信の中で、ねねさんは自身の理想とするアイドル像について熱く語りました。もっと小さい会場のところで成長の段階踏みたい。みんな今だとめっちゃ、超でかい会場を抑えてたからね。みんなと小さいところからコツコツコツコツみたいなのがやりたいんだよね。アイドルって成長コンテンツだからさらに「」と続け、「」と、ファンと共に一歩ずつ階段を上っていくようなサクセスストーリーへの憧れを明かしました。この「ホロライブは成長が早すぎる」という感覚は、ねねさん自身も感じているとのこと。「」と、ファンと同じ目線で現在の心境を吐露しました。まだ自分の中で「アイドル」として納得できる段階を踏めていない、と感じている様子。最後には「」と、ファンに認められる大きな存在になりたいという強い意欲を見せました。 と、彼女の考えに共感し、応援するコメントが見られました。ねねちはねねちのギラギラファンミーティング等で観客を盛り上げるエンターテイナーとしての素質はかなり高いと思うのでかなり活躍に期待しています。コツコツ小さな一歩からでもいいのでぜひ夢を見せてほしいですね。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ姫森ルーナ、ファンの「1stソロライブ期待」投稿に本人が「やらんよ？」と即レス！「本人登場w」「温度差草」</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/ru-na-5/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:54:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[「ホロライブプロダクション」所属のさんが、自身の1stソロライブ開催を期待する一人のファンのX（旧Twitter）投稿に対し、本人自ら「やらんよ？(・o・)」とリプライ（返信）し、話題となっています。タレント本人がファンの投稿に直接、反応する珍しい展開に、他のファンからは「本人登場で草」「ツッコミw」などの声が相次ぎました。ホロライブでは、所属タレントによる大規模なソロライブイベントが活発に開催されており、ファンにとってはもちろん、タレントにとっても大きな節目となっています。4期生として長きにわたり活躍を続ける姫森ルーナさんに対しても、ファンからは「ルーナ姫のソロライブがいつか見たい」という期待の声が寄せられていました。そんな中、10月30日（日本時間）、ファンの一人である一人が自身のXに、以下のような期待の声を投稿しました。これは、他のホロライブメンバーのライブ開催の流れなどを受け、ルーナさんのソロライブ開催を願う、多くのファンの気持ちを代弁するような投稿とみられます。通常、タレントがこうした個別のファンの投稿一つひとつに反応することは稀ですが、なんと今回、姫森ルーナさん（@himemoriluna）本人がこの投稿に直接リプライ。ファンが寄せた熱い期待に対し、あくまでもマイペースに「やらない」と宣言。まさかの本人からの光速ツッコミで、期待の声をバッサリと切り捨てる展開となりました。本人からの突然の「やらんよ？」という直接の返信に、投稿主のふじみ氏や、そのやり取りを目撃した他のファンたちは騒然。「姫のペースでやるから、あまり騒ぐでないのら」というメッセージかもしれません。周囲の期待に乗っかるのではなく、ようにしているのかも…？深読みしすぎですかね（笑）]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>姫森ルーナ、雪花ラミィの「質量の暴力」に嫉妬！「脂肪こっちに入れて」と懇願したサシ飲みとは</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/holonews/luna/</link><author>風歌</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:46:23 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブ所属の雪花ラミィさんと姫森ルーナさんが、先日、初の2人きりでのサシ飲みコラボ配信を行いました。この配信中、雪花さんの圧倒的なスタイルが画面越しに伝わり、姫森さんが「脂肪こっちに入れてくれ」と懇願する場面が飛び出しました。この日、ということで、雪花さんは冒頭から「」とソワソワした様子でした。配信が和やかに進む中、視聴者から「セクシーにしりとり対決をして、どっちがセクシーなのか決着をつけてください」というお便りが届きました。これに対し、姫森さんは、ある事実に気づいてしまいます。もうね、今ね、。もう画面上にさ。雪花さんの隠しきれない圧倒的なスタイルに、姫森さんは思わず本音を漏らします。んなたん大きい方だと思ってたんだけどさ、こう見せつけられちゃうとさ。脂肪こっちに入れてくれ。んなたんのこっちに入れてくれよ。この「」「」というパワーワードの連発と共に、姫森さんから切実なお願いが飛び出しました。この流れの発端となった「セクシーしりとり対決」も実際にやってみることに。「しりとり」「ゴリラ」「ラクダ」と、普通の単語をセクシーに言い始める両者。すると、雪花さんはを仕掛けてきました。このまさかのセリフ攻撃に、姫森さんも「セリフできたか！セリフで来やがったぞ！」と混乱。しかし、姫森さんもと強さを見せつけ、雪花さんを圧倒。最終的に、。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【ホロライブ】ハロウィン新企画「魔法少女ホロウィッチ！」が10/31に無料公開決定！豪華声優2名の参加も発表！</title><link>https://hololive-tsuushin.com/schedule/witch-4/</link><author>ホロミ</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololive-tsuushin.com/">hololive tsuushin fan blog (JP)</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[2025年のハロウィン大型企画「魔法少女ホロウィッチ！THE STAGE」10月31日(金)にホロライブ公式YouTubeチャンネルで無料公開することを発表しました！なんと、物語とアニメ、そして歌のライブが一体となった、全く新しいエンターテイメントになるとのこと。さらに、出演メンバーに加えて、の参加も決定しています。今回発表された「魔法少女ホロウィッチ！THE STAGE」のポイントは、大きく分けて3つあります。 今回の企画には、期生の垣根を越えた6名のホロライブメンバーが集結しました！（0期生）（1期生）（3期生）（4期生）（4期生）（5期生）さらに、物語を彩るキャラクターの声優として、プロの声優である（アエル役）と（ラグ役）の参加が決定！ 高橋李依さんは『【推しの子】』のアイ役、悠木碧さんは『魔法少女まどか☆マギカ』の鹿目まどか役などで知られる声優さんです。 なんと、これだけのメンバーに加えて「Special Guests」がいることも示唆されていますこのサプライズ発表を受けて、SNSではファンから 「メンツが豪華すぎる！」 「無料で見れるなんて信じられない！」 「高橋李依さんと悠木碧さんまで！？」 といった、驚きと喜びの声が上がりました。]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Thursday, October 30, 2025 at 4:35 AM EDT</title><link>https://warosu.org/vt/thread/105665248#p106100045</link><author></author><category>/vt/ /news/</category><category>VTubers</category><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 08:35:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vt.rita.moe/">/vt//news/</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>[Archive] Kureiji Ollie’s Arrival Fest Held in Holoearth on Oct. 28 PDT</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/archive_kureijiollie/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 08:26:45 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Greetings from the Holoearth Management Team!On Tuesday, October 28th, 2025 (PDT), Kureiji Ollie of hololive Indonesia visited Holoearth as her own custom avatar model for a special “Holoearth Kureiji Ollie’s Arrival Fest” event.A stream of the event is archived for all those who are interested in viewing.Kureiji Ollie’s Own T-Shirt Design “SUPER KAWAII ZOMBIE IDOL” is Available as Real Merch!Note: Please be aware that the Amazon store link is different depending on whether you are purchasing the T-shirt in white or in black.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>[hololive] The Clumsy Yet Close 3rd Generation Members are the Main Characters!? A manga starring the 3rd Generation is confirme...</title><link>https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/entry_402.html</link><author></author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 07:16:42 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/top_page.html?q=hololive">VTuber Republic</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】スケールフィギュア 百鬼あやめ～巫女衣装Ver.～：26年6月発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/ayame-kotobukiya02/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 03:02:43 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>「ホロライブ」所属 常闇トワ 2nd Live映像を、JOYSOUND「みるハコ」で全国のカラオケル…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000002747.000004747.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/4747/2747/4747-2747-fe0cd0d9eab8df3501608198ae104326-900x506.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 02:54:57 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【発売中】常闇トワ スポーツ報知 2025年10月29日付</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/mio-spotshouchi-251029/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 22:19:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[︎発売：25年10月30日（通販：同日正午より開始？）]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【発売中】常闇トワ スポーツ報知 2025年10月30日付</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/mio-spotshouchi-251030/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 22:16:41 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[︎発売：25年10月30日（通販：同日正午より開始？）]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【発売中】クレイジー・オリー / SUPER KAWAII ZOMBIE IDOL 白・黒 Tシャツ【Amazon限定】</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/super-kawaii-zombie-idol-t-shirt/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 16:39:38 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[ホロライブプロダクション所属タレント「クレイジー・オリー」が「ホロアース」の世界で自作した“あのTシャツ”が、リアルグッズとして登場！]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】ゲーム「おかゆにゅ〜〜む！R」/猫又おかゆ主演・監修ノベルゲーム【店舗特典まとめ】：26年2月26日発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/okayunyumu-r/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 16:29:08 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[︎予約開始：11月3日︎場所：トレーダー秋葉原2号店TGS2025にて配布した「チェキ風カードセット」の無料配布。パッケージ版をご予約いただいた方には「特製缶バッジ」をプレゼントいたします。【】・Nintendo Switch・Nintendo Switch・PS4・完全生産限定版(hololive Official Edition）　ゲーム本体＋グッズ＋hololive Official Edition限定グッズ　NintendoSwitch版『おかゆにゅ～～む！』通常版＋『おかゆにゅ～～む！R』通常版を特製スリーブケースに収納したセット版対象店舗で予約・購入するとプラスで特典グッズ・ボイスなどが付属！（特典はなくなり次第終了）録りおろしASMR「おかゆと湯けむり時間」ストリーミングコードカード録りおろしASMR CD「おかゆお姉ちゃんに包まれて」録りおろしASMR「起きない君にいたずらタイム♡」配信録りおろしASMR CD「夜のごほうび、おかゆのマッサージ」完全生産限定版(hololive Official Edition）︎予約期限：26年1月5日まで]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>[hololive] Collaboration with a major green tea maker! A collaboration featuring Juufuutei Raden, who has been selected as the g...</title><link>https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/entry_401.html</link><author></author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:52:49 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://vtuberrepublic.com/blog/top_page.html?q=hololive">VTuber Republic</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>“Advent’s Arrival Fest” to be Held on November 6th (PT)</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/advent/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:33:21 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Greetings from the Holoearth Management Team! (November 7th from 11:00 (JST)), the members of hololive English -Advent- will come to Holoearth as their very own avatars in a special festival event, “Advent’s Arrival Fest.”As part of this special event, new avatar items such as penlights and new
gestures will be available.Fans will also have a chance to watch parts of holonatsu Paradise After Party in the new Celestial Beach arena with the talents, and try their creativity at making talent-themed Marketplace items leading up to the event – so continue reading for more information!
Let’s meet Advent in Holoearth on November 6th PT!
(Schedule is subject to change.)
Anyone can join in the festivities for free by downloading and installing Holoearth.
(Note: Holoearth is available only on Windows.)Celestial Beach Watchalong With the Talents: holonatsu Paradise After Party
“Celestial Beach” in Holoearth.
・Taking screenshots and posting them & impressions on social media is allowed.
・Posting videos without audio up to 30 sec. long on social media is allowed.
・To adjust the volume of content playing in the Celestial Arena, go to Options (Esc) and adjust the “Media” volume setting.
Note: Playback timing may vary depending on your system environment.NOTE: Purchasing any of the following will enable entry to the event area.・Summer Splash Party Ver. Swimsuit Type A (Yel / Pk / Blu)
・Summer Splash Party Ver. Swimsuit Type B (Yel / Pk / Blu)
・Summer Splash Party Ver. T-Shirt (Blk / Wh)
・Summer Splash Party Ver. Bracelets (Yel / Pk / Blu)
・Summer Splash Party Ver. Sandals (Yel / Pk / Blu)Advent’s Arrival Fest Commemorative ItemsSpecial Advent-themed penlights will also be added.
Enjoy combining these penlights with gestures for cheering on the event!
(Schedule is subject to change.)
・Penlight Shiori Novella Type B
・Penlight Koseki Bijou Type B
・Penlight Nerissa Ravencroft Type B
・Penlight Fuwawa Abyssgard Type B
・Penlight Mococo Abyssgard Type BNote: Penlights are held in both hands when used.
Note: These items cannot be used in the Simulation Room or My Space.
Note: The Penlight Fuwawa Abyssgard / Mococo Abyssgard Type B are already available for purchase in Holoearth.Text plate items will also be added that include phrases related to Advent members.
(Schedule is subject to change.)
・Shiori Novella Text Plate 1 x 3
(Shiorin / Shiori~n! / BASED / Shiori / CUTEEEEE)
・Koseki Bijou Text Plate 1 x 3
(Bonbijou! / Biboo / Moai moai kyun! / I’m cute forgive me / Hanya?)
・Nerissa Ravencroft Text Plate 1 x 3
(Rissa / Nerissa / Devilish Diva / Ope / Hiya)
・Fuwawa Abyssgard Text Plate 1 x 3
(BAU BAU (Fuwawa color) / Fuwawa! / Gosh / I’m not a Chihuahua / Fuwa-chan!)
・Mococo Abyssgard Text Plate 1 x 3
(BAU BAU (Mococo color) / Mococo! / Haeh? / I’m not Fuwawa / Moco-chan!)Note: Text plates are consumable items.
Note: These items cannot be used in the Simulation Room or My Space.
Note: The Fuwawa Abyssgard / Mococo Abyssgard Text Plate 1 x 3 are already available for purchase in Holoearth.A new “Rebellion” gesture for each talent will be added. Celebrate the Arrival in style with these signature poses!
(Schedule is subject to change.)
・Rebellion Shiori Novella
・Rebellion Nerissa Ravencroft
・Rebellion Fuwawa Abyssgard
・Rebellion Mococo AbyssgardAdvent member acrylic stand furniture items will be added.
Decorate your space with life-sized acrylic stands of your oshi!
(Schedule is subject to change.)
・Shiori Novella Default Outfit Acrylic Stand (M / L)
・Koseki Bijou Default Outfit Acrylic Stand (M / L)
・Nerissa Ravencroft Default Outfit Acrylic Stand (M / L)
・Fuwawa Abyssgard Default Outfit Acrylic Stand (M / L)
・Mococo Abyssgard Default Outfit Acrylic Stand (M / L)Note: The M-sized stand is 1/2.5 scale and the L-sized is 1/1 scale.
Note: The Fuwawa Abyssgard / Mococo Abyssgard Default Outfit Acrylic Stand (M / L) are already available for purchase in Holoearth.Commemorative Support CampaignArrival Fest Outfit & Sticker Design CallCreate an item on Holoearth Marketplace with the spirit of summer and Advent in anticipation for the Arrival! Your item may even be featured!
(Schedule is subject to change.)
When submitting your item for review, be sure to include the tag ““.
When using an Advent talent license, you must check the hololive production license and enter the related talent name.
・To participate you must submit an item for review during the entry period above.
After passing review, set your item’s status to “Public” by the time of the event on November 6th (PT).
・Multiple talent licenses cannot be used at the same time.
・To create an item featuring both Fuwawa Abyssgard and Mococo Abyssgard, enter the talent name FUWAMOCO.
▲Choosing a license to useArrival Fest Commemorative Login CampaignTo commemorate the event, we will hold a special login campaign!, text plates, and more will be gifted during the campaign period! Just log in to receive your items.
(Items can be received from the gift box in the HoloPhone menu.)Gift items & applicable period
・Poppers x5
・Text Plate (5 types of 3 each)
・300 HoloCoin (Regular)Note: Campaign items are only distributed once per account.
(Schedule is subject to change.)]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Kureiji Ollie’s Own T-Shirt Design “SUPER KAWAII ZOMBIE IDOL” is Available as Real Merch on Amazon!</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/kureijiollie_tshirts/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:31:27 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Note: Please be aware that the Amazon store link is different depending on whether you are purchasing the T-shirt in white or in black.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Twitch x hololive production Collaboration Online Event “holoday”</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20251029-01-198/</link><author>Horii</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:50:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[October 29, 2025, Tokyo, Japan – COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo; CEO: Motoaki Tanigo) is excited to announce the very first official online collaboration event with Twitch, which will be held on November 20, 2025 (PST).Twitch, the global leading live streaming service that empowers communities to create and watch together, is collaborating with hololive production to bring talents hololive fans know and love to the platform. Talents from hololive Indonesia, hololive English, and HOLOSTARS English will take over the front page of Twitch for an all-day the “holoday” celebration.To celebrate hololive talents making their debut on Twitch, viewers will be able to obtain a limited-time Global Emote featuring COVER Corporation’s CEO, Motoaki Tanigo. Fans can look forward to a variety of fun streams hosted by the participating talents during the online event.Get ready for “holoday”, a special all-day event where hololive production talents will take over Twitch like never before! We hope you’re as excited as we are.Event Overview: Twitch x hololive production “holoday”]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>16 hololive VTubers to take over Twitch for “holoday” collab event this November</title><link>https://essential-japan.com/news/16-hololive-vtubers-to-take-over-twitch-for-holoday-collab-event-this-november/</link><author>James Richardson</author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://cdn.essential-japan.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/HOLOLIVE-TWITCH.webp" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://essential-japan.com/?s=hololive">hololive articles from Essential Japan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[COVER Corporation has announced "holoday," its first-ever official online collaboration event with the global live-streaming service, Twitch.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ver 1.1.1 Release Notes</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/ver111_updatenotice/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 07:01:48 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This is the Holoearth Management Team.Holoearth was updated on October 28th, 2025.
Update Contents
An issue where passive skill effects such as “Action Skill Attack Power Up” for the action skills “Soaring Slash,” “Heat Slash,” “Mizuchi,” “Wind Slash,” and “Frost Edge” were not applied properly in the Simulation Room was fixed.■ Bug causing items inside storage furniture to disappear
An issue where items stored inside furniture that can hold items, such as chests and furnaces, disappeared when the furniture was deconstructed in the Simulation Room and My Room was fixed.We sincerely apologize to all users for the inconvenience caused by the recent issue where items placed in furniture could be lost.
We will be offering data recovery support for users who lost items due to this issue and wish to have their play data restored.If you would like your data to be recovered, please contact us via the Holoearth inquiry form within the period stated below.Data recovery request period:
For any account that contacts us about data recovery, we will restore (roll back) the play data of the Simulation Room / My Room to the state it was in just before the Ver. 1.1.0 update implemented on October 23rd, 2025.Room play data that can be recovered:・Simulation Room
・My Room: Other: User data restoration: Specify the play data of the room you wish to have restored: Simulation Room, My Room, or both.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】PLAMATEA「白銀ノエル」プラモデル：26年6月発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/plamatea-noel/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 03:14:25 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[※期間中は必ずご予約できます。※上記期間をもって販売予定数が決定し、以降は予定数に達し次第受付終了※GOODSMILE以外の通販サイトでは数に限りあり]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive Indonesia Fan Festival @ Comic Frontier 21 will be held on November 15-16, 2025!</title><link>https://hololivepro.com/news_en/20251028-01-197/</link><author>narita</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 02:50:06 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://hololivepro.com/">hololive Official News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[October 28, 2025, Tokyo, JAPAN — COVER Corporation (Minato-ku, Tokyo, Japan, CEO: Motoaki Tanigo) announced today that hololive Indonesia Fan Festival @ Comic Frontier 21 will be held on November 15-16, 2025, at Indonesia Convention Exhibition (ICE) BSD City in Tangerang Selatan, Indonesia.EXPLORE hololive Indonesia AT COMIFURO 21
A special dedicated zone for hololive Indonesia Fan Festival will be located in Hall 10 of the ICE. The zone will include booths related to hololive Indonesia, from official booths to sponsor booths. There will also be many activities, including stamp rally, for visitors to join that will enhance their experience as hololive Indonesia fans!
The hololive Indonesia 5th Anniversary LIVE Chromatic Future, Meet and Greet with all hololive Indonesia talents, and hololive Meet stage with Vestia Zeta and Kaela Kovalskia will be held at the same weekend at Comic Frontier 21!THE FUN CONTINUES OFF-SITE
Fans of hololive Indonesia can keep the Fan Festival energy high with tie-in activities outside the venue, too, like restaurant collaboration and Illustration Contest!hololive Indonesia Fan Festival @ Comic Frontier 21 Overview
November 15-16, 2025
Indonesia Convention Exhibition (ICE) BSD City Hall 10
Jl. BSD Grand Boulevard No.1, Pagedangan, Kec. Pagedangan, Kabupaten Tangerang, Banten■ hololive Indonesia Fan Festival Booth #: 1101 (Hall 10)
A booth to celebrate the fans’ five years of love and passion towards hololive Indonesia. Take photos with the standees from hololive Indonesia 5th Anniversary LIVE Chromatic Future, and also check out various exhibits that make you reminisce about hololive Indonesia’s journey!
There will also be a message board wall for fans to write their hopes for hololive Indonesia in the future, so be sure to leave your wish!・ hololive Indonesia Fan Festival Stamp Rally
Stamp cards will be distributed at the booth, and attendees can collect stamps by visiting the booths of hololive Indonesia partner companies in the hololive Indonesia Fan Festival zone. Participants who collect all stamps on their card may be eligible to receive the hololive Indonesia Fan Festival Sticker Set!■ hololive production Official Merchandise Booth #: 1102 (Hall 10)
Fans can purchase official live merchandise (Made in Indonesia Edition) at the booth. As a purchase bonus, customers will also receive a random postcard. Image is just for illustrative purposes only, design is subject to change.Anime Collective Lab (ACL)■ Merchandise Booth #: 1103 (Hall 10)Fans can purchase special collaboration merchandise between ACL and hololive Indonesia 5th Anniversary LIVE Chromatic Future.・ ACL x hololive ID Pop Up Cafe: S1-S2 (F&B Area)
At this Pop Up Cafe, fans can enjoy local food and drinks themed around hololive Indonesia 5th Anniversary LIVE Chromatic Future.ACL is also planning to have collaboration with a Japanese Restaurant, Umakatta Gading Serpong, where fans can enjoy a special collaboration menu featuring hololive Indonesia. For more information on the above booth and collaboration, follow: https://www.instagram.com/animecollectivelab■ Pocky x hololive Indonesia Booth #: 1104a (Hall 10)
At this booth, fans can purchase Pocky sets bundled with Pocky X hololive ID Collectible Photocard (3 Pocky for 1 photocard). Not only that, fans can also participate in Gacha Machine corner to win a hololive Indonesia 5th Anniversary LIVE Chromatic Future-themed merchandise. Fans who either purchase a Pocky set or play in Gacha Machine will have access to take a photo in a special Pocky X hololive ID Photo Booth.
For latest information, follow: https://www.instagram.com/pockyid■ Booth #: 1104b (Hall 10)
Fans can purchase hololive Indonesia x Manekineko collaboration merchandise in this booth. Further merchandise announcements will be made in November, 2025. For latest information, follow Manekineko Indonesia official instagram: https://www.instagram.com/manekineko_indonesiahololive Indonesia FAN FESTIVAL STAMP RALLY
15-16 November, 2025
・ Pick up a stamp rally card at the hololive Indonesia Fan Festival Booth (Booth no. 1101).
・ Fulfill the conditions outlined for each booth and obtain a stamp from the booth staff.
・ Come back to the hololive production booth and show us your stamp card to redeem the hololive Indonesia Fan Festival Sticker Set prize!■ PARTICIPATING PARTNER BOOTHS AND REQUIREMENTS
・ hololive production Official Merchandise Booth (#1102): Visit the Booth
・ Anime Collective Lab (ACL) Booth (#1103): Take a photo in front of the booth and upload an Instagram story while tagging @animecollectivelab *
・ ACL x hololive ID Pop-up Cafe (F&B Area S1-S2): Follow ACL official Instagram
・ Booth Pocky x hololive Indonesia Booth (# 1104a): Follow Pocky ID official social media (Instagram or TikTok)
・ Booth Karaoke Manekineko (# 1104b): Follow Karaoke Manekineko official Instagram* In the event of insufficient internet connection on-site, a screenshot of the stamp condition may also be accepted.■ hololive Meet: Meet and Greet
All members from hololive Indonesia will be having a meet and greet session!
Go check the details and schedule at: https://x.com/comifuro
Vestia Zeta and Kaela Kovalskia from hololive Indonesia 3rd Generation will be appearing on Comic Frontier 21 Main Stage! It will be their first appearance together in Indonesia.
Date: Sunday, November 16, 2025 (WIB) 16:00-17:00hololive Indonesia Art Battle!
To commemorate hololive Indonesia 5th year anniversary, “hololive Indonesia Art Battle” illustration contest will be held on the illustration, manga, and novel submission platform pixiv from November 4 to December 15, 2025 (JST).Limited-edition clear files featuring the official key visual will be distributed at the hololive Production Official Merchandise Booth. A total of 1,000 copies will be distributed per day, available while supplies last.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【26年3月】グッズ予定まとめ</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/goods-mar26/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 04:38:11 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>『ホロアース』Ver.1.1.0リリース！新キャラクターや新エントランスなどを追加！ホロナツパラダイ…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000001188.000030268.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/30268/1188/30268-1188-e03c650aa18801413ab62dbe0aa008e3-1920x1080.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 23:15:20 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Okayu Nyumu! R Releases on February 26, 2026 for PC, PS4 and Switch - Final Weapon</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMikAFBVV95cUxQN0xwVUw3T2FtOGN3eFl3Y0ttS01JM2FaOS1YVm85Y09VWURoZ2JTTThGb3R2eTdVVndEZGRIOWJHTUV1aUwzTE5HempPcHljR01rbEJpd05iUjFtV2l0dWIwMjhQQjBSQV9SNEU2Qjd4c0dwNHJKQkxhQ0I2cWNOSTBPQzUtSFR6cmVneXpYWXc?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 03:10:58 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>新しい未来のテレビ「ABEMA」グローバル向けオンラインライブプラットフォーム「ABEMA Live…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000002139.000064643.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/64643/2139/64643-2139-de0a9032df48db1ed10e462b94515705-1648x928.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 23:15:10 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Tokoyami Towa 2nd Live Support Campaign in Holoearth Announcement</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/towalive/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 10:24:40 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[Greetings from the Holoearth Management Team!From October 23rd (Thu), 2025 we will launch a support campaign for Tokoyami Towa 1st Live. “SHINier” in Holoearth!
During the campaign period we will feature a street takeover with the “SHINier” key visual and sell commemorative Holoearth merchandise, including a digital version of the concert T-shirt and “SHINier Light Stick.” The background music in the area will also change to “New Order” and “Invisible.”Show your support in Holoearth and post your images within #Holoearth!
“New Order”
(Schedule is subject to change.)
Anyone can join in the festivities for free by downloading and installing Holoearth.
(Note: Holoearth is available only for Windows.)A street takeover featuring the “SHIN” key visual will take place in Alternative City. Users will also be able to take photos with a life-sized standee of Tokoyami Towa.
The background music in the area will also be changed after maintenance to “New Order” until October 30th at 17:59 (JST) and then to “Invisible” until the end of the campaign period.Street Takeover BGM Period:
(Schedule is subject to change.)“SHINier” Commemorative ItemsTokoyami Towa 2nd Live “SHINier” T-ShirtA new T-shirt will be added to the hololive production official shop in HOLOEARTH.
Enjoy this new concert T-shirt in Holoearth!
(Schedule is subject to change.)
・Tokoyami Towa 2nd Live “SHINier” T-ShirtSpecial Tokoyami Towa-themed penlights will also be added, including the “SHINier Light Stick” for fans to show their support in Holoearth!
From October 23rd (Thu) after maintenance.
(Schedule is subject to change.)
・SHINier Light Stick
・Penlight Tokoyami Towa Type BNote: SHINier Light Stick and Penlight Tokoyami Towa Type B are held in both hands when used.
Note: These items cannot be used in the Simulation Room, My Room, or My Shop.Text plate items will also be added that include phrases related to Tokoyami Towa.
From October 23rd (Thu) after maintenance.
(Schedule is subject to change.)
・Tokoyami Towa Text Plate 1 x 3
(Towa-sama / Towa / Konyappi! / Otsuyappi! / Hey!)Note: Text plates are consumable items.
Note: These items cannot be used in the Simulation Room, My Room, or My Shop.A new furniture item, the “Tokoyami Towa 2nd Live “SHINier” Key Visual Acrylic Panel” will be added for decorating users’ spaces!Note: The owner of a Simulation Room, My Room, or My Shop may place this item.
Note: When purchased the item will be sent to the “Special Items” inventory in worlds where it can be placed.
(Schedule is subject to change.)
・Tokoyami Towa 2nd Live “SHINier” Key Visual Acrylic Panel]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Ver. 1.1.0 Release Notes</title><link>https://holoearth.com/en/news/ver110_updatenotice/</link><author>HoloearthWebsiteAdmin</author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 10:13:21 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://holoearth.com/en/">hololive Holoearth</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[This is the Holoearth Management Team.Holoearth was updated on October 23rd, 2025.
Update Contents■
The entrance will be updated to a new area, Focal Square.
This new area will have information on the latest news and events related to Holoearth and act as a hang-out area for talents and users alike.Focal Square music:
“We are happy to have you” (composed by T’s MUSIC Co., Ltd. Rei Kondoh)■
A new area, Celestial Beach, is open for a limited time.
A large monitor in the center will showcase a holonatsu highlight video.■
Anna Rocca was added to Focal Square.■
Cecile Gillet was added to Alternative City.■
The NTH-α support character was added to the Simulation Room for a limited time.Holoearth Terms of Service were also also updated with “About the AI Function (Buddy NPC Function).”■Holoearth inhabitants
New NPCs were added to Focal Square and Alternative City.■
Users will now still be able to see talents even when they are not in the same room with the new “Talent Mirroring” feature.What will be mirrored:
・Avatar model
・Location
・Item usageApplicable areas:
・Focal Square
・Celestial Arena
1. Voice chat will not be mirrored. This is planned for a future update.
2. The talent model will not be shown when sitting at a Poker Room table.■
A new “Exchange Code” feature was added, where specific words can be entered in the “Exchange Codes” menu (ESC key) to receive gifts within Holoearth.Areas exchange codes can be used:
・Focal Square
・Poker Room4. Items & customization options■
By completing certain requirements, users can now receive pathfinder outfit items.Gift conditions:
Make it to your My Room for the first time to get:
・Simple LeggingsMake it to your My Shop for the first time to get:
・Pathfinder Sneakers Type A
・Pathfinder Sneakers Type BClear the “Battle of Wits” tutorial in the Simulation Room to get:
・Pathfinder Jacket Type A
・Pathfinder Jacket Type B■
To commemorate the holonatsu After Party, a new “Water Gun” item was gifted to users.
The item can be found in users’ gift boxes (H key).■
The following avatar fashion items were added.●Hats
・ALTERMODE Beret (Blk / Bn / Olv)
・ALTERMODE Beanie (Blk / Bn / Olv)●Tops
・ALTERMODE Short Jacket (Blu / Bg / Olv)
・ALTERMODE Trench Jacket (Blu / Bg / Olv)
・Happi (Blu / Blk / Red)
・Summer Splash Party Ver. Swimsuit Type A (Yel / Pk / Blu)
・Summer Splash Party Ver. Swimsuit Type B (Yel / Pk / Blu)
・Summer Splash Party Ver. T-Shirt (Blk / Wh)●Bottoms
・ALTERMODE Layered Skirt (Blu / Bg / Olv)
・ALTERMODE Wide Pants (Blu / Bg / Olv)●Socks
・ALTERMODE Logo Socks (Or / Pk / Yel)
・ALTERMODE Stripe Socks (Blk / Bn / Red)●Shoes
・ALTERMODE Cut-Out Boots (Blk / Bn / Olv)
・ALTERMODE Sneakers (Blu / Bn / Olv)
・Summer Splash Party Ver. Sandals (Yel / Pk / Blu)●Underwear
・ALTERMODE Underwear (Blk / Bg / Olv)●Eyewear
・ALTERMODE Round Sunglasses (Or / Blu / Yel)
・ALTERMODE Color Sunglasses (Or / Pk / Yel)●Earrings
・ALTERMODE Earrings (Blu / Pk / Or)●Necklace
・ALTERMODE Choker (BlkRsGld / BnSlv / BlkGld)●Gloves
・ALTERMODE Glove (Blk / Bn / Olv)●Neck
・ALTERMODE Glove (Blk / Bn / Olv)●Wrist
・Summer Splash Party Ver. Bracelets (Yel / Pk / Blu)●Contacts
・Colorful Pop
・Pastel Flower
・Two-Tone Sheen■
The following gestures were added:
・Circle Dance
・Sit-Ups
・Welcome
・Confident
・Zombie Pose 2■Avatar Customization Options
New avatar customization options were added:●Eyes
・Graceful Eyes (Normal)●Eyebrows
・Graceful Eyebrows●Hair (Bangs)
・Natural Doll Bangs
・Deep Side-Parted Bangs
・Center-Parted Diamond Cut
・Styled Center Part
・Natural See-Through Bangs●Hair (Middle)
・Soft Wavy Side Bangs
・Loosely Curled Side Bangs●Hair (Back)
・Ponytail
・Twin Buns
・Feathered Short●Eyeshadow
・Rose Pink Type B
・Toffee Pink Type B
・Dull Brown Type B
・Fuchsia Type B
・Tangerine Type B
・Aqua Spray Type B
・Violet Type B
・Snowy White Type B
Fixed an issue where the hem would clip through when tucking certain bottoms into boots.■
Fixed an issue where certain colors would clip through clothing.■
Fixed an issue where the outline around the neck would become distorted.■Simulation Room, My Room, My Shop
Various minor fixes.Various Fixes & Adjustments■”Event” chat tab for Celestial Arena
[Area] Send messages to all users in rooms of the same area.
[Room] Send messages only to all users in the same room.■Hiding avatars of users near Official Holoearth account avatars.
Avatars in close proximity to official account avatars will be hidden from view.
This feature is available only to official accounts such as talents.■Fast travel kiosk design change
The fast travel kiosks in Alternative City will have an updated design.
Fast travel via bus stops will be disabled, and there will be changes to fast travel locations.Fast travel areas:
・Central Plaza
・ALTERMODE (fashion shop)
・Official Shop (hololive production official shop in HOLOEARTH)
・ALT BEAUTYS (avatar customization facility)
The “Tutorial” section has been changed to “Help”—with detailed information.
You can access “Help” from the HoloPhone (H key).
When starting Photo Mode, it will now start from the camera’s perspective in all areas, rather than just in Alternative City and the entrance area.■Adjustments to avatar neck range of motionChanges to minimum and recommended system requirementsDue to the end of Microsoft support for Windows 10, we are updating the Holoearth minimum and recommended system requirements.Updated Requirements
▼Minimum requirements
Processor : Intel® Core i5 8400 or equivalent
Memory : 8GB
Graphics : NVIDIA GeForce GT 1030
Storage : 80GB or more space available▼Recommended requirements
OS : Windows 11 64-bit i7 8700 or equivalent
Memory : 16GB
Graphics : NVIDIA GeForce RTX 2070
DirectX : DirectX® 12
Storage : 80GB or more space availablePrevious Requirements
▼Minimum requirements
OS : Windows 10 64-bit or higher
Processor : Intel® Core i5 or equivalent
Memory : 8GB
Graphics : NVIDIA GeForce GT 1030
Storage : 80GB or more space available▼Recommended requirements
OS : Windows 10 64-bit or higher i7 8700 or equivalent
Memory : 16GB
Graphics : NVIDIA GeForce RTX 2070
DirectX : DirectX® 12
Storage : 80GB or more space availableThe following issues have been confirmed following maintenance and will be fixed with the next update.
We apologize for the inconvenience caused.■ Passive Skill Bug (Added October 24, 2025)
In the Simulation Room, there is a bug where passive skill effects such as “Action Skill Attack Power Up” for the action skills “Soaring Slash,” “Heat Slash,” “Mizuchi,” “Wind Slash,” and “Frost Edge” are not being applied properly.■ Bug causing items inside storage furniture to disappear (Added October 24, 2025)
In the Simulation Room and My Room, there is a bug where items stored inside furniture that can hold items, such as chests and furnaces, to disappear when the furniture is deconstructed.
When deconstructing these furniture items, be sure to take out all items stored inside beforehand.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】 hololive サンスター文具 シリーズ オリジン衣装 兎田ぺこら / 宝鐘マリン / 角巻わため / 獅白ぼたん ：26年2月発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/sunstar-stationery02/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 03:12:09 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[︎発売日【26年2月下旬】兎田ぺこら / 宝鐘マリン / 角巻わため / 獅白ぼたん︎発売日【26年2月下旬】兎田ぺこら / 宝鐘マリン / 角巻わため / 獅白ぼたん︎発売日【26年2月下旬】兎田ぺこら / 宝鐘マリン / 角巻わため / 獅白ぼたん︎発売日【26年2月下旬】兎田ぺこら / 宝鐘マリン / 角巻わため / 獅白ぼたん︎発売日【26年2月下旬】兎田ぺこら / 宝鐘マリン / 角巻わため / 獅白ぼたん︎発売日【26年2月下旬】兎田ぺこら / 宝鐘マリン / 角巻わため / 獅白ぼたん]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】ねんどろいど 星街すいせい セーラー衣装 Ver.：26年4月発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/nendoroid-suisei-sailor/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 03:06:31 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[※期間中は必ずご予約できます。※上記期間をもって販売予定数が決定し、以降は予定数に達し次第受付終了※GOODSMILE以外の通販サイトでは数に限りあり]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Summer Internship 2025: Learning About Business Strategy and Production</title><link>https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en/list/3223</link><author>cover_hirata</author><category>COVER</category><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://coveredge.cover-corp.com/en">COVEREdge Magazine</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[What is COVER’s Summer Internship?It was another scorching hot summer this year – how did everyone spend it?In mid-August, COVER held a three-day hands-on Summer Internship program designed for students to experience business production and learn how to structure business development through practical exercises. Through the program, participants had the opportunity to experience the actual process of creating new business ideas, particularly in the entertainment industry, and to receive direct feedback from upper management. The internship aims to give students a firsthand understanding of COVER’s approach to business strategy and how new projects are brought to life. We spoke with the team in charge of the Summer Internship to learn more about its purpose.  “The purpose of this program is to give participating students the opportunity to learn and experience the following three key aspects:To understand the strategic thinking and processes behind management within the entertainment industryTo experience the planning and development processes of business projects within the entertainment fieldTo gain a firsthand understanding of COVER’s new business creation centered on VTubers, while receiving mentorship and feedback from professionals on-site. That’s why, for the Summer Internship 2025, we set a clear goal: to deliver presentations from multiple perspectives and receive direct feedback from the executive team. At COVER, the Corporate Planning Division plays a vital role in, not simply coming up with ideas, but bringing those ideas to life, supporting them, putting them on a stable trajectory and ensuring they are profitable. Through this internship, we wanted students to understand the process and approach required to turn a business concept into reality as we believe that understanding this kind of thinking and workflow will serve them well in any career path they pursue – whether as working professionals or as future members of a corporate planning team.”Experiencing Business Production in COVER’s Corporate Planning DivisionSo what exactly did the Summer Internship 2025 look like?This year’s program invited nine students, who were divided into teams of three, to take on a three-day challenge in business production.Here is how the three-day program unfolded: Day 1 ― Group Work BeginsThe program kicked off with an opening meeting, followed by introductions to members of the Corporate Planning Division who would be supporting the students as mentors throughout the internship. After a casual lunch where everyone got to know each other a little better, the mentors gave an overview of COVER’s main areas of business, adjacent industries, and potential markets before students were divided into their respective teams and their group work finally began!Day 2 ― Creating Proposals for a  New Business”Day 2 began with a quick morning meeting before diving straight into group work. Students were not just merely coming up with business ideas – if they stayed as “pie-in-the-sky” concepts, the experience would not have been quite as meaningful. With guidance from their mentors, students learned how to analyze businesses, design new business plans, and evaluate profitability and risk, as they continued to expand and shape their ideas. The group work continued after lunch, and the day wrapped up with progress reports and feedback sessions as everyone prepared for the final presentations. Day 3 ― Bringing It All Together: Presenting Before the Executive TeamThe final day also began with group work after the customary morning meeting. To ensure each group’s well-thought-out business ideas came across clearly, mentors shared tips on how to deliver effective presentations and helped the students refine their proposal materials. At 5 p.m. on the final day, the presentations began with CEO Tanigo and other members of the executive team in attendance. Final Day Presentation ReportSummer Internship presentations were governed by three main rules: (1) 15 minutes for the presentation and 5 minutes for Q&A, (2) strict time management, (3) no updates to the materials after submission. With those rules in place, each team arrived early at the venue alongside their mentors from the Corporate Planning Division to carefully go over their presentation materials.As the clock neared 5 p.m. and the presentations were about to begin, members of the executive team started to fill out the venue one after another; the interns focused and determined. The session began with each team giving their presentation, followed by Q&A sessions with the executives. After a short break, the event concluded with the awarding of the Excellence Award and feedback from CEO Tanigo.Proposals included a social contribution project that utilizes COVER’s motion tracking technology to digitize and pass down the skills of experienced professionals, an immersive theme park concept where fans and talents can go between each other’s worlds, and a digital tabletop figure device designed to enhance and support fans’  activities.During the feedback session, executives praised the students for their fresh perspectives and out-of-the-box thinking when coming up with ideas not bound by the conventions of the VTuber industry, as well as the feasibility of their proposals. This  also served as the perfect opportunity for executives to share their insights on COVER’s vision for the future and offering practical advice on how to approach business planning. Looking Back on Summer Internship 2025Feedback from ParticipantsWe received feedback from perspectives we’d never considered before. It really made me realize the sincerity behind the advice we were given. It was an invaluable experience to hear directly from the company’s top executives.Through this experience, I learned that creating a business isn’t just about coming up with ideas. It’s about analyzing successful cases, understanding their core elements, and finding ways to differentiate them. The insights I gained here will definitely help shape my future approach to business.I was able to move past surface-level trends for success and develop a more fundamental way of thinking. Getting direct feedback from the executives also helped me understand how real business decisions are made: something that will surely be a major asset in my career. The mentoring sessions were especially meaningful. Every conversation was packed with insights and learning.Reflections from the Program CoordinatorOn the Final Day PresentationsWhat stood out was how seriously each team considered the question “Why COVER be the one to take on this business idea?”Their approaches were truly diverse – some worked backward from COVER’s strengths, others analyzed markets that could be accessed from our existing areas of business, and some made sure their ideas were grounded in solid reasoning to address real-world challenges. Rather than simply envisioning a “New business,” they kept asking themselves what it truly means for COVER to lead such an initiative giving depth and credibility to every proposal, which is what left the strongest impression on me. What stood out to me was how each team built their projects around open discussions. Every member’s ideas could be seen in the final presentations – a true reflection of how well they collaborated.We also held a short mid-program sharing session, where each team had five minutes to share their progress, challenges, and proposed solutions. Hearing other teams’ perspectives sparked new ideas and helped participants have a fresh take on their own projects and spot missing elements in their own proposals, expanding the scope of their learning. The sharing session encouraged more open communication within and across teams, which I believe ultimately led to higher quality presentations.COVER continues to grow under its mission, “Together, Let’s Create Culture Loved by All,” driven by the challenge of elevating VTubers into a culture loved by people around the world. COVER’s greatest strength lies in its personnel – professionals from diverse backgrounds in creative, business, and technology, who respect and inspire one another and work together to achieve a common goal. This internship offers a special opportunity to experience the passion and business innovation that drive COVER.We’re excited to see the participants go on to create  that inspires people around the world together with COVER! ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】VTuberスタイル 2025年11月号/ 巻頭特集 AZKi</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/vtuberstyle-202511/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 08:08:04 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive&apos;s next indie game is a Papers, Please-style inspection game to spot fake VTubers - Essential Japan</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMivgFBVV95cUxQOU5fWTFIaUwyNWZlMUJFQkNxdm9DWGg2MFo5SU1EblFuSk9yMmxvQkdvVG95QjRpc1JvSDJjdWpUV09NamZkajhjZVZKeTR4UnN2dGdqR2ktMjhEZGYxTmFvbkczdmpPcktGNlpXczBvMEY2LUhEbjcwMC15Y2xfNWFsbUdNbXR3YlJrN0NRUFRVZlBMY2RROHltZUlDU2tDWktndDQ3eDR0LTk3MTBrNEpGNk1wNDZPYXUySS1n?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 21:05:53 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>New hololive 2.5D fighting game will see Usada Pekora battle Houshou Marine - Essential Japan</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMirgFBVV95cUxPQVRub0M2V0pBV3hyRmdZaVBXbVBOWW5OZDBkZ1dwbDdmd3Nzcm01UHhrMnI1cXJuaXlNRTdlQUpISlpIckhBRG1qcE42QTV5U1JfTWdWODZ5M2dtLVpyZU01U3VHTHdqWjNsbFBnSnFCR1pYLTVfSExlOWVhcTAtZkk2ZmZESFdJUk1qUGd3N0ZBbUY3dTdvMEhETENjaVh6VzJocnBGMWE2eF9TNEE?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 20:58:32 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Protect Hololive Vtubers From Imposters in Hologuard Game - Siliconera</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMijgFBVV95cUxQcHY1N2xNRk95dkd4XzA2cEk2U3pFdjZ6VWZxTDFrWjlUYjJGcDlsa3NialZTdUdsN2owYVgtdHNxRWRBdk54ZS1ab2xkM1JwT3F4VUxKbU91MEltamV2UjJqLWlMZGIwX0lfaUFjbGctaUgzVld0bTZISWxXLUpnamtjcThkVXNId3FyXzdR?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Hololive&apos;s indie label announces Papers, Please-inspired quiz game Hologuard - DBLTAP</title><link>https://news.google.com/rss/articles/CBMiowFBVV95cUxOZU9vck5JZnVpSGlFTi1IRk45MlotU01iNlc2cVlFbzQxRzVzdk9kckF2R3MxSjE5ZGRwWXhnUFREbHNTQnQwX0l0N3YyV2x4OXdUd2tjU0FlekJoY01EQkR0Y2FFX0hRWEdxd0Y4S2xpdjNfaXQwSVQtUnVZVkYtc1pKV2puUllabVRvaXpacmRxTXowdThOczFmM0pfODFYWko4?oc=5</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:47:47 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://news.google.com/topics/CAAqKAgKIiJDQkFTRXdvTkwyY3ZNVEZuWDNKc2EyaDRjQklDWlc0b0FBUAE?hl=en-US&amp;gl=US&amp;ceid=US:en">hololive on Google News</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>New hololive 2.5D fighting game will see Usada Pekora battle Houshou Marine</title><link>https://essential-japan.com/news/new-hololive-2-5d-fighting-game-will-see-usada-pekora-battle-houshou-marine/</link><author>James Richardson</author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://cdn.essential-japan.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/hololive-fantasy-battle.webp" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://essential-japan.com/?s=hololive">hololive articles from Essential Japan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A new 2.5D fighting action game has been announced, based on the popular VTuber unit "hololive Fantasy."]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>hololive’s next indie game is a Papers, Please-style inspection game to spot fake VTubers</title><link>https://essential-japan.com/news/hololives-next-indie-game-is-a-papers-please-style-inspection-game-to-spot-fake-vtubers/</link><author>James Richardson</author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://cdn.essential-japan.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/hologuard.jpg" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://essential-japan.com/?s=hololive">hololive articles from Essential Japan</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[A new, official fan-made game has been announced under the "holo Indie" brand—a "VTuber Entrance Inspection Quiz Game" titled Hologuard.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】食玩デフォルメフィギュア「ホロライブ デフォルメコレクション Vol.3」／ ロボ子さん/宝鐘マリン/尾丸ポルカ/風真いろは：26年3月発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/deformer-vol-3/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 23:16:59 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[︎種類（ランダム仕様）【ラインナップ】2.宝鐘マリン4.風真いろは6.ドクロくん＆一味クマ8.ぽこべぇ︎単品内容・彩色済フィギュア１体(全8種)・ガム(ソーダ味)1個]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>【予約受付中】ホロライブプロダクション ウエハース vol.5：26年3月発売</title><link>https://merch-matome.com/wafers-vol5/</link><author>jun3720</author><category>merch</category><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 23:08:07 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://merch-matome.com/">Merch Matome</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[【ラインナップ】・兎田ぺこら・白銀ノエル・天音かなた・常闇トワ・雪花ラミィ・獅白ぼたん・ラプラス・ダークネス・博衣こより・ベスティア・ゼータ・こぼ・かなえる・古石ビジュー・フワワ・アビスガード・エリザベス・ローズ・ブラッドフレイム・セシリア・イマーグリーン・響咲リオナ・水宮枢・綺々羅々ヴィヴィ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>ホロライブ3期生1st EPリリース決定！2026年1月17日、18日にKアリーナ横浜でライブ開催！</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000001187.000030268.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/30268/1187/30268-1187-3cd55597cea4c5f48e9e26e87f47a876-1920x1080.png?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 22:15:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>『hololive 3rd Generation Live#きゅるるん大作戦〜最強アイドル、推すしか…</title><link>https://prtimes.jp/main/html/rd/p/000002119.000064643.html</link><author></author><category>hololive</category><enclosure url="https://prcdn.freetls.fastly.net/release_image/64643/2119/64643-2119-9bcebce1bd2e26c81baa52e97ee7fb64-1920x1080.jpg?width=295&amp;height=195&amp;canvas=118%3A78&amp;quality=85%2C75&amp;format=jpeg&amp;auto=webp&amp;fit=bounds&amp;bg-color=fff" length="" type=""/><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 22:15:22 +0000</pubDate><source url="https://prtimes.jp/main/action.php?run=html&amp;page=searchkey&amp;search_word=Hololive&amp;search_pattern=1">hololive in PRTimes news releases</source><content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>